<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >
	<channel>
		<title> | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>http://192.168.1.206/FreshRSS/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of  | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 04:38:01 -0700</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 11:38:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="/i/?a=rss&amp;state=2" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
				<item>
			<title>I just cleared out my Proton mail inbox</title>
			<link>https://marblethoughts.bearblog.dev/i-just-cleared-out-my-proton-mail-inbox/</link>
						<dc:creator>marblethoughts</dc:creator>
			<category>status</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Hi, just an update- I got through all my recent email messages and read/responded. Feel free to shoot me a hello on <strong>marblethoughts@proton.me</strong> or write on my <a href="https://marblethoughts.bearblog.dev/guestbook/">guestbook</a> (unfortunately I had to disable auto-approval because of the spam I received... come on guys, do better :( I didn't like that at all!)</p>
<p>Anyway, I'm back :)</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 01:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763811424085769</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Red Flags Everywhere and I Forgot My Umbrella</title>
			<link>https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/2025/11/22/red-flags-everywhere-and-i-forgot-my-umbrella/</link>
						<dc:creator>Musings from a Tangled Mind</dc:creator>
			<category>Everyday Musings</category>
			<category>dating</category>
			<category>dating sites</category>
			<category>humor</category>
			<category>life</category>
			<category>love</category>
			<category>men</category>
			<category>musings</category>
			<category>observations</category>
			<category>online dating</category>
			<category>relationships</category>
			<media:content url="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/31ec7a2e33056eb9b17551f99a60a9ba20d8b41e7681ea12d7fe7911294c5215?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image"><media:title type="html">surojabu11</media:title></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Online dating is… huh.</p>
<p>I would say it’s like a carnival, but carnivals at least pretend to have safety codes. Dating apps are more like that dream-version circus where the clowns have taken over, the popcorn machine is on fire, and every exit sign just points you back into the tent. And the tent is also on fire.</p>
<p>And men — bless them — are a mystery wrapped in a red flag wrapped in a group text I definitely should’ve left on read.</p>
<p>Yep, you guessed it. I’m dipping my toe back into the dating pool. And what I’ve learned so far is this, most men see dating apps not as a place to meet people, but as an audition tape for the privilege of being blocked.</p>
<p>It’s honestly impressive.</p>
<p>Here’s a recent example — a vignette, if you will — of my first encounter (yes, <em>first </em>encounter) with a gentleman of questionable um, search history.</p>
<p><em>Guy:</em> hey<br>
<em>Me:</em> Hi there! How’s your week going?<br>
<em>Guy:</em> u up?<br>
<em>Me: </em>…I mean, yes… it’s 7:15 p.m. It’s evening. Everyone is up. It’s how time works.<br>
<em>Guy</em>: want 2 come over<br>
<em>Me:</em> um, I don’t know you.<br>
<em>Guy</em>: i’m normal<br>
<em>Me:</em> Sir, that’s exactly what people say when they’re not, in fact, normal.<br>
<em>Guy</em>: ok but what r ur thoughts on choking<br>
<em>Me</em>: My thoughts are that you should learn punctuation first.<br>
<em>Guy:</em> u wanna pee on my face or nah<br>
<em>Me:</em> Heyyy… [ex husband], is this you??</p>
<p>He then sent a photo I will not describe, out of both courtesy and basic human decency, and I blocked him so fast I’m pretty sure my phone got friction burns.</p>
<p>And somehow — <em>somehow</em> — I’m the one they call “a bit odd.” Which… fair. But also, at least my weirdness is creative. Flavored. Artisan-crafted. Not “here’s my unsolicited anatomy, please validate me.”</p>
<p>So yes. Dating is hard.<br>
Men are confusing.<br>
And I’m still here, searching for the one man who will love:</p>
<ul>
<li>snacks,</li>
<li>horror movie stats,</li>
<li>meme chaos,</li>
<li>and the fact that I speak to my cat in full sentences.</li>
</ul>
<p>Until then, I’ll be on the apps — politely dodging the red-flag circus performers and treating every DM as a potential opening line to my friends:</p>
<p>“You will not <em>believe</em> what just happened.”</p>
<p><span>.</span></p>
<p> </p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 23:20:56 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763811424085768</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Weeknotes: Nov. 15-21, 2025</title>
			<link>https://tracydurnell.com/2025/11/21/weeknotes-nov-15-21-2025/</link>
						<dc:creator>Tracy Durnell</dc:creator>
			<category>Weeknotes</category>
			<category>personal</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Win of the week:</strong> I was brave and went in person to speak at a public hearing in favor of <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2024/08/04/letter-to-council-re-upzoning-houghton-village/">a local housing project</a>! 😱 Maybe winging it was not my most eloquent moment, but I did it 🦾 (Not going to look it up and rewatch tho 😅)</p>
<p><strong>Looking forward to:</strong> new attic insulation next week! We had planned to get it done in 2020 but then we didn’t want a ton of people in our bedroom (attic access is in our primary bathroom 😑) for several years</p>
<p>Still getting used to the new skylight — we both keep turning on the light while attempting to turn it off because we’re so used to the landing being a dark cave 😂 So far, big fan of the skylight, hate the solar nightlight but that’s the part that makes it eligible for the tax credit 🤷‍♀️</p>
<h2>Stuff I did:</h2>
<ul>
<li>13.25 hours consulting</li>
<li>yay booked more appointments 🙃</li>
<li>looked back at spending for the year to update retirement planning</li>
<li>did some more moving money around and rebalancing, think I’m done for a while finally — ooh good job me I sold half our MSFT stock before it tanked, I would say totally accidental timing except that I was dumping it because I think Microsoft’s making some dumb choices lately, so just mostly accidental</li>
<li>voted on neighborhood safety projects (got on a neighborhood email list recently)</li>
</ul>
<p><span data-sanitized-id="more-31650"></span></p>
<h3>Dinners:</h3>
<p>I did meal plan again, but then screwed it up by making a leftover-less dinner on Monday instead of the meal that would give us lunches for two days… this meal planning thing is going to take some practice to get back in the habit.</p>
<ul>
<li>Takeout veggie burger with mushrooms and swiss + sweet potato fries + strawberry milkshake (tried a new place called Joe’s because our usual burger takeout place was closed, would eat again, though next time definitely need to take a digestive enzyme)</li>
<li>Baked potatoes + creamed leeks + mushroom gravy</li>
<li>Baked beans + <a href="https://www.sugarandsoul.co/buttermilk-cornbread/#wprm-recipe-container-48140">buttermilk cornbread</a> (I’ve made this before but I was underwhelmed today) + caramelized-ish onions + Coke (hmm the caffeine seems to have hit me today 🫨)</li>
<li>Veggie burgers + curly fries (we forgot we had leftover caramelized onions until we were done eating 😭)</li>
<li>Seven layer dip + chips + leftover pineapple</li>
<li>Sausage sandwiches with leftover caramelized onions</li>
<li>Beans on toast + poached eggs + apple cider</li>
</ul>
<h2>Reading:</h2>
<ul>
<li>Read <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2025/11/16/read-sweep-of-the-blade/"><em>Sweep of the Blade</em></a> by Ilona Andrews</li>
<li>Re-read <em>Games of Command</em> by Linnea Sinclair</li>
<li>Finished reading <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2025/11/16/read-listen/"><em>Listen</em></a> by Michel Faber</li>
<li>Continued reading <em>Art in the After-Culture</em> by Ben Davis and <em>Culture as Weapon</em> by Nato Thompson</li>
<li>Started re-reading <em>Understanding Comics</em> by Scott McCloud</li>
<li>Read from <em>Aesthetic Intelligence</em> by Pauline Brown and <em>How to Art</em> by Kate Bryan</li>
<li>Received <em>Blank Space</em> by W. David Marx</li>
<li>Pre-ordered <em>Enchanting the Fae Queen</em> by Stephanie Burgis</li>
</ul>
<h3>Words I looked up:</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/gunsel">gunsel</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/doxic">doxic</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Pretty stuff I saw:</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/%24s_!Pkdu!,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F16049b35-dc6a-4881-980d-9359bb075c82_1007x1037.jpeg">a cool moody Beksiński landscape</a> I hadn’t seen before (<a href="https://alexanderadamsart.substack.com/p/zdzislaw-beksinski-and-the-tyranny">via</a>)</li>
<li>immediately bought <a href="https://psychedeliclens.store/products/morel-riso-print">this morel mushroom riso print</a> 😍 (my grandparents took up mushrooming instead of birding “because mushrooms don’t move” and my gramma’s kitchen was the mushroom decor equivalent of other people’s chicken kitchens)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.inprnt.com/gallery/thompson_art/an-owl-at-night/">An Owl at Night</a> by Aled Thompson</li>
<li><a href="https://www.blackdragonpress.co.uk/products/cats-eyes">Cat Eyes</a> and <a href="https://www.blackdragonpress.co.uk/products/tzitzimitl">Tzitzimitl</a> by João Ruas</li>
<li><a href="https://www.blackdragonpress.co.uk/products/kea">epic kea portrait</a> by Vanessa Foley</li>
<li>also ordered one of <a href="https://ko-fi.com/cmgaldre/shop">these pretty trivets</a> made from scrap wood</li>
<li>dig <a href="https://www.thesixbells.com/products/amber-oval-platter">this platter</a></li>
<li>this darling <a href="https://www.article.com/product/24954/coy-sconce-brass?queryID=4e839d24dced6682c916827300175118&amp;index=production_product">brass sconce</a> (though I avoid exposed bulbs)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.beyondretro.com/products/light-green-dress-l-1">this sweet vintage mint dress</a></li>
<li>rad NASA photo of <a href="https://science.nasa.gov/missions/webb/webb-first-to-show-4-dust-shells-spiraling-apep-limits-long-orbit/">three gravitationally bound stars</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>New music I listened to:</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://song.link/s/6pVETleBrWqseIfVEFevgP">Boundary Rider</a> by Tycho and Paul Banks (<a href="https://chrisglass.com/2025/10/29/in-the-alley-on-the-way-to-soup/">via</a>)</li>
<li>Findlay – <a href="https://findlaymusic.bandcamp.com/track/life-is-but-a-dream">Life is But A Dream</a> and <a href="https://findlaymusic.bandcamp.com/album/the-last-of-the-20th-century-girls">Ride</a> (<a href="https://bulletin.sherif.io/2025/11/21/forgotten-pleasures.html">by way of</a>)</li>
</ul>
<h2>Nature notes:</h2>
<figure aria-describedby="caption-attachment-31758" data-sanitized-id="attachment_31758" data-sanitized-class="wp-caption alignnone"><img src="http://tracydurnell.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/PXL_20251116_221424331.jpg" alt="water drops beading on the tightly closed buds on a bundle of long stems" width="750" height="1000" data-sanitized-class="size-full wp-image-31758"><figcaption data-sanitized-id="caption-attachment-31758" data-sanitized-class="wp-caption-text">tall oregon grape flowering in another week or two maybe?</figcaption></figure>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 22:23:46 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763811424085767</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sometimes the internet</title>
			<link>https://folkmoss.bearblog.dev/sometimes-the-internet/</link>
						<dc:creator>folkmoss</dc:creator>
			<category>blog</category>
			<category>eng</category>
			<category>internet</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes the internet scares me. And I'm not talking about dark webs, cyber crimes and gruesome humans behind keyboards. No, <mark>I'm talking about human interaction mediated by bits and bytes and how, when one decides to write something in here, it instantly becomes part of the ether that is the internet</mark>. <em>No take backsies</em>, I guess. Which is funny if you think about it, considering the horde of <strong>deadlinks</strong> and whatnot, but this phenomena is (mostly) outside of the original poster's hands.</p>
<p>I might delete this entire blog, dig it out of the Way Back Machine, scrape whatever I can off of the face of the internet, and yet, somehow, somewhere, in someone's bookmarks or send-to-kindles or offline backups... there can be a slice of folkmoss there which I cannot control.</p>
<p>I was surfing through a website earlier today when I saw a complete stranger mentioning me and complimenting said website.</p>
<p>Like... <em>what</em>?</p>
<p>Who is that, what is happening, how did they find I linked that website... But of course. The answer is quite obvious and boring: they clicked here and found the link and thought it was cool enough to leave a lil note to the webmaster. Meanwhile, I didn't even remember linking it!</p>
<p>It was so out of the blue, so unexpected to find mention of yours truly in someone else's web space. So yeah, sometimes the internet does scare me a little bit.</p>
<hr>
<h3 data-sanitized-id="in-other-news">In other news</h3><ul>
<li>I'm playing around with pixel art again. Created my first grimy cursors on <a href="https://www.cursor.cc/?action=icon_list&amp;user_id=186465">Cursor.cc</a> and I love them. Yes, I was feeling Halloweeny still.</li>
<li><strong>I was fiddling on Neocities</strong> to have <a href="https://pixeliana.neocities.org/">my LibraryThing widget</a> there as well and, taking a cue of Petra Pixel's widgets, I got it working alright. But the thing is, I cannot, for the life of me, figure out <em>why</em> it refuses to stay centered on my sidebar. I'll just have to live with that, I guess.</li>
<li><strong>As for IRL,</strong> I've done a bunch of conference interpretation in the past few weeks, which means I get to pay off my debts and start 2026 fresh. This is the first month I've had leftover money on my bank account (for a hot minute there I thought I'd forgotten to pay some bill). I'll finally be able to <em>save</em> money. Maybe even <em>invest</em> it. Imagine that! It's been years since I've had any money working for me. <a href="https://youtu.be/ON3qRFzTzo4">I miss that feeling.</a></li>
<li>After two weeks without checking <a href="https://listography.com/folkmoss">Listography</a>, all the lists that needed updating are up to date now. It was only two weeks but it felt like an entire month. I really missed it, I love my Listo and checking other ppl's stuff.</li>
<li>I've moved from Firefox to Vivaldi. We'll see how that goes. So far, so good. It looks very robust for this average internet user here. Also discovered about <a href="https://about.start.me/">Start.me</a> and I love it.</li>
</ul>
<center>
<p>※</p>
<small>
<blockquote>
<p>This post was last edited 7 hours, 1 minute ago. You can reply <a href="mailto:thefolkmoss@pm.me">via email</a> or leave a message on my <a href="https://folkmoss.bearblog.dev/guestbook">guestbook</a>.</p>
</blockquote>
</small><p>⇠  // <a href="https://folkmoss.bearblog.dev/an-i-live" title="A.N. | I live" data-sanitized-class="previous-post">Previous</a> ⇢</p>

</center>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 21:35:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763811424085766</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Streets of Rage 4</title>
			<link>https://joelchrono.xyz/blog/streets-of-rage-4/</link>
						<dc:creator>joelchrono</dc:creator>
			<category>game</category>
			<category>review</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Some games give you a lot to talk about, and some others are pretty straight-forward mindless fun!</p>

<p>I don’t have a huge history with the <em>Streets of Rage</em> series, but I am quite familiar with <a href="https://joelchrono.xyz/blog/couch-gaming/">multiplayer games</a>, and this just happened to be one of the popular ones when I looked at lists online. Still, I never prioritized it as much when I had plenty of other options, and I also wasn’t a big fan of the artstyle from the screenshots, since I really preferred the pixelart style the series had had during its original trilogy on the Sega Genesis.</p>

<p>In any case, I saw the physical edition of <em>Streets of Rage 4: Anniversary Edition</em> for cheap online, I lost control again, and by the time I noticed I had the game on my collection and pretty much played from start to finish with friends on a weekend.</p>

<p>While this is a fantastic game I will return to many times, I didnt’t have that much to say about it and it’s not like I am incredibly passionate for it—<em>or so I thought</em>. I almost didn’t feel like writing a review and sharing it because I don’t think I add anything new to the conversation, as someone who isn’t super familiar with beat’em ups and such.</p>

<p>However, I write whatever I want here so that’s irrelevant :P</p>

<figure data-sanitized-class="img">
  <picture>
    <source type="image/webp">
    <source type="image/png">
    <img src="https://joelchrono.xyz/assets/img/blogs/2025-11-21-streets-of-rage-4-official-artwork.png" alt="Streets of Rage 4 official artwork" data-sanitized-class="mx-auto">

  </picture>
  <figcaption data-sanitized-class="caption">Streets of Rage 4 official artwork</figcaption></figure>

<p>The <strong>story</strong> is simple and to the point. The children of Mr. X (a villain from previous games) started their own Crime Syndicate and have brought the city to chaos once again, so it’s up to you to save the city once again, venturing into the <em>streets of rage</em> to clean it up from the criminals raoming around.</p>

<p>The <strong>gameplay</strong> is great! it’s a beat’em up after all. It’s fun, it’s easy to learn, but there’s a high ceiling to master especially if you are chasing high scores. You basically have regular attacks, throws, and Blitz moves. A new addition to the series are some special attacks, which will lower your HP, however, succesive attacks will let you recover it, unless you get hit, providing a great risk-reward balance that I enjoyed a lot. There’s a variety of characters, some new ones and some old ones, all of them with their own unique styles. Tanks, lightweights, etc.</p>

<p>The <strong>art</strong> was neat. As I mentioned before the franchise started and stuck on the Sega Genesis, and never went through an early 3D graphics phase or high-res pixelart like other classic series did. This new entry—a couple decades after the previous one—went for hand-drawn character art, which looks absolutely incredible. At first I wasn’t a fan, but as soon as I started playing it, the animation work did its magic. It works perfectly and the lightning, shadows and other visual effects make the whole thing amazing. The locations and background art is good too, some of it is inspired by old stages from the original trilogy , but most are brand new ones that fit right in with the overall aesthetic. Every boss and enemy has pretty good animation and attack patterns too.</p>

<p>The <strong>soundtrack</strong> of this game is as amazing as it gets. It fits perfectly with the rest of the franchise and it’s one of the main standouts of the game. This will hype you up like nothing else and get you in the mood to go to the streets and punch some criminals and corrupt policemen. Seriously though, it adapts depending on the action going on and is something I’ll definitely listen to while going to the gym or running around.</p>

<p>Some other cool things this game offers are a Roguelike mode, which comes included in the Switch version (both physical and digital) and some great extras like concept art, pixel art, character profiles, a PvP mode, etc.</p>

<p>Overall, this game was a fantastic experience to go through. This review was made after a single playthrough of the campaign and a couple of runs of the roguelike mode, I think there’s quite a lot of other things yet to experience, and I kind of want to get better at it on the Roguelike mode.</p>

            
		<p>
	<a href="mailto:me@joelchrono.xyz?subject=Streets%20of%20Rage%204">Reply to this post via email</a> | 
	<a href="https://fosstodon.org/@joel/115591184437254176">Reply on Fediverse</a>
</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 19:59:48 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763811424085765</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>De La Soul - Cabin In the Sky</title>
			<link>https://iam.skoo.bz/de-la-soul-cabin-in-the-sky/</link>
						<dc:creator>S. L.</dc:creator>
			<category>Albums</category>
			<category>Music</category>
			<media:content url="https://iam.skoo.bz/content/images/2025/11/PNG-image.png" medium="image"></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://iam.skoo.bz/content/images/2025/11/PNG-image.png" alt="De La Soul - Cabin In the Sky"><p>A couple of years ago, De La released a video for “Oodles of O’s”, a track from their second album <em>De La Soul is Dead</em>, released over three decades ago. Many things change over time, but one thing that didn’t was the track was still a head nodder. But, one thing that had changed was Trugoy the Dove, aka Dave, was no longer with us.</p><p><em>Cabin in the Sky </em>starts off with a rollcall, which goes through the list of collaborators on the album. All is fun until you get to Dave. That’s when the sadness hits.</p><p>However, as Pos mentions on "YUHDONTSTOP", “Cindy said, ‘If you all stop, then Dave stops.’” Sprinkled throughout the album, there are verses from Dove that serve as reminders of his exceptional ability. Initially, the album starts off somber, but it quickly transforms into a celebration.</p><p>Beyond the obvious surrounding Dave, the production throughout is dope, which is a trademark of De La albums. There are beats from the likes of Jake One, Pete Rock, and DJ Premier. Throughout, De La shows they can adapt to different production styles, proving just how versatile they are.</p><p>Frankly, it’s great to hear from these guys again. They also gave us a solid album.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:53:38 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763811424085764</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>you can do it, but not everything</title>
			<link>https://jeffdelp.bearblog.dev/you-can-do-itbut-not-everything/</link>
						<dc:creator>jeffdelp</dc:creator>
			<category>micro</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Life can be challenging.</p>
<p>Stressful. Hectic. Busy. Overwhelming.</p>
<p>Our capacity to deal with the world around us varies and is finite.</p>
<p>When we reach our limit, we have to accept it.</p>
<p>Don't give up.</p>
<p>Reduce the load, or do something rejuvenating to increase our capacity.</p>
<p>No one can do everything, all the time.</p>
<p>Life can be challenging.</p>
<p>But, you can do it!</p>
<p><small>if you enjoyed this post, consider a toast; comment by email, or say hello: jeff[dot]bearblog[at]gmail[dot]com</small></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763811424085763</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>🎬 Don't Do That</title>
			<link>https://mtwb.blog/videos/2025/dont-do-that/</link>
						<category>video</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Video:</strong> <a href="https://youtu.be/Ugr024DMMeQ?si=2svpbBavB003C1tz">https://youtu.be/Ugr024DMMeQ?si=2svpbBavB003C1tz</a></p><p>Installing Gentoo on an Old ThinkPad by Bad Acronym</p><p>I had more fun watching this than I should have.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:33:57 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763811424085762</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Welcome Daughter</title>
			<link>https://thatalexguy.dev/posts/welcome-daughter/</link>
						<dc:creator>Alex White</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>2AM on Wednesday morning my wife woke me up with the sentence I've been anxiously awaiting:
"I think it's time to go to the hospital". By 3AM we were at reception for the
maternity ward (despite the best efforts of never ending university construction). At 4:26AM I saw my daughter's face for the first
time.</p>
<p>We got to our postpartum room around 7AM. While my wife got settled, I grabbed a cup of coffee to fight off the lack of sleep.
Surveying our new temporary home, I noted it was possibly the same or 1 room over from where my son first spent the night with us.
Unfortunately in the years since, they had managed to further downgrade the bed for the support person (my back is still sore),
but the hospital food had definitely at least improved!</p>
<p>We spent around 36 hours in the hospital before being discharged. Unlike my son, my daughter is a great sleeper. She falls asleep
quickly and stays asleep for quite awhile. It's been a huge relief for my wife and I, as our son is quite a ball of energy.</p>
<p>At 14 hours old, my daughter and son met. He was jumping up and down, unable to contain his excitement to meet his baby sister!
He had a lot of questions, and wanted to stare and touch her as much as possible. She just slept. Eventually his focus shifted
to a bag of chips and a cookie he found.</p>
<p>Now it's Friday night, we're going into our second evening at home as a family. I managed to get the Christmas decorations up before
the birth, so the home has a cozy vibe as fall transitions into winter outside.</p>
<p>I'm very thankful that our family is 1 bigger going into Thanksgiving this year. I'm also incredibly thankful to be spending time away from
work (although only 5 weeks, America really sucks sometimes). My son was ecstatic when I told him daddy won't be working for awhile,
and instead playing with him everyday (we've decided it's best for me to be on son duty and my wife + mother-in-law on daughter duty).</p>
<p>All in all, I'm tired, but so very happy. Welcome to the world daughter and welcome to our loving family.</p>
<hr>
<p>I intentionally kept details vague, no names and definitely no photos of my kids on the internet.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 15:54:01 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763811424085761</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The State of Nats #10: Smoke like a travel presenter</title>
			<link>https://stateofnats.bearblog.dev/the-state-of-nats-smoke-like-a-travel-presenter/</link>
						<dc:creator>stateofnats</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><em>[Everything between October 19 and the day of publishing this]</em><br>
Ha Noi, Vietnam</p>
<h2 data-sanitized-id="data">Data</h2><p><code>Flights taken: 2</code></p>
<p><code>Books purchased: 3</code></p>
<p><code>Books read: 2</code></p>
<h1 data-sanitized-id="new-timezones">New timezones</h1><h3 data-sanitized-id="at-1100-hrs">At 1100 hrs</h3><p>Today, I am essentially Anthony Bourdain. I am embodying a fake AI slop version of him, millennial, female, perpetually middle class minded, truth-spurting capsule of the sediments of my thoughts. I am a fish out of water, a woman on a mission. I am walking with a sardonic face and a matter-of-factly gait.</p>
<p>The only thing I lack is a cigarette. The only thing I miss is a cigarette.</p>
<p>To add to the general disrespect I have for my health, the pining for a cigarette is at its peak. I have never been a smoker yet crave it between my fingers as I walk in Ha Noi. It feels appropriate here, today, I want to be Bourdain. I want to seamlessly get along with locals, eat flavourful food and rationalise their politics against what I know of my own little world. I want to do things that read good in memoirs, yet leave no lasting impact on my being. I want to feel safe in wandering and taking chances. I want Tony's confidence.</p>
<p>{Incoming message: Sorry, we cannot check you in ahead of schedule.}</p>
<h3 data-sanitized-id="at-1200-hrs">At 1200 hrs</h3><p>I am also a woman with feminine disposition. So, I want a sexy French depression. I want a black dress and a frown for an accessory. A Chanel jacket, a Dior skirt (look at me, putting two rivals together). I want a <em>je ne sais quoi</em> quality. A cigarette while I wear sunglasses in the rain. I want to stroke a cat while I am at it. I want an old lady to approach me and offer me their grandson. I want to say no.</p>
<p>I want to make my version of a <em>Bourdain travel ensemble</em>. A cigarette between my fingers, a city under my feet. Noodles in my belly, a sustained blood alcohol level.</p>
<p>I am being vile, a non-smoker promoting smoking. Yet as an accessory it is the most appropriate. My choice to travel is made possible by only one method, turning hard earned money into ash. The selfishness of "I want to go there and see that and eat this and walk there" is actualised with my arrival in Ha Noi. I am here to consume a country, second time around, and revisit with more vigour than in 2017, when I came a humble and curious being. I have returned ravenous.</p>
<p>Only because I have been awake more of the last 36 hours, I am feeling triumph and fatigue. I want I want I want. I am here to take.</p>
<p>{Email Inbox: The job role you applied for and thought you were suited for is not going to be given to you. Sincerely, corporate.}</p>
<h3 data-sanitized-id="at-1300-hours">At 1300 hours</h3><p>I am worthless, pathless, career-less, aimless, jobless, dedication-less, crumpled mess of a person. I do not want a cigarette, I AM a cigarette.</p>
<h3 data-sanitized-id="at-1355-hours">At 1355 hours</h3><p>I am worthless, pathless, career-less, aimless, jobless, dedication-less, crumpled mess of a person. I want a shower.</p>
<h3 data-sanitized-id="at-1500-hours">At 1500 hours</h3><p>I am hungry.</p>
<hr>
<h2 data-sanitized-id="culture-consumption">Culture consumption</h2><p>I watched Steven Wilson perform live. And I had tears in my eyes when he played Pariah. This is the first concert I have attended with Ru, and it is valuable that was of his favourite musicians. Is any artist worth an evening of inhaling dust? Perhaps yes, when they are beloved by the person you love, and you have the <em>stupid</em> fever of making him happy.</p>
<h6 data-sanitized-id="adventures-in-selling-tickets">Adventures in selling tickets</h6><p>I sold three tickets to strangers in this concert. This endeavour was solitary, as the thoughtlessness of the original buyers led to a sunken investment of thousands. Recovery was essential. I used Reddit and Whatsapp to seek interested parties for the concert tickets. Here was the journey and a few noteworthy moments from this pursuit.</p>
<ul>
<li>I talked with over 50 people from Reddit and leads from whatsapp sharing by friends in their networks.</li>
<li>I searched several subreddits where there were mentions of the Steven Wilson concerts to find the right ones for suggesting a sale.</li>
<li>With Ru's Reddit account and mine, I split the posts into two types of content:
Emo prog rock content - Ru's account
Sales content - My account
The sales content is clean. <em>I have a ticket, here is how you can buy it</em> and a DM would continue the conversation. The emo content, however, was more engagement centric. It always had a sentimental or a situational title with a vague line in the body suggesting a ticket is available for sale. The sale chat was more in the comment section.</li>
<li>All tickets were sold at cost price. Pretty much everyone was selling at cost price. It was a good vibe.</li>
<li>All three tickets were sold to people who made the decision quite quickly. Anyone who took longer did not end up making the purchase.</li>
<li>On one occasion, I posted to Ru's account that he has a <em>single</em> ticket left. Ru (really me) received this message:
<em>Can I replace your friend and come along instead? 😬 F, but still.</em>
After I mentioned that she could certainly join, me (Ru but me pretending to be Ru) and my wife, after I shared all the details, I got this response:
<em>Oh you already have company, I thought you didn't, hence though I could go with someone. Pretty sure spouses don't want random people coming.</em>
The conversation went into an awkward territory, where it was soon clear she would come for the concert as a plus one on Ru's "extra" ticket and only with him. She ended the chat with, <em>sure, thanks</em>.
She did not purchase the ticket.</li>
<li>One guy could not come because he could not convince his girlfriend to tag along.</li>
<li>One guy wanted to buy it but his friends refused, and he did not want to go alone.</li>
<li>I levelled the playing field by texting the same people seeking tickets from two accounts, sharing the same price to clarify that not only was it indeed the cost price, but it was also a good price to purchase at. I felt like I was flooding the market with <em>two different brand names</em> selling the <em>same product</em>.</li>
<li>I used my other reddit account to upvote these posts. With at least one downvote expected, this always helped balance the heat.</li>
</ul>
<p>Once confirmed, and after some contemplation period, the sale process was often complete. People payed the advance, then showed up at the concert and paid the rest. Sweet kind people, rock fans, Steven fans. This was a very wholesome trade.</p>
<h6 data-sanitized-id="additionally">Additionally</h6><p>I am reading <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/224004055-mother-mary-comes-to-me">Mother Mary Comes to Me</a> by Arundhati Roy. Because of this trip, I am parted from the last 100 pages of the book. I finished listening to <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/51014471-the-house-in-the-cerulean-sea">The House in the Cerulean Sea</a> which was meh and cute at the same time. It is really <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/60556912-the-housemaid">The Housemaid</a> that captured my imagination, and I devoured it within a day.</p>
<p>The film Pirates of the Carribean: The Curse of the Black Pearl is a nearly-perfect film and has captured my attention. It was an easy watch on a frustrating day.</p>
<p>Pho-ya later
Nats</p>
<hr>
<div data-sanitized-class="benjamin"><a href="https://natashayad.substack.com/">Other Writings</a></div>
<h5 data-sanitized-id="the-concept-of-comment-section-is-broken-if-you-have-thoughts-youd-like-to-share-with-me-try-email">The concept of comment section is broken. If you have thoughts you'd like to share with me, try email.</h5><div data-sanitized-class="benjamin"><a href="mailto:yadavnatasha@gmail.com?subject=Re:%20The%20State%20of%20Nats%20#10:%20Smoke%20like%20a%20travel%20presenter">Reply via email</a></div>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 04:59:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763811424085760</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
