<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >
	<channel>
		<title> | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>http://192.168.1.206/FreshRSS/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of  | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 11:06:29 -0700</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:06:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="/i/?a=rss&amp;state=2" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
				<item>
			<title>Cute little Pokemon-esque Roottrees-alike</title>
			<link>https://blog.lauramichet.com/cute-little-pokemon-esque-roottrees-alike/</link>
						<dc:creator>lauram</dc:creator>
			<category>deduction_games</category>
			<category>games</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>This cute little narrative deduction game, <a href="https://celia14.itch.io/my-friends-the-monster-trainers">My Friends the Monster Trainers,</a>is a short (for me, 20-minute) browser-based deduction puzzle where you have to deduce the type, moves, habitat, and art for a set of Pokemon-like monsters, using only a set of letters describing children getting into battles with them.</p>
<p>The game lacks Obra Dinn style guess banking, so it's a bit more possible to brute force than other games in this genre... but it's short and each creature has a LOT of different qualities you must deduce from the letters, so it doesn't seem like it really merited guess banking.</p>
<p>There's a devlog about it <a href="https://celia14.itch.io/my-friends-the-monster-trainers/devlog/1149334/pokemon-x-deduction-the-development-of-my-friends-the-monster-trainers">here</a> which gets into its background as a 72 hour game jam game, as well as some of the reasoning behind its puzzle design. There's even a little bit in here about why the devs avoided the Obra Dinn style guess banking and what they did instead to add some friction to brute-forcing gameplay. I really enjoyed reading it!</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 10:59:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766253891949230</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>rise</title>
			<link>https://tacitexposure.bearblog.dev/rise/</link>
						<dc:creator>tacitexposure</dc:creator>
			<category>poetry</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><em>rise and rise until you die</em><br>
<em>kill yourself a thousand times</em></p>
<p><a href="https://tacitexposure.bearblog.dev/taboo" title="Embracing the taboo" data-sanitized-class="previous-post">Previous</a> </p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 10:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766253891949229</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#AdventJukebox 20: Merry Xmas Everybody by Slade</title>
			<link>https://thomasrigby.com/posts/adventjukebox-20-merry-xmas-everybody-slade/</link>
						<dc:creator>Thomas Rigby</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://song.link/y/88WsYBGmrjI"><em>"Merry Xmas Everybody"</em></a> by <strong>Slade</strong></p>
<p>There's a line in this song that says “Does Granny always tell you the old songs are the best?” which is funny because now <em>this</em> is the "old song" my kids' Granny thinks is best.</p>
<p>Anyway, is it really Christmas if you haven't heard Noddy Holder screaming "It's Christmas!" like a Midlands hard rock banshee?</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:55:59 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766253891949228</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Traveler and the Tourist</title>
			<link>https://nikhil.bearblog.dev/the-traveler-and-the-tourist/</link>
						<dc:creator>nikhil</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>With the rise of social media, especially after COVID, we have seen a sharp increase in global tourism. People want to see the world. They want to fulfill a checklist—a checklist they created not organically, but by watching others maintain similar lists in their lives. They want to tick everything off because everyone else seems to be doing the same.</p>
<p>This mindset gave rise to indulgence in all kinds of experiences. You travel to places so visually stunning that you feel compelled to record them on camera and share them with the world. What was once meant to be <em>experienced</em> has now become an <em>event</em> to be broadcast. Spots that were once secluded and untouched were pushed into the spotlight because more and more people craved novelty—novelty they could display. Merely sharing an experience is no longer enough. That experience must be unique, rare, and impressive enough to invite admiration.</p>
<p>This is why the word “tourist” has taken on a negative connotation. Tourists are often perceived as people who visit a place, click a few pictures, litter the surroundings, and return home. They show little concern for the place itself. They have no interest in its history or culture. They do not wish to learn—only to see, capture, and announce to the world that they were there.</p>
<p>A traveler, however, is different from a tourist. He visits a place because it genuinely interests him. He learns about the culture. He attempts to blend into the environment. He explores the people by observing their routines, enduring the hardships they endure, and living through the joys they find meaningful. In return, he discovers places that are isolated yet breathtaking. Ironically, it is these travelers who first uncover such niche and secluded spots—only for them to later become fodder for tourists to exploit in the name of novelty.</p>
<p>The traveler lives in many places, and those places, in turn, live within him. They transform him. They humble him. He may document his experiences through a blog post or an insightful video, but for him, it is never about a checklist. There is no checklist. He stays long enough to understand the rhythm of the place—to feel how it breathes.</p>
<p>Have you ever visited a thousand-year-old structure, like a temple? There are many such temples in India. You will usually find two kinds of people there. The first kind studies the intricate detailing, observes the geometry, and tries to map history onto the structure itself. The second kind stands in front of the same architectural marvel clicking pictures of themselves—images curated for attention and validation. They frame the architecture as a backdrop rather than a subject. Nobody enjoys the company of the second kind. Everyone gravitates toward the first. The reason is obvious.</p>
<p>The second one has the photos; the first one has the story.</p>
<p>The same holds true in the mountains. You will again find two kinds of people. One breathes in the cold air, absorbs the vastness through his eyes, and lets the silence settle within him. The other is busy calculating angles—drone shots, tripod setups, selfies, panoramas. Always capturing, rarely experiencing. Nobody likes the second kind of people.</p>
<p>Ultimately, it comes down to this: are you undergoing a new experience, or are you merely collecting proof that you were there? The former initiates transformation. It offers a new perspective. You begin to realize how trivial many of your worries are—how your thoughts have inflated simple problems into overwhelming burdens. That is how you truly refresh yourself. That is how you feel rejuvenated. That is how you actually feel the time off you took.</p>
<p>You can feel refreshed even by traveling just 100 kilometers over a weekend—if your intention is to experience a new reality rather than tick off a checklist or collect photos. There is nothing wrong with clicking pictures. The problem lies in the objective. Experience first. And if something truly resonates with you, capture it—not for others, but as a reminder of a moment where you felt peace. That is why we collect souvenirs. Social media has flipped this objective upside down.</p>
<p>The true reason we should travel is to free ourselves from the mental baggage we carry. This baggage is born out of the routines and realities we inhabit daily. By stepping into a new reality and adopting a new routine—even briefly—we create space to relax and reset. Distancing yourself from the mundane is how you detach from your old reality and reconnect with your inner self through a new one, even if only for a few days. This separation allows you to see life in a new light.</p>
<p>The next time you travel, try something different. Ask yourself how you would survive in that place using only the amenities available there. You cannot bring anything with you. How would you adapt to new technologies in a remote yet scenic location? How would you manage daily chores in freezing winters or humid tropical climates? Try to follow the local routine as closely as possible. Learn a new skill while living there. Think about the problems people face—not from empathy or pity, but from lived experience.</p>
<p>Your shortcomings will surface in such realities. Identify them. Then introspect. Ask yourself whether those shortcomings stem from your personality or from the environment. Whether you need to change your surroundings—or change yourself. Most problems arise when your personality is in constant conflict with the reality you inhabit.</p>
<p>And that is why they say: to travel is to discover yourself.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 07:42:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766253891949227</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Waking up in an airport hotel room with a runway view.</title>
			<link>https://adactio.com/notes/22314</link>
						<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://adactio.com/images/uploaded/22314/small.jpg" alt="Waking up in an airport hotel room with a runway view.">
<p>Waking up in an airport hotel room with a runway view.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 07:13:09 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766253891949226</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why do people leave comments on OpenBenches?</title>
			<link>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2025/12/why-do-people-leave-comments-on-openbenches/</link>
						<dc:creator>@edent</dc:creator>
			<category>/etc/</category>
			<category>OpenBenches</category>
			<category>web</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>I'm still a believer in the promise of Web 2.0. The idea that giving people a curated space to chat produces tiny sparks of magic.</p>

<p>My wife Liz and I have been running the <a href="https://openbenches.org/">OpenBenches project</a> for about 8 years - it's a crowd-sourced repository of memorial benches. People take a geotagged photo of a bench's plaque, upload it to our site, and we share it with the world.  Might sound a bit niche, but we have around thirty-nine <em>thousand</em> benches catalogued from all over the world.</p>

<p>From the start, we had a comment form under each bench. Of course, we pre-moderate any comments. That <a href="https://www.openbenches.org/blog/online-safety-act/">helps with our Online Safety Act obligations</a> and prevents spam from being published. We don't collect any personal data, to reduce our GDPR exposure. Our comments are self-hosted using the excellent <a href="https://commentics.com/">Commentics</a> - which means we don't send people's data off to a 3rd party.</p>

<p>We <em>thought</em> that this would be used to tell us that an inscription was wrong, or if a bench had moved, or something like that.</p>

<p>We were completely wrong!</p>

<p>People use OpenBenches comments for all sorts of things. Of course, there are a few which provide details about the bench itself:</p>

<p><a href="https://openbenches.org/bench/33640"><img src="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/removed.webp" alt="This bench was removed after the river flooded and majorly eroded the bank earlier this year (spring 2025), and now two new benches are in approximately the same place but a little further back from the river." width="1248" height="402" data-sanitized-class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-64159"></a></p>

<p>Other provide a little context about the person:
<a href="https://openbenches.org/bench/38738"><img src="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/info.webp" alt="
She competed under her birth name, Zsuzsa Nádor:
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zsuzsa_Nádor
There's a Wikipedia article about Roman, too:
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Roman_Halter" width="1248" height="402" data-sanitized-class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-64161"></a></p>

<p>But those sorts of comments are hardly the majority.  The comments break down (roughly) into these categories:</p>

<h2 data-sanitized-id="i-want-to-know-more-about-this-person"><a href="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2025/12/why-do-people-leave-comments-on-openbenches/#i-want-to-know-more-about-this-person">I want to know more about this person</a></h2>

<p><a href="https://openbenches.org/bench/3225"><img src="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/grandson.webp" alt="I am the grandson of Janet Constance Hardie, who had a sister Ethel Hardie. Ethel Hardie married Harry Macinnes and then died in 1961. Ethel and Harry had a daughter named Ethel Elvery Macinnes. Is the Ethel Hardie, who is remembered on this bench related to the above Hardies of my family ? Best Regards, Neil Rowlandson" width="1248" height="582" data-sanitized-class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-64163"></a></p>

<h2 data-sanitized-id="i-sat-on-this-bench-searched-for-the-inscription-and-found-this-site-i-want-to-share-my-feelings"><a href="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2025/12/why-do-people-leave-comments-on-openbenches/#i-sat-on-this-bench-searched-for-the-inscription-and-found-this-site-i-want-to-share-my-feelings">I sat on this bench, searched for the inscription and found this site. I want to share my feelings</a></h2>

<p><a href="https://openbenches.org/bench/13312"><img src="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/devon.webp" alt="Sounds like she was an inspirational woman. Clearly gone to soon. Sat on her bench today whilst visiting from Devon." width="1248" height="282" data-sanitized-class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-64164"></a></p>

<h2 data-sanitized-id="thank-you-for-putting-a-bench-here"><a href="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2025/12/why-do-people-leave-comments-on-openbenches/#thank-you-for-putting-a-bench-here">Thank you for putting a bench here</a></h2>

<p><a href="https://openbenches.org/bench/38259"><img src="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/peace.webp" alt="A peaceful spot on the banks of the river Orwell. Thanks for those that funded it." width="1248" height="222" data-sanitized-class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-64165"></a></p>

<h2 data-sanitized-id="this-has-moved-me"><a href="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2025/12/why-do-people-leave-comments-on-openbenches/#this-has-moved-me">This has moved me</a></h2>

<p><a href="https://openbenches.org/bench/37741"><img src="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/amy.webp" alt="I'm sat on the bench now i didn't know the lady but so sad to pass at such a young age by what i have found on the internet she was liked loved and respected my thoughts with all the family even though it's been almost 4 years since her I'm sure she will never be forgotten. Someone has placed a bunch of yellow flowers on the bench that is what first made me stop and look RIP Amy" width="1248" height="642" data-sanitized-class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-64166"></a></p>

<h2 data-sanitized-id="my-heart-has-broken"><a href="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2025/12/why-do-people-leave-comments-on-openbenches/#my-heart-has-broken">My heart has broken</a></h2>

<p><a href="https://openbenches.org/bench/39228"><img src="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/miss.webp" alt="I love you. I miss you. I so long to see you." width="1248" height="224" data-sanitized-class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-64167"></a></p>

<h2 data-sanitized-id="i-cant-visit-this-bench-but-im-glad-someone-has-shared-a-photo"><a href="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2025/12/why-do-people-leave-comments-on-openbenches/#i-cant-visit-this-bench-but-im-glad-someone-has-shared-a-photo">I can't visit this bench, but I'm glad someone has shared a photo</a></h2>

<p><a href="https://openbenches.org/bench/13023"><img src="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/mary.webp" alt="Mary was my best friend, from primary school until she died. I have not visited her bench but hope those who sit there in that beautiful place will also have experienced wonderful friendships as I did." width="1248" height="402" data-sanitized-class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-64170"></a></p>

<h2 data-sanitized-id="thank-you-for-adding-a-photo"><a href="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2025/12/why-do-people-leave-comments-on-openbenches/#thank-you-for-adding-a-photo">Thank you for adding a photo</a></h2>

<p><a href="https://openbenches.org/bench/26373"><img src="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/thanks.webp" alt="This is my father’s memorial bench on half penny pier thank you to the person who took the photos x" width="1248" height="282" data-sanitized-class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-64169"></a></p>

<h2 data-sanitized-id="i-dont-know-the-person-this-bench-commemorates-but-i-want-to-let-them-know-theyre-still-loved-and-remembered"><a href="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2025/12/why-do-people-leave-comments-on-openbenches/#i-dont-know-the-person-this-bench-commemorates-but-i-want-to-let-them-know-theyre-still-loved-and-remembered">I don't know the person this bench commemorates, but I want to let them know they're still loved and remembered</a></h2>

<p><a href="https://openbenches.org/bench/35294"><img src="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/mum.webp" alt="My mum and her girlfriends sat on the bench today and told your father stories about how they were visiting this place many decades ago. They hope your father was listening. All the best to you" width="1248" height="402" data-sanitized-class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-64171"></a></p>

<h2 data-sanitized-id="thats-nice"><a href="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2025/12/why-do-people-leave-comments-on-openbenches/#thats-nice">That's nice</a></h2>

<p>Hundreds of people sharing connections. Wanting to express their feelings. Understanding the terrible pain of loss and the hope that, someday, someone will think fondly of us.</p>

<p>You can <a href="https://openbenches.org/comments">view all the comments on OpenBenches.org</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:34:14 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766253891949225</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Things that make me go yay!</title>
			<link>https://thomasrigby.com/posts/things-that-make-me-go-yay-2025-12/</link>
						<dc:creator>Thomas Rigby</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>I can be a bit of a curmudgeon and focus on the negatives when I feel the pressure. I know it's not good for me to get into that negativity spiral so reflecting like this is important.</p>
<p>So, without further ado, here are some things I have been enjoying lately.</p>
<ul>
<li>Peppermint hot chocolate after a walk in the cold</li>
<li>Hosting Christmas for our extended family</li>
<li>How cosy the house looks when it's dark out and all the lamps are on</li>
<li>Hearing the cows in the field mooing to each other early in the morning</li>
<li>Lily Allen's new album</li>
<li>Christmas fantasy romance films</li>
</ul>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 05:23:12 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766253891949224</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>the brave coward</title>
			<link>https://mikkolaksola.com/the-brave-coward/</link>
						<dc:creator>mikkolaksola</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>I was asked at a job interview yesterday to describe the bravest thing I've ever done.</p>
<p>I'm not going to lie, it caught me a bit off guard. Not surprisingly, my first thoughts were hilariously bad, especially compared to better answers that came to me later — while driving back home.</p>
<p>Anyway.</p>
<p>My initial answer and following discussion eventually led me to highlight some simple, seemingly boring everyday situations where one might put themselves out there and be vulnerable: starting a difficult conversation, asking that person out, revealing your true feelings, asking for a promotion or a raise, or trying anything new in public.</p>
<p>I started to feel OK-ish about my answer at this point.</p>
<p>But my brain wasn't done and kept going — out loud, of course.</p>
<p>Actually, I wasn't sure those were acts of bravery after all, despite seeming like such on the outside. When I really think about it, I didn't do any of them because I'm so brave and overcame the fear. It's actually quite cowardly. I did them because I <em>fear</em> the alternative much, much more.</p>
<p>Regret.</p>
<p>The possibility of <em>that</em> is so much scarier than any rejection could ever be.</p>
<p>You want to be <em>really</em> brave? To stare fear into the eyes and not flinch?</p>
<p>Just do nothing and face the consequences.</p>
<p>I'm happily a coward.</p>
<p><u>Putting yourself out there and going for it <em>is</em> the safe option.</u></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 04:51:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766253891949223</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>let's give it a sniff: Bits and Bops</title>
			<link>https://itwont.work/blog/lets-give-it-a-sniff-bits-and-bops</link>
						<description><![CDATA[<p>let's give it a sniff: Bits and Bops</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766253891949222</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
