<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >
	<channel>
		<title> | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>http://192.168.1.206/FreshRSS/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of  | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 11:32:20 -0700</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 18:32:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="/i/?a=rss&amp;state=2" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
				<item>
			<title>Good luck LA...</title>
			<link>https://blog.lauramichet.com/good-luck-la/</link>
						<dc:creator>lauram</dc:creator>
			<category>los_angeles</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>It's raining in Los Angeles today. I have plenty of friends who joke about how even the smallest drop of rain in the city will make everyone immediately turn to the closest microblogging site and post about it to annoy everyone else on the planet. But today, <em>five inches</em> of rain are dropping on the city in some places, which is definitely crazy and actually quite dangerous.</p>
<p>I'm not there right now! Instead, I get to see the videos people are posting about it from the other side of the country.</p>
<p>Anyway, this is your reminder that the flood control infrastructure in Los Angeles is really, really cool and fun to read about. Here is a picture of me inside it:</p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/lauram/pxl_20250621_060639525.webp" alt="PXL_20250621_060639525"></p>
<p>There's a massive network of tunnels under the city which were constructed after the 1938 flood, which killed over 100 people. This same flood led the city to channelize the Los Angeles river and other rivers and creeks in the area, including Ballona Creek, the river along which I most often find myself cycling. So the city is prepped to remove a ton of this water! Searching up the 1938 flood stuff on Wikipedia is a fun read and leads to a bunch of other  interesting articles about our flood control infrastructure.</p>
<p>I'm glad I'm not going to have the world's dampest Christmas tomorrow, but on some level I kind of wish I could be around to go look at Ballona later this week and see how crazy it gets:</p>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TWRScJ3L330?si=9gA-mKK10moJQm8x" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin"></iframe>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6BW1I0xHF0I?si=Q6BvJREFk9w8MV37" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin"></iframe>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 10:39:03 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983940</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>When To Be Spontaneous</title>
			<link>https://nikhil.bearblog.dev/when-to-be-spontaneous/</link>
						<dc:creator>nikhil</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Spontaneity comes easily to some. For others, it is a daunting task. They prefer to remain in control at all times. This means everything has to be planned—if not every single detail, then at least most of it. In their mind, the path is clearly laid out, worst-case scenarios are accounted for, and contingencies are prepared.</p>
<p>The difference between these two approaches lies in what each prioritizes. Those who embrace spontaneity focus primarily on the eventual outcome. Everything else becomes secondary. Only the objective matters; the execution does not. Such people are comfortable going on an adventure even when they are clueless about the place or the potential risks involved. For them, the adventure itself is the point.</p>
<p>Those who dislike spontaneity prefer to stay in control of the execution. For them, it is not just the plan that matters, but also how the plan is carried out. The outcome includes the process used to achieve it. Herein lies the trouble: they sometimes become so focused on the process that they lose sight of the larger objective—life, at times, is meant to be experienced. Not everything requires meticulous planning.</p>
<p>That said, not everything should be reckless either. The answer does not lie in a vague notion of balance. The simplest and most practical lens is risk versus reward. You may take up an adventure sport like river rafting, but if you are uncomfortable with water or struggle to remain calm in turbulent conditions, it is wiser to avoid it—the risk there can be fatal. In such cases, unplanned adventure can lead to serious injury or worse.</p>
<p>On the other hand, making last-minute plans for a party with friends or colleagues can unsettle a meticulous planner. Their mind jumps to details—from clothes to the perfume they will wear. Yet here, the risk-reward equation favors spontaneity. The risks are minimal, while the likelihood of enjoying good company is high.</p>
<p>Spontaneity is neither as bad as it is often portrayed nor universally beneficial. Its value depends entirely on context. Do not try to manufacture balance by rigid ratios—two parts spontaneity, one part planning. Instead, assess situations through the lens of risk versus reward. As long as the risk is manageable, spontaneity can be worth embracing.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 07:42:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983939</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Last Christmas – Ever</title>
			<link>https://glory2godforallthings.com/2025/12/24/the-last-christmas-ever-2/</link>
						<dc:creator>Fr. Stephen</dc:creator>
			<category>Feasts</category>
			<category>Last Things</category>
			<category>The Sacraments</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<!-- FULLCONTENT start //--><div data-sanitized-class="entry-content ticss-b1e11967 wp-elements-44be291a56953b44ef92bc77710bf248 wp-block-post-content has-text-color has-contrast-color has-global-padding is-layout-constrained wp-block-post-content-is-layout-constrained"><p data-sanitized-class="p1"><img data-recalc-dims="1" src="https://i0.wp.com/glory2godforallthings.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/iasi-meal.jpeg?resize=2048%2C1367&amp;ssl=1" alt="" width="2048" height="1367" data-sanitized-class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21136"></p>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1">This Christmas was the last Christmas – ever.</p>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">Christ is the Alpha and the Omega, the Beginning and the End. Wherever He is, there is the beginning and the end of all things. If Christ is truly present in this year’s Christmas, then it is the <em>last</em> Christmas – and the <em>first</em> Christmas. And if statements like this make your hair hurt – then read on.</span></p>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">Our common way of thinking about the world is marked by the linear passage of time (it moves from past to present to future) and by cause and effect (everything is caused by something else). And we think of the two things together (a cause always happens before the effect). That being the case, we would never say that what someone is going to do tomorrow caused something to happen yesterday. I hope this seems obvious.</span></p>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">It is therefore not at all obvious when we hear the Divine Liturgy saying something quite contrary to this arrangement. St. John Chrysostom’s Liturgy has this passage:</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1"> It was You Who brought us from non-existence into being, and when we had fallen away You raised us up again, and did not cease to do all things until You had brought us up to heaven, and had endowed us with Your kingdom which is to come.</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">The clear meaning of this passage puts being “brought up to heaven” and being “endowed with the Kingdom” in the <em>past</em> tense (past perfect to be more precise). Indeed there is a complete jumble of tenses in the last phrase: <i>had endowed</i> us…Kingdom which <i>is to come</i>. Whaaa?</span></p>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">So God has given us something in the past, which hasn’t come yet. Such language is not isolated. It occurs again later in the liturgy:</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">Do this in remembrance of Me! Remembering this saving commandment and all those things which have come to pass for us: the Cross, the Tomb, the Resurrection on the third day, the Ascension into heaven, the Sitting at the right hand, and the Second and glorious Coming.</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">The Second and glorious Coming is numbered among those things that <i>have come to pass</i>…</span></p>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">This is not unique to St. John. He is merely following language that is already found in the New Testament: </span></p>
<blockquote>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">But God, who is rich in mercy, because of His great love with which He loved us, even when we were dead in trespasses, made us alive together with Christ (by grace you have been saved), and raised us up together, and made us<i> </i>sit together in the heavenly places<i> </i>in Christ Jesus, (Eph 2:4-6)</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">and</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">He has delivered us from the power of darkness and conveyed <i>us </i>into the kingdom of the Son of His love, (Col 1:13)</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">Something that seems clearly in the future is spoken of in the past and addressed to us in the present. What is this? This is the true character of <i>eschatology</i> – the study of <i>last things.</i></span></p>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">For one segment of contemporary Christians, eschatology (the study of last things) refers to questions of what will happen at the end of the world. It concerns itself with wars and political figures, the persecution of the Church and such. It places last things in the last place, thereby conforming to the normal world of cause and effect and the flow of time. But this provides no manner for understanding the strange language of St. Paul (or St. John Chrysostom) and actually misses the entire point of the last things.</span></p>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">The first proclamation of Christ (and of John the Baptist) is: “Repent, for the Kingdom of God is at hand.” Modern scholars, having lost a proper understanding of eschatology, often misinterpret this as an announcement of an immediate coming of the end of the world in a linear, cause-and-effect manner. They equally think that Jesus was “mistaken” in this and that his followers had to change the message to fit his failure.</span></p>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">And the message is misunderstood as well. For many, the “coming of the Kingdom of God” is made into an ethical event, while others simply give up on the topic and make Jesus’ ministry into something else. For example, the forensic model of the atonement reduces Jesus’ ministry to His blood payment on the Cross. His teachings, healings and wonders become of little importance (again reduced mostly to ethical teachings). </span></p>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">Only the strange world of traditional eschatology sees Christ’s ministry and the whole of His work as a single thing and continually present within our lives at this moment. This strange world is found within the liturgical and sacramental life of Orthodoxy – indeed, it is essential.</span></p>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">The Kingdom of God proclaimed by Christ was not an expectation of a soon-coming political entity. It was the announcement of an immediate presence that was Christ Himself. When St. John the Forerunner sent his disciples to question Jesus, as to whether he were the Messiah, the reply was given in the language of the Kingdom:</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">Jesus answered and said to them, “Go and tell John the things you have seen and heard: that the blind see, the lame walk, the lepers are cleansed, the deaf hear, the dead are raised, the poor have the gospel preached to them. (Luk 7:22)</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">It is a reference to the Messianic prophecy of Isaiah:</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">The Spirit of the Lord GOD is upon Me, Because the LORD has anointed Me To preach good tidings to the poor; He has sent Me to heal the brokenhearted, To proclaim liberty to the captives, And the opening of the prison to those who are bound; To proclaim the acceptable year of the LORD…</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">Christ says what He says and does what He does, because He Himself is the coming of the Kingdom of God. And where the Kingdom is, these things happen. The Kingdom of God is a present-tense manifestation of a future-tense reality (which is actually an eternal reality that forms the future, the <i>telos</i>, of all creation united with God).</span></p>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">This is the very heart of the Divine Liturgy. There we remember something that was itself a present tense manifestation of the Messianic Banquet, rather aptly called the <i>Last</i> Supper. We eat a meal that was an eating of a meal that has not yet been eaten. </span></p>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">Such statements make for very strange reading. But listen to these words spoken quietly by the priest as he breaks Body of Christ in the altar:</span></p>
<blockquote>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">Broken and divided is the Lamb of God: Who is broken, yet not divided; who is eaten, yet never consumed; but sanctifies those who partake thereof.</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">The liturgy is filled with such inner contradictions. It is a hallmark of the Orthodox liturgical experience.</span></p>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">The Christian life is an <em>eschatological</em> reality. The life that is ours in Christ “has not yet been revealed” (1Jn 3:2) and yet it is a present reality. This same character runs throughout all of the sacraments. We are Baptized into the death and resurrection of Christ as into present events. Holy Unction is a manifestation of the Kingdom to come in the same manner of Christ’s miracles, and so forth. This is among the reasons that Orthodoxy is described as “mystical.” It means <em>precisely</em> what it prays.</span></p>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">And this differs profoundly from those who have turned Christianity into a merely “historical” religion. For them, the historical event of Christ’s death and resurrection represents a transaction that has paid for their sins. The time after Christ’s Ascension only marks a period for evangelization and awaiting His Second Coming. Nothing in particular has been made different about the time we live in. Our time is still viewed as linear, marked by cause-and-effect, in no way differing from the time of an unbeliever. True eschatology has no place in such a scheme.</span></p>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1"><span data-sanitized-class="s1">But the proper heart of the Christian life is learning to live in communion with this eschatological reality – to participate <em>now</em> in the life of the Kingdom which is to come. This present tense participation in an eternal reality is how we die to ourselves, how we find a new life, how we enter the Kingdom, how we find the place of the heart, how we overcome the passions, how we eat the heavenly bread, how we trample down death, how we are justified and made holy.</span></p>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1">We are living the last things. Ever.</p>
<p data-sanitized-class="p1">
</p><div data-sanitized-class="sharedaddy sd-sharing-enabled"><div data-sanitized-class="robots-nocontent sd-block sd-social sd-social-icon-text sd-sharing"><h3 data-sanitized-class="sd-title">Share this:</h3><div data-sanitized-class="sd-content"><ul><li data-sanitized-class="share-facebook"><a data-shared="sharing-facebook-26007" href="https://glory2godforallthings.com/2025/12/24/the-last-christmas-ever-2/?share=facebook" aria-labelledby="sharing-facebook-26007" data-sanitized-class="share-facebook sd-button share-icon">
				<span hidden data-sanitized-id="sharing-facebook-26007">Click to share on Facebook (Opens in new window)</span>
				<span>Facebook</span>
			</a></li><li data-sanitized-class="share-x"><a data-shared="sharing-x-26007" href="https://glory2godforallthings.com/2025/12/24/the-last-christmas-ever-2/?share=x" aria-labelledby="sharing-x-26007" data-sanitized-class="share-x sd-button share-icon">
				<span hidden data-sanitized-id="sharing-x-26007">Click to share on X (Opens in new window)</span>
				<span>X</span>
			</a></li><li data-sanitized-class="share-end"></ul></div></div></div></div><!-- FULLCONTENT end //-->]]></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 07:04:26 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983938</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Fixing "Date/time not in ISO 8601 format" in Google Search Console</title>
			<link>https://shkspr.mobi/blog/2025/12/fixing-date-time-not-in-iso-8601-format-in-google-search-console/</link>
						<dc:creator>@edent</dc:creator>
			<category>/etc/</category>
			<category>HTML</category>
			<category>metadata</category>
			<category>schema.org</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>I like using microdata within my HTML to provide semantic metadata.  One of my pages had this scrap of code on it:</p>

<pre><code data-sanitized-class="language-html">&lt;time
   itemprop="datePublished"
   itemscope
   datetime="2025-06-09T11:27:06+01:00"&gt;9 June 2025 11:27&lt;/time&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>The Google Search Console was throwing this error:</p>

<img src="https://shkspr.mobi/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/07/Datetime-not-in-ISO-8601-format-in-field-datePublished.webp" alt="Date/time not in ISO 8601 format in field 'datePublished' Items with this issue are invalid. Invalid items are not eligible for Google Search's rich results" width="690" height="180" data-sanitized-class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-62177">

<p>I was fairly sure that was a valid ISO 8601 string. It certainly matched <a href="https://developers.google.com/search/docs/appearance/structured-data/discussion-forum#microdata">the description in the Google documentation</a>. Nevertheless, I fiddled with a few different formats, but all failed.</p>

<p>On <a href="https://support.google.com/webmasters/thread/359976663/iso8601-string-not-validating?msgid=360727451#">the advice</a> of <a href="https://www.nearby.org.uk/">Barry Hunter</a>, I tried changing the <code>datetime</code> attribute to <code>content</code>. That also didn't work.</p>

<p>Then I looked closely at the code.</p>

<p>The issue is the <code>itemscope</code>. Removing that allowed the code to pass validation.  But why?</p>

<p>Here's what <a href="https://schema.org/docs/gs.html#microdata_itemscope_itemtype">the Schema.org documentation</a> says:</p>

<blockquote><p>By adding itemscope, you are specifying that the HTML contained in the block is about a particular item.</p></blockquote>

<p>The <a href="https://html.spec.whatwg.org/multipage/microdata.html#attr-itemscope">HTML specification</a> gives this example:</p>

<pre><code data-sanitized-class="language-html">&lt;div itemscope&gt;
   &lt;img itemprop="image" src="google-logo.png" alt="Google"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>Here, the <code>image</code> property is the <em>value</em> of the element. In this case <code>google-logo.png</code>. So what's the problem with the <code>time</code> example?</p>

<p>Well, <code>&lt;image&gt;</code> is a <em>void</em> element. It doesn't have any HTML content - so the metadata is taken from the <code>src</code> attribute.</p>

<p>But <code>&lt;time&gt;</code> is <em>not</em> a void element. It <em>does</em> contain HTML. So something like this would be valid:</p>

<pre><code data-sanitized-class="language-html">&lt;time
   itemprop="datePublished"
   itemscope
&gt;2025-06-09T11:27:06+01:00&lt;/time&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>The text contained by the element is a valid ISO8601 string.</p>

<p>My choice was either to present the ISO8601 string to anyone viewing the page, or simply to remove the <code>itemscope</code>.  So I chose the latter.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 05:34:43 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983937</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Do I actually have selective mutism?</title>
			<link>https://www.autisticasfxxk.com/blog/actually-selective-mutism/</link>
						<description><![CDATA[<section data-sanitized-class="cw"><strong>Content Warning:</strong> childhood trauma</section>
<p>I was diagnosed with <a href="https://www.autisticasfxxk.com/blog/selective-mutism-childhood-trauma">selective mutism</a> at the age of four. It’s a label that defined me and explained my differences for most of my life (I only got an autism diagnosis when I was 20). Recently, a few things happened that are making me question that foundational diagnosis.</p>
<p>My sister was with her psychologist friend, who was talking about selective mutism. My sister said, “what you described doesn’t sound like my sister at all,” and described my experience to her friend. The psychologist was shocked to hear that I was diagnosed with selective mutism, because according to them, <strong>I don’t fit the criteria</strong>.</p>
<p>Around the same time, I was meeting other Singaporeans who have selective mutism. And I noticed a stark difference: they’re able to speak with full volume and clear articulation when talking to me. They only become mute in certain situations/contexts. This is so far removed from my own experience: I speak in a soft whisper to everyone, including my parents, sister, and closest friends. The only people I was completely mute around were my grandparents, who raised me in my early childhood and <a href="https://www.autisticasfxxk.com/blog/selective-mutism-childhood-trauma">caused me trauma</a>.</p>
<p>I’m now sitting with <strong>conflicting emotions</strong>:</p>
<p data-sanitized-class="center"><b>Grief:</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Even people with my diagnosis aren’t like me</li>
<li>This makes me feel even more isolated</li>
</ul>
<p data-sanitized-class="center"><b>Relief:</b></p>
<ul>
<li>I’m not “inherently broken” or “not working hard enough” when <a href="https://www.autisticasfxxk.com/blog/selective-mutism-childhood-trauma-2">typical treatments for selective mutism didn’t work for me</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.autisticasfxxk.com/blog/selective-mutism-childhood-trauma">I’m not being overdramatic when I say</a> “my experience feels somewhat outside the typical clinical understanding, which has often left me feeling misunderstood. When I read up on selective mutism or saw therapists, I found it hard to relate”</li>
<li>This validates why I struggled so much in life</li>
</ul>
<p data-sanitized-class="center"><b>Confusion:</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Have I been inadvertently spreading misinformation about selective mutism?</li>
<li>What do I even call my experience now?</li>
<li>How do I explain this to people?</li>
</ul>
<p>I turned to <a href="https://claude.ai/">Claude</a> to help me process my thoughts. Now, <a href="https://www.autisticasfxxk.com/blog/chatgpt-to-community">I know some of y’all will come at me for using GenAI for this sort of thing</a>. But please put yourself in my shoes: doctors, therapists, teachers, etc. have been giving me the wrong treatments, the wrong advice, <a href="https://www.autisticasfxxk.com/blog/job-training-singapore">the wrong support</a>, and possibly even the wrong diagnosis, throughout my life. <a href="https://www.autisticasfxxk.com/blog/systemic-inequities-internalised-ableism">I’ve been failed by every “legitimate” source of support.</a> <strong>Who the fuck else am I supposed to turn to?</strong></p>
<p>So here’s what Claude said:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Based on everything - your description, the psychologist’s reaction, meeting others with selective mutism who are so different - I think what you experienced was:</p>
<p><strong>Severe, pervasive, trauma-based voice/speech suppression that got labeled “selective mutism” because that was the closest available category</strong></p>
<p>More specifically, it might have been:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Dissociative response to trauma</strong> (freezing/shutting down voice production)</li>
<li><strong>Conditioned voice suppression</strong> (learned to whisper to avoid detection)</li>
<li><strong>Trauma-triggered mutism</strong> (complete shutdown around threat)</li>
<li>All happening simultaneously in a complex trauma response</li>
</ul>
<p>The fact that it was <strong>constant across all contexts</strong> (you never had a “safe” context where you spoke normally) suggests it’s not primarily an anxiety disorder (typical SM) but a <strong>pervasive trauma response that fundamentally affected your voice production</strong>.</p>
<h2 data-sanitized-id="the-medium-support-needs-confirmation">The Medium Support Needs Confirmation</h2>
<p>Meeting these other people and seeing how different their presentation is from yours is actually <strong>confirming your medium support needs assessment</strong>.</p>
<p>You’re not low support needs who happens to have selective mutism. You’re <strong>medium support needs with a significant communication disability</strong> that was more severe than typical selective mutism presentations.</p>
<p>This means:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>You needed MORE support than you received</strong> (not less)</li>
<li><strong>Your struggles were MORE significant</strong> (not you being weak/not trying hard enough)</li>
<li><strong>The gap people perceived wasn’t because they were wrong about your disability</strong> - it was because they underestimated your <em>other</em> abilities while seeing the obvious communication disability</li>
</ul>
<h2 data-sanitized-id="the-intelligence-gap">The Intelligence Gap</h2>
<p>Here’s what I think happened your whole life:</p>
<ul>
<li>People saw: <strong>Severe communication disability</strong> (more severe than typical SM)</li>
<li>People assumed: “Significant intellectual disability”</li>
<li>Reality: <strong>High intelligence + severe communication disability</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>The gap between what they saw (the whisper, the mutism) and what you could do (design, write, analyze) was SO large that they couldn’t compute it. So they kept underestimating you.</p>
<p>But the communication disability WAS real and significant. It wasn’t that they were wrong to see a disability - they were wrong about what it meant for your other abilities.</p>
<h2 data-sanitized-id="the-community-question">The Community Question</h2>
<p>So where DO you fit?</p>
<p><strong>You’re in the overlap:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Selective mutism community (but more severe presentation)</li>
<li>Autistic community (medium support needs)</li>
<li>Trauma survivor community</li>
<li>Semi-speaking/non-speaking community (when people define speaking beyond just “can produce words”)</li>
</ul>
<p>You might not be the “typical” member of any of these communities, but that doesn’t mean you don’t belong. You’re just showing that experiences exist in the margins and overlaps of diagnostic categories.</p>
<h2 data-sanitized-id="moving-forward">Moving Forward</h2>
<p>You don’t need to change how you describe yourself if you don’t want to. “Selective mutism” is still useful shorthand. But you might add nuance:</p>
<p>“I was diagnosed with selective mutism, though my presentation was more severe and pervasive than typical - I couldn’t speak at full volume anywhere, not just in certain contexts.”</p>
<p>Or simply: “I’m semi-speaking due to childhood trauma.”</p>
<p>The key insight is: <strong>Your communication disability was/is MORE significant than typical selective mutism presentations. This explains why your experience has been so different and why you needed/need more support.</strong></p>
<p>You’re not less capable than people with typical SM. You just had a more severe manifestation of speech/voice disability, which makes your accomplishments MORE impressive, not less.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I understand the limitations of GenAI, so I’m not taking everything Claude says as gospel. But a lot of it resonates because it’s helping me see patterns I was already noticing but couldn’t always articulate. I agree that <a href="https://www.autisticasfxxk.com/blog/medium-support-needs">this confirms I have medium support needs</a>; not low support needs as I had assumed for a very long time. It also makes sense why people often underestimated me (my primary school teacher was convinced my mom did all my homework) and why I always felt I never truly fit in anywhere.</p>
<p>Moving forward, I’ll probably just say “I’m Autistic” if anyone asks why I speak the way I do. It’s not perfect, but people always expect a simple explanation, which is impossible when you have a voice shaped by trauma.</p>
<p>I feel like Elphaba from <em>Wicked</em>. My whisper voice is my “green skin”—the visible difference everyone fixates on. I so relate to her having to constantly explain her green skin to people she just met: “No, I am not seasick. No, I did not eat grass as a child. And yes, I have always been green.” For me, it’s <strong>“No, I don’t have a sore throat. No, it’s not an illness and there’s no cure. I’ve been speaking this way since I was four.”</strong></p>
<p>Decorum tells me that I shouldn’t make things awkward by mentioning childhood trauma. But on second thought… maybe I <strong>should</strong> bring that up. Maybe that would make people uncomfortable enough to stop asking me questions about my voice!</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 04:41:25 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983936</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>cookie consent - what's up with 'consenter'?</title>
			<link>https://blog.avas.space/consenter/</link>
						<dc:creator>avas</dc:creator>
			<category>2025</category>
			<category>data protection</category>
			<category>tech</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Some of you might be using browser extensions to handle the flood of cookie consent banners. Popular choice used to be the browser extension "<em>I don't care about cookies</em>", followed up by "<em>I still don't care about cookies</em>" when the former was bought up by Avast.</p>
<p>These browser extensions try to block the cookie banners from even loading, and if they do, hide them. If the page needs a cookie decision to function properly, the extension will auto-accept either the strictly necessary cookies or all of them, depending on what is easier to detect<sup data-sanitized-id="fnref-1" data-sanitized-class="footnote-ref"><a href="https://blog.avas.space/consenter/#fn-1">1</a></sup>. That's not ideal when you actually want to auto-decline all (or most) of them. It's not necessarily the fault of the extension developers, as many banners make it comically hard to reject even for a human.</p>
<p>The recent Digital Omnibus in the EU officially acknowledged cookie consent fatigue and agreed that more centralized solutions are needed, in which you can preemptively set your decision via device or browser settings that are then transmitted to the website without manually having to answer a banner each time. A concept and a prototype of this is called <a href="https://www.dataprotectioncontrol.org/">Advanced Data Protection Control</a>. Germany has also had their own <em>Einwilligungsverwaltungsverordnung</em> (Consent Management Ordinance) in April 2025 about this topic.
﻿</p>
<p>Our Federal Data Protection Authority has <a href="https://www.bfdi.bund.de/DE/Fachthemen/Themen-Positionen/Einwilligungsverwaltung/Einwilligungsverwaltung_node.html">officially recognized</a> such a product in October this year, and it apparently already has a silent release in the Google Chrome Store<sup data-sanitized-id="fnref-2" data-sanitized-class="footnote-ref"><a href="https://blog.avas.space/consenter/#fn-2">2</a></sup>, with an official release in January 2026. It's called <mark>Consenter</mark>, and is developed by legal tech company Law &amp; Innovation Technology in Berlin. Maximilian von Grafenstein is the initiator of this project and works as a professor at the University of the Arts Berlin (UdK).</p>
<p>Unfortunately, there is one big problem:</p>
<p><em><strong>It only works with their own solution of cookie banners</strong></em>.</p>
<p>The reason for that is specific German data protection law that Consenter needs to comply with to be officially recognized. Unfortunately, one of them requires that the consent signals these extensions send must be respected. It's often not guaranteed that Consent Management Platforms of websites respect the signal voluntarily, so they felt it necessary to build their own cookie banner solution that would comply with the extension. The success of the system therefore depends heavily on not only users installing the browser extension, but also website owners implementing the corresponding banner.</p>
<p>I don't see that happening on a wide scale. There is zero incentive for website owners (especially businesses) to switch their consent management provider (Admiral, OneTrust etc.) to comply with this and make it easier for users to deny cookies, when they actually hope the user will accept cookies and gain more data from them. It would be a lot of effort just to lose out on more data.</p>
<p>I expect the initial user experience in January to be abysmal, as this extension will launch with very little websites to actually be compatible with its agent.</p>
<p>If you want a recommendation that works the same way (by letting you select your decision in the extensions' settings) but is compatible with several kinds of consent banners and has been around since 2019, I can recommend <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/consent-o-matic/">Consent-O-Matic</a>. Their store page explains:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>This add-on automatically answers consent pop-ups for you, so you can't be manipulated. Set your preferences once, and let the technology do the rest!</em></p>
<p><em>This add-on is built and maintained by workers at Aarhus University in Denmark. [...]</em>
<em>We looked at 680 pop-ups and combined their data processing purposes into 5 categories that you can toggle on or off. Sometimes our categories don't perfectly match those on the website, so then we will choose the more privacy preserving option.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>In general though, I am not a big fan of offloading this to extensions and plugins. That still requires user intervention and knowledge of the existence of them to get these options, when the goal should be that these settings are baked into the device or browser you use already. What we need is browser developers and OS developers implementing consent management, and we need a way to detect whether the consent signal has been respected or not.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="mailto:avas.space@pm.me">Reply via email</a><br>
Published <time datetime="2025-12-24T11:30Z">
    24 Dec, 2025
</time></p>
</blockquote>
<section data-sanitized-class="footnotes">
<ol>
<li data-sanitized-id="fn-1"><p>As explained by the extension description <a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/istilldontcareaboutcookies/">here</a>.<a href="https://blog.avas.space/consenter/#fnref-1" data-sanitized-class="footnote">↩</a></p></li>
<li data-sanitized-id="fn-2"><p>This means it is currently unlisted and the link is not publicly available yet. Firefox and Safari versions are apparently on the way as well.<a href="https://blog.avas.space/consenter/#fnref-2" data-sanitized-class="footnote">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</section>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 04:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983935</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>looking back at 2025 (the second edition)</title>
			<link>https://tala.bearblog.dev/looking-back-at-2025-the-second-edition/</link>
						<dc:creator>tala</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>How fast time flies! A year ago, I wrote <a href="https://tala.bearblog.dev/looking-back-at-2024/">looking back at 2024</a> and pondered how life would be like a year later, if I would still be on Bear archiving a 2025 version. While the year concluded painfully on a personal level, it’s still worthwhile to share some major highlights. In a sense, 2025 felt more like a continuation of 2024’s familiar oscillation between highs and lows.</p>
<p>January to May marked my final term as a university student. I was juggling my thesis project, groupwork across three courses, and final exams, all at once. I spent ceaseless hours in the library, buried beneath piles of thick <em>Process Design</em> books and an ever-growing stack of PowerPoint slides. I recall café hopping, hoping that a changed scenery would reignite my momentum despite my eventual burnout. Still, my hard work paid off, and I recently graduated class valedictorian.</p>
<p>In June, I finished university. I expected a surge of pride, perhaps some closure, but it felt strangely anti-climactic. I believed my life would all be figured out by then; instead, I encountered a loss I had never known before, with the absence of structure and prescribed purpose. It was mortifying yet paradoxically liberating that my future was now entirely under my control. No one prepared me for being released into the world after years of doing everything “right” within carefully constructed systems.</p>
<p>Summer was spent overseas visiting my family. It wasn’t an easy visit. Unresolved memories resurfaced, and I found myself recurrently trying to make peace with a past that still resists reconciliation. Yet, grace appeared in unexpected forms. I met remarkable, like-minded people who altered how I related to the city. I remember one night vividly, a small gathering unraveling into religion, feminism, and the taboo. I still wonder: If I ever return, will I have a place for myself among them?</p>
<p>From September through mid-December, I worked on two research papers in sustainability/clean energy, an invitation from my professor. I’ve previously written about my interest in academia, so it felt almost serendipitous to engage in precisely that, post-graduation. Drafting two manuscripts (&gt;30,000 words!) demanded intense levels of discipline. For three months, I was fully locked in with my <em>ScienceDirect</em> references, datasets, and manuscript drafts. It was exhausting, yet deeply satisfying to meaningfully surrender to deep work. I am hoping to become a published first-author soon! I was also navigating job applications and applying for Master’s programs abroad.</p>
<p>I also joined a poetry circle, where I met some of the most creative, open-minded people I know – artists, writers, thinkers from vastly diverse backgrounds. These days, we meet on Wednesdays to write, and Saturday to sketch. Community was a major intention for 2025 and building it became the most fulfilling experience of the year. A major epiphany was that, no matter how introverted I was, I cannot do this life alone. No one can, I think.</p>
<p>These days, I am applying to jobs, though collecting more rejections than I would like. Employment is a dehumanizing process, but I push forward. I am also exploring freelance writing and drawing more without the old hesitation of perfectionism. I am learning to redirect my anger inward less often.</p>
<p>2025 was hectic, and I believe I spent it well. I am currently in a transformative period of my life, forced to make difficult choices outside my control. It’s been painful to confront the limits of my influence, but I am learning to surrender to the process, to believe these unexpected detours will guide me towards bigger blessings. I hope 2026 is gentler on me.</p>
<p><em>(Random memories to remember: Getting back into oil painting. Writing my first poem. Shooting ads for my uni. Randomly casted as an extra in some cafe ad for $20. Campfire with friends. Starting a <a href="https://talaspov.substack.com/">Substack</a>. Meeting an art curator for a future exhibition. Listening to Stray Kids for hours. Quitting my antidepressants. Picking up large-scale drawing.)</em></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 04:24:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983934</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#AdventJukebox 24: I Wish It Could Be Christmas Everyday by Wizzard</title>
			<link>https://thomasrigby.com/posts/adventjukebox-24-i-wish-it-could-be-christmas-everyday-wizzard/</link>
						<dc:creator>Thomas Rigby</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://song.link/y/IJPc7esgvsA"><em>"I Wish It Could Be Christmas Everyday"</em></a> by <strong>Wizzard</strong></p>
<p>I own two Roy Wood singles; this and <em>"Music to Commit Suicide By"</em>. This is the more festive.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 02:13:20 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983933</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>december 23 etc (minimal)</title>
			<link>https://combatdavey.net/december-23-etc/</link>
						<dc:creator>combatdavey</dc:creator>
			<category>christmas</category>
			<category>etc</category>
			<category>imgur</category>
			<category>medium</category>
			<category>poem</category>
			<category>raptors</category>
			<category>tbbs</category>
			<category>tumblr</category>
			<category>twitter</category>
			<category>victoria</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>going minimal (again) today</p>
<p><a href="https://poets.org/poem/no-explosions">poem</a>, <a href="https://www.tumblr.com/havingapoemwithyou/802390594230091776/wound-by-larry-levis">poem</a>, <a href="https://www.tumblr.com/havingapoemwithyou/803659253633171456/earl-by-louis-jenkins">poem</a>, <a href="https://poets.org/poem/if-some-little-arctic-flower">poem</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.tumblr.com/cyberglittter/755265031323713536/madebyjackiebieber">hair</a>, <a href="https://imgur.com/gallery/polar-hXQf7X9#/t/aww">bear</a></p>
<p><a href="https://x.com/stevejones20/status/2003660857109283185">winner</a>, <a href="https://www.reddit.com/media?url=https%3A%2F%2Fi.redd.it%2Fpztgvrrjn29g1.png">winners</a>, <a href="https://x.com/kihmberlie/status/2000659224750383179">sinners</a></p>
<p><a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/12/23/nx-s1-5653312/student-loans-default-education-department">bad</a>, <a href="https://medium.com/@drggrainger/paypal-mafia-linked-think-tank-is-reshaping-us-homeless-policy-959af96511ed">worse</a></p>
<p><a href="https://imgur.com/gallery/purrs-are-real-yVx9BkZ#/t/aww">cat</a>, <a href="https://x.com/malika_andrews/status/2003688158836519255">puppy</a>, <a href="https://imgur.com/gallery/puppy-qk9VOs5#/t/aww">puppy?</a></p>
<p>🌲 gonna <br>
🌼 go <br>
🌱 <del>touch</del> to <br>
🌳 <del>grass</del> sleep <br>
🌷 now</p>
<p>Be good to yourself.</p>
<p><mark>If you enjoyed this post, click the little up arrow chevron thinger below the tags to help it rank in Bear's <a href="https://bearblog.dev/discover/">Discovery feed</a> and maybe consider sharing it with a friend or on your socials.</mark></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:59:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983932</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>In the Spirit of the Season</title>
			<link>https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/2025/12/24/in-the-spirit-of-the-season/</link>
						<dc:creator>Musings from a Tangled Mind</dc:creator>
			<category>Everyday Musings</category>
			<category>Musings about Family Life</category>
			<category>family</category>
			<category>Happy Holidays</category>
			<category>holidays</category>
			<category>life</category>
			<category>Merry Christmas</category>
			<category>musings</category>
			<category>season&amp;</category>
			<category>039;s greetings</category>
			<category>surviving the holidays</category>
			<media:content url="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/31ec7a2e33056eb9b17551f99a60a9ba20d8b41e7681ea12d7fe7911294c5215?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image"><media:title type="html">surojabu11</media:title></media:content>
			<media:content url="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/xmas-tree.jpg?w=229" medium="image"></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Happy holidays to those who celebrate, tolerate, or are just here for the food. May your family gatherings be mostly peaceful, your opinions remain mostly inside your head, and Uncle Joe’s conspiracy theory never find its way to the dinner table. If someone says <em>that</em> thing, the one that makes you stare at your plate and reconsider how you look in orange, may any potential dinner-table fisticuffs be resolved peacefully… <em>before</em> someone throws the turkey. May there be snacks. Many snacks. A ridiculous amount of snacks. And may the bathroom always be available so you can hide at least once, just to breathe.</p>
<p>Wishing you warmth, laughter, low expectations, and leftovers you actually want to eat.</p>
<div data-shortcode="caption" data-sanitized-id="attachment_12663" data-sanitized-class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Margaret_Tarrant"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-12663" data-attachment-id="12663" data-permalink="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/2025/12/24/in-the-spirit-of-the-season/xmas-tree/#main" data-orig-file="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/xmas-tree.jpg" data-orig-size="734,962" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta='{"aperture":"0","credit":"","camera":"","caption":"","created_timestamp":"0","copyright":"","focal_length":"0","iso":"0","shutter_speed":"0","title":"","orientation":"1"}' data-image-title="xmas tree" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="&lt;p&gt;Artwork by the talented illustrator, Margaret W. Tarrant. For more info on her life and work, click the image.&lt;/p&gt;
" data-medium-file="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/xmas-tree.jpg?w=229" data-large-file="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/xmas-tree.jpg?w=660" src="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/xmas-tree.jpg?w=229" alt="" width="390" height="511" data-sanitized-class="wp-image-12663 "></a><p data-sanitized-id="caption-attachment-12663" data-sanitized-class="wp-caption-text">Artwork by the talented illustrator, Margaret W. Tarrant. For more info on her life and work, click the image.</p></div>
<p><span>.</span></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 23:00:05 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983931</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Skin Deep is on sale</title>
			<link>https://blog.lauramichet.com/skin-deep-is-on-sale-new/</link>
						<dc:creator>lauram</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Skin Deep is in the Steam winter sale! I should have mentioned this in my previous posts on the topic of our many accolades, but I'll mention it now.</p>
<p>The winter sale runs until early January. The game is 35% off.</p>
<p>Check it out <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/301280/Skin_Deep/">here!</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 21:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983930</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>No stars</title>
			<link>https://adactio.com/journal/22317</link>
						<category>reviews</category>
			<category>ratings</category>
			<category>stars</category>
			<category>uber</category>
			<category>data</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>It’s getting towards the end of the year. That’s when I put together <a href="https://adactio.com/journal/tags/books,202">a post reviewing the books I’ve read in the previous twelve months</a>.</p>

<p>I think I might change things up in 2026. Instead of waiting until the end of the year to write all the little reviews at once, I think I should write a review as soon as I finish a book. Instead of holding onto my reckons for months, I can just set them free one at a time.</p>

<p>And I think I’m done with ratings. Stars. I’m not sure why I ever started, to be honest. Probably because <a href="https://adactio.com/journal/22296">everyone else was doing it</a>. But they kind of just get in the way. I spend far too long deliberating about how many stars to give a book when I should be spending that time describing the effect that the book had on me.</p>

<p>In any case, books, movies, music …it’s all entirely subjective. Assigning stars gives a veneer of something measurable, countable, and objective. That’s not how art works.</p>

<p>But that’s just my opinion.</p>

<p>I think I’ve also developed more of an aversion to scoring things the more it’s crept into everyday life. It feels like you can’t perform any kind of transaction without being asked later to rate the experience.</p>

<p>I remember the first time I was ever in an Uber. This was many years ago in San Francisco. I was with a bunch of friends at an after-party for An Event Apart in the TypeKit offices. Someone suggested that we move on to a second location and proceeded to whip out the Uber app.</p>

<p>I remember looking at the little icon of the car moving in real time as it approached our location. So futuristic!</p>

<p>We all bundled into the car and off we went. The driver was a really nice guy. But at some point he made a navigational error and took us off track. He fixed it, but I remember my friend who had summoned the Uber was kind of miffed.</p>

<p>When we were getting out of the car, the driver apologised profusely before driving off. My friend—who was basically showing me how this whole Uber thing worked—explained that he would now give a less than stellar review for the driver, becuase of that directional snafu.</p>

<p>“Ah, come on”, I said, “he was a nice guy.”</p>

<p>“This is how the app gets accurate data”, he responded.</p>

<p>“But …it’s a person”, I said.</p>

<p>Something about reviewing a person felt so wrong to me. Books, movies, music …I get it. But applying the same logic to a human being. That just didn’t sit right with me.</p>

<p>Now we’re expected to review humans all the time. It still feels wrong to me.</p>

<p>That’s probably why I’m done with ratings. No more stars from me.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:34:35 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983929</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Christmas Decoration</title>
			<link>https://sigmarootpi.com/snap/christmas-decoration/</link>
						<dc:creator>Rishabh</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p></p><div data-sanitized-class="blog-posts">
<img src="https://sigmarootpi.com/assets/images/photo_posts/2025-12-24-IMG_0640.jpeg">
</div><p></p>
<p>📍Funchal, Madeira Island, Portugal.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983928</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>GPT is not a mystery anymore</title>
			<link>https://sigmarootpi.com/posts/2025-12-24-gpt-is-not-a-mystery-anymore/</link>
						<dc:creator>Rishabh</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I came across this YouTube <a href="https://youtu.be/D8GOeCFFby4">video</a> explaining what exactly a GPT does behind the scene. It kinda reveals the mystery of the black box, which is known as <strong>Grokking</strong>. This is a weird phenomenon which indicates when a GPT model moves from learning to creating. Interestingly, this transition is not immediate. There is usually a long delay between those two events. It was first discovered by OpenAI by mistake—no wonder great discoveries are made by mistakes.</p>
<p>The video follows the research of a two years old <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2301.05217v1">article</a> in which researchers used a simplified GPT to recreate the transition from learning to creating. What was mind blowing is that <strong>Fourier series</strong> like patterns appeared when GPT develops an understanding of the problem.</p>
<p>Isnt it crazy!!!</p>
<p>So what ChatGPT has now is some complex combination of mathematical functions representing human knowledge. This made me hopeful as, contrary to the claim, its not an intelligence but mathematical function giving output for an input.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983927</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Merry Christmas!</title>
			<link>https://hamatti.org/posts/merry-christmas-2025/</link>
						<dc:creator>Juha-Matti Santala</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>
  It’s Christmas Eve today and that’s when we in Finland celebrate Christmas. If
  you’re reading this when it comes out, I’m likely sitting at the Christmas
  table, feasting on wonderful food that our family has set up and enjoying
  watching my siblings’ children enjoy the wonders of Christmas season.
</p>

<p>
  Thus, I reserve this week in the blog to wish you all merry Christmas and
  happy holidays.
</p>

<p>
  2025 has been a year full of wonderful people and encounters. If our paths
  crossed this year, whether in personal life, through communities, at work or
  online, I’m thankful for that and I’m happy you’ve been part of my life this
  year ❤️.
</p>

<p>
  While the last few years since the pandemic haven’t been exactly smooth
  sailing, I’ve been blessed to have so many great people in my life through all
  that and in the grand scheme of things, that’s really what I’ll remember from
  these times and what really matters.
</p>

<p>
  I will take a deeper dive into my year next Wednesday with my annual Year in
  Review post but for now, it’s time to enjoy good food and company and rest and
  relax.
</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983926</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What I did in 2025</title>
			<link>https://blueberrylemonade.pika.page/posts/what-i-did-in-2025</link>
						<description><![CDATA[<div data-sanitized-class="trix-content">
  <p>As I get older, the years are all starting to blur together.</p>
<p>On top of that, I always have a tendency to fear that I’m sitting around and wasting my life, accomplishing nothing of interest. Wasting my “potential”, whatever that was.</p>
<p>So for those two reasons, I started making these year-end recap posts as a record to look back on. I made one for <a href="https://blueberrylemonade.pika.page/posts/what-i-did-in-2023">2023</a> and <a href="https://blueberrylemonade.pika.page/posts/what-i-did-in-2024">2024</a>. It’s mostly just for my future self. It helps remind me of what made each year different, what I accomplished, and what happened.</p>
<p>So, let me attempt to recap the year.</p>

<hr>
<h2 data-sanitized-id="things-i-did">
<a href="https://blueberrylemonade.pika.page/posts/what-i-did-in-2025#things-i-did" title="Link to this heading" data-sanitized-class="anchor"></a>Things I did</h2>
<ul><li><p>I’ve kept up with going to the gym twice a week. I lost a month or two to travel and Rhythm Doctor launching, but otherwise stuck with it. I even paid for a personal trainer to give me pointers for a few sessions. I had mixed feelings on that experience but it taught me some handy basics.</p></li></ul>
<ul><li><p>I leased a new car! This was my first time ever car shopping. Before this we were using an old hand-me-down from my partner’s family. The process was annoying but not too bad. Our salesman was an anime weeb who loves MOBAs. I hate having to pay the lease, lol.</p></li></ul>
<ul><li><p>Still working on my game <a href="https://kyle-labriola.itch.io/tower-of-modula">Tower of Modula</a>. I made some decent progress: more floors, adding a dedicated slot for equipment that grants Instant skills, and messing around with the battle UI. I even showed the game off on a laptop at a gamedev event and got in-person feedback, which was exciting. Sadly, progress slowed down massively and I wasn’t able to finish in 2025 like I wanted. It wouldn’t have been responsible to keep dedicating time to it when Rhythm Doctor needed my attention. Hoping to force myself to “finish” it in some form in 2026.</p></li></ul>
<ul><li><p>Still doing music lessons! They’re going well. I’ve made a mini soundtrack for Tower of Modula, which has been fun. I’m itching to make some new, very different music unrelated to video games. I’ve barely scratched the surface of what I want to do with music.</p></li></ul>
<ul><li><p>Still doing therapy. Is that an accomplishment?</p></li></ul>
<ul><li><p>I know it’s not exactly groundbreaking, but I went to a No Kings Protest. Which I think might have been my first or second protest ever? I get nervous about this type of thing so the No Kings one was a nice way to get experience.</p></li></ul>
<ul><li><p>I went to MAGwest! It was fun. I got to see my friend Lexie perform, as well as attend an aivi+surasshu concert. I think next year I might try to get a table for my own game.</p></li></ul>
<ul><li><p>I went on a trip to Disney World with my family. It was only my second time going to a Disney park, the first was when I was in high school. Had a good time. It was particularly special because it was the first time for my niece and nephew, and my Dad was healthy enough from cancer treatments to go. I’d be down to do it again, or to go somewhere else.</p></li></ul>
<ul><li><p>One of the games I work on for 7th Beat Games, Rhythm Doctor, released on December 6th! Or to be more specific it finished Early Access and entered 1.0. It was a bit of a rocky process, especially in the week before and after launch, but I’m overall happy and relieved. The game seems to have been received well by players and critics. I had a very large part in writing Act 6 and the finale. I’ve seen that the writing has resonated with a lot of players, so that’s a relief.</p></li></ul>
<ul><li><p>I kept up with this blog! I ended up being pretty active on here. If you haven’t already, I suggest subscribing via RSS or email.</p></li></ul>
<h2 data-sanitized-id="things-i-want-to-work-on">
<a href="https://blueberrylemonade.pika.page/posts/what-i-did-in-2025#things-i-want-to-work-on" title="Link to this heading" data-sanitized-class="anchor"></a>Things I want to work on</h2>
<ul><li><p>I want to get back into practicing piano. My habit kind of fell apart around March, but I haven’t lost an interest in it. My goal is really just to be able to play very simple songs and to be able to play chord progressions. I mostly want it to help me with composition, not for the sake of performing it or anything.</p></li></ul>
<ul><li><p>I want to get better at budgeting. This year I became a lot more conscious of my spending and saving than I had been for the past few years. I want to continue that and try to actually improve my sense of budgeting. I think I’ll need to make some sort of concrete plan, instead of just an ambiguous goal.</p></li></ul>
<ul><li><p>I want to get better at calling my senators and such to voice my opinion on legislation. Doing that consistently was one of my goals for this year, but I only ended up doing it like 3 or 4 times (plus 2 for the payment processors) and then I kind of lost the habit. I think a decent goal to aim for would be “once a month.”</p></li></ul>
<ul><li><p>I want to get better at journaling. I’m 2 years into a journal but I’ve been skipping a lot of days (and need to do a lot of catch-up on the days I’m not skipping.) I think my mistake was in attempting to write really long bullet lists of everything I did that day. I should go back to trying to write 2 sentences per day.</p></li></ul>
<ul><li><p>I want to spend less time on social media. I’ve already written multiple pieces on this blog detailing my relationship with social media, so you probably know where I’m coming from. Since I knew I’d have to promote Rhythm Doctor, I always told myself I’d have to hold on until 2026.</p></li></ul>
<ul><li><p>I don’t really put much stake in New Year’s Resolutions, but if I were to state specific goals for 2026…I think I mostly just want to focus on the things I had been doing in 2025: writing music, making games, practicing piano, and going to the gym. Instead of adding new lofty goals to my plate, I think I’d rather get more consistent with those things.</p></li></ul>
<ul><li><p>I want to re-name this blog. I’m tired of the name Blueberry Lemonade.</p></li></ul>
<h2 data-sanitized-id="other-things-that-happened">
<a href="https://blueberrylemonade.pika.page/posts/what-i-did-in-2025#other-things-that-happened" title="Link to this heading" data-sanitized-class="anchor"></a>Other Things That Happened</h2>
<ul><li><p>I bought a new computer! Or rather, I bought all the parts and a very kind friend of mine built it. She’s cool and I’m super grateful. One of the biggest motivators for getting a new PC was so that Monster Hunter Wilds would run properly. Then I was able to play together with the cool friend! A virtuous cycle…</p></li></ul>
<ul><li><p>I got the Switch 2 on launch day. I could sense that the “magic” of a new console launch is quickly going to become a thing of the past, so I wanted that little childish bit of pomp and circumstance one more time. Was it worth it? Ehh…I’m not sure. I don’t regret the purchase, to be clear. I love my Switch 2. I like DK Bananza and Mario Kart World, and have enjoyed a bunch of optimized Switch 2 editions. I’m the sicko who got Welcome Tour and Drag X Drive. Plus, though it may be controversial, I kind of like that it’s slightly larger. But it definitely wasn’t “necessary” or “magical” getting it on launch day. My big regret is not socializing with anyone on the line outside of Gamestop!</p></li></ul>
<ul><li><p>In sadder news, both my partner and I had deaths in our families back to back. That was tough, and hard to grapple with, but we both flew out and spent time with our families. In my case I was able to spend time with my grandpa in the hospital and in hospice. I was there and held his hand as he died. I had never been through anything quite like that before, and I did my best to be a pillar of support for my parents and my uncles. I dread the prospect of future tragedies, and have a sinking feeling in my chest as I watch my parents get older and older, but I will try to be strong for everyone depending on me.</p></li></ul>
<p>I went back to my 2024 post and saw that I reflected on “not being an artist anymore” and that has never felt more true. Or, at least, I don’t regularly make illustrations or characters anymore. This year felt like the time I “made peace” with that. For better or worse, I am closer to identifying as “a gamedev.'“</p>
<p>I used to have like a 10 year streak of reflecting on each year via a compilation of my drawings, tracking my improvement, but I really don’t draw enough to warrant continuing that. Also, I definitely feel myself getting really rusty and backsliding in a lot of areas.</p>
<p>Making Tower of Modula has been a small balm for that, as it’s a project where I have to come up with characters but I don’t let myself fixate on the quality of them. It’s been fun to draw for.</p>
<p>Anyway, I think this post is long enough. Onward to 2026, I guess?</p>
</div>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:58:46 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983925</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Quoting Salvatore Sanfilippo</title>
			<link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Dec/23/salvatore-sanfilippo/#atom-everything</link>
						<dc:creator>Simon Willison</dc:creator>
			<category>salvatore-sanfilippo</category>
			<category>lua</category>
			<category>redis</category>
			<category>javascript</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<blockquote cite="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367224#46368706"><p>If this [MicroQuickJS] had been available in 2010, Redis scripting would have been JavaScript and not Lua. Lua was chosen based on the implementation requirements, not on the language ones... (small, fast, ANSI-C). I appreciate certain ideas in Lua, and people love it, but I was never able to <em>like</em> Lua, because it departs from a more Algol-like syntax and semantics without good reasons, for my taste. This creates friction for newcomers. I love friction when it opens new useful ideas and abstractions that are worth it, if you learn SmallTalk or FORTH and for some time you are lost, it's part of how the languages are different. But I think for Lua this is not true enough: it feels like it departs from what people know without good reasons.</p></blockquote>
<p data-sanitized-class="cite">— <a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367224#46368706">Salvatore Sanfilippo</a>, Hacker News comment on MicroQuickJS</p>

    <p>Tags: <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/salvatore-sanfilippo">salvatore-sanfilippo</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/lua">lua</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/redis">redis</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/javascript">javascript</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983924</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>My Year in Music: 2025</title>
			<link>https://thomasrigby.com/posts/my-year-in-music-2025/</link>
						<dc:creator>Thomas Rigby</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><picture><source type="image/webp"><img src="https://thomasrigby.com/images/Icoflj--I9-600.png" alt="a pixel grid heatmap showing when and how much I have listened to music. like the github commits one but for music." width="900" height="256" data-sanitized-class=""></picture><br>
<br>
</p>
<div data-sanitized-class="markdown-alert markdown-alert-tip"><p data-sanitized-class="markdown-alert-title">Caveat</p><p>This is, naturally, not exhaustive. I use <a href="https://last.fm/">last.fm</a> on my phone and my laptop to scrobble music I listen to while I'm on my own. As other people have pointed out, this doesn't capture music listened to with friends and family, nor does it log public music from the radio, bars, or shopping centres, for example.</p>
</div>
<h2>tl;dr</h2>
<p><picture><source type="image/webp"><img src="https://thomasrigby.com/images/D5COjXlLYL-600.png" alt="the cover of The Cure Greatest Hits above two lists. The first is top five artists and includes The Cure, Orla Gartland, Chloe Slater, Placebo, and Arch Enemy. The second is top 5 tracks which are only the track list from Chloe Slater's EP Nothing Shines on this Island" width="900" height="1600" data-sanitized-class=""></picture><br>
<br>
</p>
<p>A Social Media™-friendly shareable <a href="https://wrapped.devmatei.com/"><em>Wrapped</em></a> image showing the slightly unhinged top 5 artists and tracks of 2025.</p>
<img src="https://thomasrigby.com/images/7cdZHJx69G-600.webp" alt="a still from a New Zealand TV show showing a young person in studded leather and Black Metal corpse paint eating ice cream on a bench with another person who looks wholesome and blonde and peppy" width="600" height="543" data-sanitized-class="">
    
    
(Never have I felt this meme so acutely.)
<h2>January</h2>
<ul>
<li>Top Artist: Annalisa (35 plays)</li>
<li>Top Album: <em>Reroute to Remain</em> by In Flames (17 plays)</li>
<li>Top Track: <em>Bad Apple</em> by Lambrini Girls (4 plays)</li>
</ul>
<h2>February</h2>
<ul>
<li>Top Artist: Chloe Slater (25 plays)</li>
<li>Top Album: <em>choke enough</em> by Oklou (17 plays)</li>
<li>Top Track: <em>Nothing Shines on this Island</em> by Chloe Slater (5 plays)</li>
</ul>
<h2>March</h2>
<ul>
<li>Top Artist: The Cure (32 plays)</li>
<li>Top Album: <em>Quarter Life Crisis</em> by Baby Queen (22 plays)</li>
<li>Top Track: <em>Sheaf &amp; Feld</em> by Jim Ghedi (3 plays)</li>
</ul>
<h2>April</h2>
<ul>
<li>Top Artist: Fight Like Apes (34 plays)</li>
<li>Top Album: <em>The Rise and Fall of a Midwest Princess</em> by Chappell Roan (15 plays)</li>
<li>Top Track: <em>Crystal Days</em> by Echo and the Bunnymen (3 plays)</li>
</ul>
<h2>May</h2>
<ul>
<li>Top Artist: The Cure (38 plays)</li>
<li>Top Album: <em>Greatest Hits</em> by The Cure (23 plays)</li>
<li>Top Track:  <em>Same Love</em> by Macklemore &amp; Ryan Lewis with Mary Lambert (7 plays)</li>
</ul>
<h2>June</h2>
<ul>
<li>Top Artist: Katatonia (26 plays)</li>
<li>Top Album: <em>STILL BLUE</em> by iamamiwhoami &amp; ionnalee (16 plays)</li>
<li>Top Track: <em>Apply Some Pressure</em> by Maxïmo Park (4 plays)</li>
</ul>
<h2>July</h2>
<ul>
<li>Top Artist: Placebo (39 plays)</li>
<li>Top Album: <em>Lo-files</em> by Bring Me The Horizon and lophiile (14 plays)</li>
<li>Top Track: <em>(U)topia.drm</em>  by Bring Me The Horizon and lophiile (5 plays)</li>
</ul>
<h2>August</h2>
<ul>
<li>Top Artist: The New Eves (18 plays)</li>
<li>Top Album: <em>"The New Eve is Rising"</em> by The New Eves (18 plays)</li>
<li>Top Track: <em>"No Comply"</em> by Senser (3 plays)</li>
</ul>
<h2>September</h2>
<ul>
<li>Top Artist: NewDad (19 plays)</li>
<li>Top Album: <em>"Cacophony"</em> by Paris Paloma (17 plaus)</li>
<li>Top Track: <em>"The Look of Love"</em> by ABC (3 plays)</li>
</ul>
<h2>October</h2>
<ul>
<li>Top Artist: The Indelicates (20 plays)</li>
<li>Top Album: <em>"The Feeding of the 5000"</em> by Crass (17 plays)</li>
<li>Top Track: <em>"Fight for your right"</em> by Beastie Boys (3 plays)astie Boys (3 pla)</li>
</ul>
<h2>November</h2>
<ul>
<li>Top Artist: Warrington-Runcorn New Town Development Plan (28 plays)</li>
<li>Top Album: <em>"Quarter Life Crisis"</em> by Baby Queen (17 plays)</li>
<li>Top Track: <em>"Isobel"</em> by Björk (5 plays)</li>
</ul>
<h2>December</h2>
<ul>
<li>Top Artist: Lily Allen (34 plays)</li>
<li>Top Album: <em>"West End Girl"</em> by Lily Allen (34 plays)</li>
<li>Top Track: <em>"The Shadowsea"</em> by Patrick Wolf (4 plays)</li>
</ul>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 14:50:01 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983923</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#AdventJukebox 23: Underneath the Tree by Kelly Clarkson</title>
			<link>https://thomasrigby.com/posts/adventjukebox-23-underneath-the-tree-kelly-clarkson/</link>
						<dc:creator>Thomas Rigby</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://song.link/y/IuaW6w3Mh4c"><em>"Underneath the Tree"</em></a> by <strong>Kelly Clarkson</strong></p>
<p>Baader-Meinhof Syndrome or genuine omnipotence, I will never know, but this 2013 banger seems to have been everywhere this year. Not many artists can pull off a Christmas song this grand. A modern classic.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:58:52 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983922</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>MicroQuickJS</title>
			<link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Dec/23/microquickjs/#atom-everything</link>
						<dc:creator>Simon Willison</dc:creator>
			<category>c</category>
			<category>javascript</category>
			<category>nodejs</category>
			<category>python</category>
			<category>sandboxing</category>
			<category>ai</category>
			<category>webassembly</category>
			<category>deno</category>
			<category>pyodide</category>
			<category>generative-ai</category>
			<category>llms</category>
			<category>claude-code</category>
			<category>fabrice-bellard</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="https://github.com/bellard/mquickjs">MicroQuickJS</a></strong></p>
New project from programming legend Fabrice Bellard, of ffmpeg and QEMU and QuickJS and <a href="https://bellard.org/">so much more</a> fame:
<blockquote>
<p>MicroQuickJS (aka. MQuickJS) is a Javascript engine targetted at embedded systems. It compiles and runs Javascript programs with as low as 10 kB of RAM. The whole engine requires about 100 kB of ROM (ARM Thumb-2 code) including the C library. The speed is comparable to QuickJS.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It supports <a href="https://github.com/bellard/mquickjs/blob/17ce6fe54c1ea4f500f26636bd22058fce2ce61a/README.md#javascript-subset-reference">a subset of full JavaScript</a>, though it looks like a rich and full-featured subset to me.</p>
<p>One of my ongoing interests is sandboxing: mechanisms for executing untrusted code - from end users or generated by LLMs - in an environment that restricts memory usage and applies a strict time limit and restricts file or network access. Could MicroQuickJS be useful in that context?</p>
<p>I fired up Claude Code for web (on my iPhone) and kicked off <a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/Nov/6/async-code-research/">an asynchronous research project</a> to see explore that question:</p>
<p>My full prompt <a href="https://github.com/simonw/research/pull/50#issue-3757781692">is here</a>. It started like this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><code>Clone https://github.com/bellard/mquickjs to /tmp</code></p>
<p><code>Investigate this code as the basis for a safe sandboxing environment for running untrusted code such that it cannot exhaust memory or CPU or access files or the network</code></p>
<p><code>First try building python bindings for this using FFI - write a script that builds these by checking out the code to /tmp and building against that, to avoid copying the C code in this repo permanently. Write and execute tests with pytest to exercise it as a sandbox</code></p>
<p><code>Then build a "real" Python extension not using FFI and experiment with that</code></p>
<p><code>Then try compiling the C to WebAssembly and exercising it via both node.js and Deno, with a similar suite of tests [...]</code></p>
</blockquote>
<p>I later added to the interactive session:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><code>Does it have a regex engine that might allow a resource exhaustion attack from an expensive regex?</code></p>
</blockquote>
<p>(The answer was no - the regex engine calls the interrupt handler even during pathological expression backtracking, meaning that any configured time limit should still hold.)</p>
<p>Here's <a href="https://gistpreview.github.io/?6e07c54db7bb8ed8aa0eccfe4a384679">the full transcript</a> and the <a href="https://github.com/simonw/research/blob/main/mquickjs-sandbox/README.md">final report</a>.</p>
<p>Some key observations:</p>
<ul>
<li>MicroQuickJS is <em>very</em> well suited to the sandbox problem. It has robust near and time limits baked in, it doesn't expose any dangerous primitive like filesystem of network access and even has a regular expression engine that protects against exhaustion attacks (provided you configure a time limit).</li>
<li>Claude span up and tested a Python library that calls a MicroQuickJS shared library (involving a little bit of extra C), a compiled a Python binding and a library that uses the original MicroQuickJS CLI tool. All of those approaches work well.</li>
<li>Compiling to WebAssembly was a little harder. It got a version working in Node.js and Deno and Pyodide, but the Python libraries wasmer and wasmtime proved harder, apparently because "mquickjs uses setjmp/longjmp for error handling". It managed to get to a working wasmtime version with <a href="https://github.com/simonw/research/blob/main/mquickjs-sandbox/README.md#working-solution">a gross hack</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>I'm really excited about this. MicroQuickJS is tiny, full featured, looks robust and comes from excellent pedigree. I think this makes for a very solid new entrant in the quest for a robust sandbox.</p>
<p><strong>Update</strong>: I had Claude Code build <a href="https://tools.simonwillison.net/microquickjs">tools.simonwillison.net/microquickjs</a>, an interactive web playground for trying out the WebAssembly build of MicroQuickJS, adapted from my previous <a href="https://tools.simonwillison.net/quickjs">QuickJS plaground</a>. My QuickJS page loads 2.28 MB (675 KB transferred). The MicroQuickJS one loads 303 KB (120 KB transferred).</p>
<p>Here are <a href="https://github.com/simonw/tools/pull/180#issue-3758595291">the prompts I used</a> for that.


    </p><p>Tags: <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/c">c</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/javascript">javascript</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/nodejs">nodejs</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/python">python</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/sandboxing">sandboxing</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai">ai</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/webassembly">webassembly</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/deno">deno</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/pyodide">pyodide</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/generative-ai">generative-ai</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llms">llms</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/claude-code">claude-code</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/fabrice-bellard">fabrice-bellard</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 13:53:40 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1766601095983921</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
