<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >
	<channel>
		<title> | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>http://192.168.1.206/FreshRSS/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of  | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 15:34:32 -0700</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 22:34:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="/i/?a=rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
				<item>
			<title>Thinking About Going Dark on Social Media</title>
			<link>https://iam.skoo.bz/thinking-about-going-dark-on-social-media/</link>
						<dc:creator>S. L.</dc:creator>
			<category>Life</category>
			<category>Tech</category>
			<media:content url="https://iam.skoo.bz/content/images/2025/11/photo-1608093310256-d8289063a5e7.jpeg" medium="image"></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://iam.skoo.bz/content/images/2025/11/photo-1608093310256-d8289063a5e7.jpeg" alt="Thinking About Going Dark on Social Media"><p>This is just a thought that’s been on my mind the last couple of days. I’ve already kicked social media apps like Facebook and Instagram off my phone around the end of October. The next step would be to kick these apps off of my iPad as well and potentially put a block on them in my browser on my laptop. Beyond that, it’s going dark entirely.</p><p>I’ve already done quite a bit. I’ve limited notifications, turning them off on my devices entirely and limiting what in-app notifications pop up. I’ve filtered the hell out of my Facebook feed, limiting it to close friends only and scrutinizing who I let follow me on these platforms and what they can see if I do let them on.</p><p>Yet, it doesn’t feel like enough. It still feels far too noisy. I still feel the pull to check these things on my devices. I’ve seen a bit of advice that we should try reading, journaling, or simply sitting in silence during the first part of our day, but I find these things even hard to try or maintain with the constant pull of these social networks. Even worse, none of it feels fulfilling. None of this feels like I’m connecting with anyone on them. Definitely not in the same way I would if I were actually having a conversation with them.</p><p>I recently wrote about how I wish I had a <a href="https://iam.skoo.bz/a-feed-of-my-friends/">feed of my friends</a> in my RSS reader I could look forward to instead. Something that felt more intentional and less influenced by the noise of socials. Something that feels deeper and more intimate. I view personal websites as an extension of our homes. This is where I’m the most comfortable telling my stories and speaking my truths and ideas. This platform nurtures this kind of thing. It’s me with a blank canvas to write whatever my fingers can output onto a keyboard. I can pause without getting distracted. I can calculate my next move. It’s serene.</p><p>This makes me think about going dark on socials and only posting here. Honestly, I don’t feel comfortable with the number of coworkers I have following me on Facebook for example. I’m in a leadership position and our company policy states I can only hang out with those who are my peers, or of a same ranking as me. That severely limits who I can interact with in person. Social media gives me the same vibe. I don’t necessarily want some of these folks knowing much about me off the clock. I don’t want to be seen with them. And some, I don’t trust to protect my reputation. If I’m to promote up, then I need to stay off people’s radars in the wrong way.</p><p>Coincidentally, because of Meta’s shitty algorithms, anytime I’ve left posts to my site on my Facebook page, they’ve gotten next to nothing for clicks according to my site’s analytics. So, the chance many of them find my website is slim. I feel very comfortable sticking to my personal site and its federated presence on Mastodon.</p><p>So, what’s next? Apple has some built in blocks within its settings that can block you from certain apps and websites, or at least limit the time spent there. The other part of this is to fill the time I’m on socials with something more fulfilling, like writing, taking a walk, exercising, reading, learning, and so many other things I want to get into. I want to get back in shape and ride my bike more, maybe becoming a bit of a nerd around that. I’d like to check out concerts and sporting events. I also want to get serious about listening to music again, perhaps even trying to buy a vinyl or two every month from the local shops here. All of these are better options than doomscrolling and getting spied on.</p><p>But here’s the other part of the story. I’m going quietly outside of this post. I promise you, no one notices. No one ever does. My brother is an example of this. He has a Facebook profile that he’s never posted to, yet people still wish him happy birthday every year as if he were a regular. Nobody notices when you don’t use the shit.</p><p>I feel like all of this will get me back to having a more still mind. Coincidentally, one if my favorite people Craig Mod <a href="https://craigmod.com/ridgeline/217/?ref=iam.skoo.bz">just wrote about this subject</a>:</p><blockquote>The modern smartphone, laden with the corporate ecosystem pulsing underneath its screen, robs us of this feeling, conspires to keep us from “true” fullness. The swiping, the news cycles, the screaming, the idiocy — if anything destroys a muse, it’s this. If anything keeps you locked into a fetid loop of looking, looking, and looking once more at the train wreck, it’s this. I find it impossible to feel fullness, even in the slightest, after having spent just a bit of a day in the thralls of the algorithms.<br><br>The smartphone eradicates “space” in the mind. With that psychic loss of space, grace becomes impossible. You see the knock-on effects of this rippling out across the world politically.</blockquote><p>He then continues:</p><blockquote>I realize the above might sound like the rant of a crank. But I think the detrimental — psychological and physiological — nature of doomscrolling, of being sucked into the algorithms, is something we all “know,” though — because we’re so cloaked in “onlineness” — often forget. The good thing: It’s easy to experience fullness, to pull your head out of the muck, to be the Goon Antipode, to cleave space from the online sludge in the mind, to hear some kind of “inner voice” once again, and then to act on what inspiration comes from that.</blockquote><p>Seriously, check out <a href="https://craigmod.com/?ref=iam.skoo.bz">Craig’s work</a>, it’s great! But the point is there: we start to think for ourselves more the less we’re doomscrolling and actually living, creating, and learning. I feel like we’re collectively aware of it, but it feels like we’re also collectively waiting for everyone else to make the move away. I’m making that decision for myself now, starting with 30 days and going from there.</p><p>In the meantime, I look forward to living life with my friends and finding inspiration from my experiences. I’d love to follow more personal sites, so if you have one, <a href="mailto:blog@skoo.bz">let me know</a>. And if you are local to me, seek me out. I’m not hard to find. Be good to yourselves.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 13:44:36 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763330521919613</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>#TIL: Intentionally blank page</title>
			<link>https://thomasrigby.com/posts/til-intentionally-blank-page/</link>
						<dc:creator>Thomas Rigby</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Courtesy of <a href="https://kayserifserif.place/">Katherine</a> via <a href="https://www.nicchan.me/">Nic Chan</a>'s <a href="https://manuelmoreale.com/interview/nic-chan"><em>"People &amp; Blogs"</em></a> interview, I learned about intentionally blank pages.</p>
<p>Having read a <a href="https://thomasrigby.com/reading/">book or two</a> in my time, I've seen these blank pages; usually a quirk of the way books are bound in bundles of evenly numbered pages that doesn't always align exactly to the number of printed/written pages.</p>
<p>This is a print-only phenomenon — digital books and websites don't have those printing constraints. But, in memory of those pages being lost to the endless march of technology, the <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20180224075941/http://this-page-intentionally-left-blank.org/whythat.html">"This Page Left Intentionally Blank" Project</a> is calling on us, the webmasters of personal sites, to add an intentionally blank page to our websites.</p>
<p>You can find mine at <a href="https://thomasrigby.com/blank/"><code>/blank</code></a>. What a lovely idea.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 13:22:59 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763330521919612</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Weeknotes: 2025-W46</title>
			<link>https://thomasrigby.com/posts/2025-w46/</link>
						<dc:creator>Thomas Rigby</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<h2>10th November - 16th November</h2>
<p>I went for a walk this week; took the dog out early doors, pre-dawn. I thought it was a bit blowy. When I got home my wife informed me there's a yellow weather warning for a named storm coming in.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cheshire-live.co.uk/news/chester-cheshire-news/live-updates-cheshire-road-shut-32875545">Storm Claudia took out some trees, cars, and houses</a>. We escaped the worst of it; the bins were thrown around and fence panels dislodged. I had to drag one out of the road at near midnight to prevent accidents.</p>
<hr>
<p>Visited the new Havas Village Manchester offices this week. They are currently rather sterile and corporate but, hopefully, some personality will get injected once we're are in and "being creative". The weirdest thing, though, is I can see my old house from my new desk…</p>
<hr>
<p>I threw a roll of film through my replacement Minolta SRT303 and posted it to <a href="https://photohippo.co.uk/">Photo Hippo</a> for development and scanning. The mirror return mechanism is a little sticky which wasn't mentioned in the listing! It shouldn't affect the final images though, it just creates a bit of an annoying distraction while shooting. Hopefully, it'll not be an issue until I can get it lubricated.</p>
<hr>
<p>I am now pretty convinced there are two tawny owls; one in the big tree by the field at the end of the village and one in the copse by the cemetery. Although, with a top speed of 80kph (50mph) and near-silent flight, one could have easily beaten me.</p>
<hr>
<blockquote>
<p><q>The hour is come but not the man</q><br>
<cite>Susan Cooper, <em>"Greenwitch"</em></cite></p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<h2>Links of Interest™</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://fmjansen.com/posts/started-phd/">PhD on applications for identity wallets</a></li>
<li><a href="https://joelchrono.xyz/blog/52-weenotes-later/">52 Week Notes later</a></li>
<li><a href="https://anniemueller.com/posts/outside-sad-is-better-than-inside-sad">Outside sad is better than inside sad</a></li>
<li><a href="https://pxlnv.com/linklog/lastfm-2002/">In 2002, Last.fm Was the Cutting Edge of the Social Web</a></li>
</ul>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:45:24 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763330521919611</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Clepsydra</title>
			<link>https://tacitexposure.bearblog.dev/clepsydra/</link>
						<dc:creator>tacitexposure</dc:creator>
			<category>poetry</category>
			<category>thoughtful</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>The year must sing.<br>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=08HcdIM3qSs">Its' time yet nigh, shall be anew.</a><br>
Number, one more.</p>
<p>The stream measures.<br>
The lake collects.<br>
The fall ensures the cloud accepts.</p>
<p>Drops coalesce, come into rest.<br>
Into the dirt where they fit best.<br>
Azul to somber, breath becomes tight.<br>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IvUU8joBb1Q">Rapid, unending. To day, through night</a>.</p>
<p>Years gone by, year to come.<br>
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uXxTZAiQp2k">Time waxes. Rain, bar none</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://tacitexposure.bearblog.dev/feynman" title="Surely You're Joking, Mr. Feynman by Richard Feynman" data-sanitized-class="previous-post">Previous</a> </p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 14:33:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763330521919610</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>2025-w46</title>
			<link>https://hlomen.bearblog.dev/2025-w46/</link>
						<dc:creator>hlomen</dc:creator>
			<category>weeknotes</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>The word that sums up this week is: <strong>tired</strong>. A new level of whole-family weariness has set in, with one of my kids in particular hitting the end 🤪 on Friday. The weekend has been great but I fear we are setting forth into a new week having not really recovered. I’ve not bothered to keep up with my journal this week; and unusually, this is written off the cuff instead of based on my hand notes. A sign of the week.</p>
<p>A top moment for me was finishing a new roof for my mini firewood store 🔨. Something I’m looking forward to next week is getting some film 🎞️for my newly replaced and working SLR 📷.</p>
<h3 data-sanitized-id="headlines">headlines</h3><p>🧠 <em>Understanding:</em> My team has been to easily giving me the monkey 🙈<sup data-sanitized-id="fnref-1" data-sanitized-class="footnote-ref"><a href="https://hlomen.bearblog.dev/2025-w46/#fn-1">1</a></sup>. Some complicated family dynamics and a challenge to me in parenting to give the kids gentle attention. Not that I won’t have to keep learning the hard and long way!</p>
<p>🧶 <em>Creating &amp; cultivating:</em> As part of my phone dumbing-down effort (last post) I spent my pocket money on a replacement for my broken 35mm camera. This weekend, making a shelving unit for child #2.</p>
<p>📺 <em>Consuming:</em> Homemade burgers 🍔, yum! Some mulled wine too 🎄.</p>
<p>🔆 <em>Connecting:</em> Had some people round for Sunday lunch, which turned out really well (excellent gammon by my lovely wife). Also was great to visit our regional office to see some colleagues in person, including sitting next to one of my team leads, which was a nice bonus!</p>
<p>✒️ <em>Pen &amp; ink combo:</em> TWSBI 500AL with ⬛️ De Atrementis Vanilla</p>
<p>🏹 <em>For my future self:</em> [onething::I can’t control or make us succeed, but I can try to set us up for sucess]</p>
<hr>
<p>&lt;&lt; <a href="https://hlomen.bearblog.dev/goodbye-whatsapp" title="goodbye whatsapp" data-sanitized-class="previous-post">Previous</a>   &gt;&gt;</p>
<section data-sanitized-class="footnotes">
<ol>
<li data-sanitized-id="fn-1"><p>I.e. the initiative; from a Harvard Business Review article <a href="https://internalmedicinefaculty.wustl.edu/app/uploads/2018/05/Whos-Got-the-Monkey-HBR.pdf">link</a><a href="https://hlomen.bearblog.dev/2025-w46/#fnref-1" data-sanitized-class="footnote">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</section>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763330521919609</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Small Web, Big Voice</title>
			<link>https://kevquirk.com/blog/small-web-big-voice/</link>
						<dc:creator>Kev Quirk</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<div data-sanitized-class="link">
    <h2>Small Web, Big Voice</h2>
    <span>by Andre Franca</span>
    <p>Andre argues that independent blogging isn’t about scale at all, but about integrity — choosing a place you control, writing in your own voice, and keeping the web human.</p>

    <p><a href="https://afranca.com.br/small-web-big-voice" data-sanitized-class="button">Read Post →</a></p>
    <hr data-sanitized-class="email-hidden">
  </div>




<p>I read this post this morning while I was perusing my RSS feeds with a coffee. Firstly, I’m not sharing this because Andre called out my blog (although being bundled with people like <a href="https://rachsmith.com/">Rach</a> and <a href="https://manuelmoreale.com/">Manu</a> is <em>extremely</em> flattering). I’m sharing it because I agree with everything he says in the post.</p>

<p>Having a place on the web that I’m 100% in control of, where I can share my own thoughts, feelings, and opinions is very powerful for me. Over time this blog has evolved from me sharing technical posts most of the time, to a legit personal blog with a technical twist.</p>

<p>Despite what sites like <em>ProBlogger</em> say, I don’t have a niche, and I don’t try to grow my audience (<a href="https://kevquirk.com/blog/revisiting-the-web-analytics-rabbit-hole/">I don’t even know how big my audience is</a>). I just write whatever is on my mind at any given time, and people usually get in touch with me to discuss the topic. It’s fantastic.</p>

<p>If you’re on the fence about starting a blog, I implore you to do so. It’s probably the best thing I’ve ever done with a computer. If you, please drop me an email with the link - I love discovering new blogs!</p>


<div data-sanitized-class="email-hidden">
  <hr>
  <p>Thanks for reading this post via RSS. RSS is great, and you're great for using it. ❤️</p>
  <p>
    <a href="mailto:72ja@qrk.one?subject=Small%20Web,%20Big%20Voice">Reply to this post by email</a>
  </p>
</div>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 09:22:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763321802423692</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The art we make as children</title>
			<link>https://chavanniclass.wordpress.com/2025/11/16/the-art-we-make-as-children/</link>
						<dc:creator>Ratika Deshpande</dc:creator>
			<category>diary</category>
			<category>memoir</category>
			<category>childhood</category>
			<category>notebooks</category>
			<media:content url="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3c01cee950e21d4f28b9086b49afb4c05bddf47c69611ed3eaf3e40277707053?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image"><media:title type="html">ratikadeshpande</media:title></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Since resuming a regular notebook-keeping  habit, I’ve started collecting the “junk” of every day life–tickets, flower, receipts–to have tangible reminders of moments lived. </p>



<p>Yesterday a friend of mine (the same one who <a href="https://chavanniclass.wordpress.com/2025/11/12/little-surprises/">bought star fruits for me</a> the other day) gave me a little tamarind roll, the wrapper of which I pasted in my notebook. It reminded me of the scrapbook I’d kept as a child, when I was about 10-12 (I may have started it at 9; I don’t really remember). I wish I hadn’t thrown it away. I’d collected dozens of chocolate and toffee wrappers and pasted them in it, along with pretty pictures and illustrations from newspapers and magazines.</p>



<p>I also wish I hadn’t thrown away the diary with a golden cover in which I’d written my first poems, as well as a slim blue notebook in which I’d composed poems as well as short stories, written in neat, print handwriting as if I were actually making a <em>book. </em>I can recall that the very first poem in it was one I’d written about my relationship with the girl I used to call my Best Friend Forever (BFF) but with whom I lost all touch five years later. </p>



<p>I can’t recall the other poems but I do remember a couple of short stories. There was one about a Christmas party gone wrong and another that was about a group of friends having creepy experiences in a haunted house that turns out to be a movie set (or something like that). I was in my <em>Goosebumps </em>fan girl phase and so all the stories I wrote were not so much as “influenced” by those books as they were attempts at writing my own <em>Goosebumps </em>stories. I was so confident in my self-perceived ability to write horror back then! Right now, our book club is running a horror comedy writing contest and I feel utterly incapable of writing anything that won’t be, to use some internet vocabulary, a cringefest.</p>



<p>Anyways, the main takeaway from this, which I can’t do anything about but you maybe can, dear reader, is this: no matter what else you purge from your life, <em>never </em>throw away the art you made as a child. I’m going to try to keep this in mind for my own children.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763321802423691</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>i am not my liver</title>
			<link>https://spectre.bearblog.dev/i-am-not-my-liver/</link>
						<dc:creator>spectre</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/spectre/painintheworldnotinthisroom.webp" alt="painintheworldnotinthisroom"></p>
<p>never have i ever been clubbing. never have i ever downloaded bumblebff. never have i ever agreed to spend halloween with a stranger. tonight all three fingers go down.</p>
<p>i try to envision a club. lights? probably. music? top 40s, its a latin club so lots of spanish. people? drunk, hot, stupid. people who know how to dance. people who don't have to think about knowing how to dance. i imagine there is no coat check. that these perfect stupid people who know how to dance dont need jackets or boots or bags. vodka jackets are in style at the club of my naïve imagination.</p>
<p>among these perfect, dancing people, i am jacketed, heeled, and in makeup befitting a 12 year old who just got her first issue of vogue teen. among these perfect, stupid, dancing people i stumble and stagger and reach and move, perhaps with them in color and myself in black and white.</p>
<p>my first step toward becoming stupid hot and dancing is leaving my glasses at home. they ruin the outfit. what do i need to see?</p>
<p>i sat outside the club for 40 minutes. its maybe 3 degrees, my feet hurt, and i just passed a packed small bar with a live MCR coverband. i want to turn around.</p>
<p>my new friend approaches the club, also jacketed. i feel relieved. she says she thought i was a catfish. to tell you the truth, i say, i thought i was a catfish.</p>
<p>we go inside. the bouncer doesnt make small talk. i make a comment to her about it and she looks at me like im kinda dumb. the club is downstairs. the coat check only takes cash because of course they do. she covers me. its 10:40pm and the dance floor is empty aside from a twink dressed like a roman emperor surrounded by 5 incredibly attractive scantily clad women.</p>
<p>may i be reincarnated as a twink during my next trip through samsara.</p>
<p>my friend grabs my hand and drags me to the bar. "what do you want" "i want the chocolate martini" two shots of tequila were ordered. it goes down like water. ive never had tequila before. like water. theres a lime and i dont know what to do with it. she sucks on it after. theres a smooth burn down my throat but i dont really feel it.</p>
<p>she grabs my hand and drags me to the dance floor. we dance. i say i cant dance and we dance. she can dance. some fat tall guy decides he wants to dance. i freeze. she pulls me away. she decides she needs another. more tequila. two shots of tequila. its like water. i think of my friend who swore of tequila after two shots made her vomit. i think ill tell her. it's just like water.</p>
<p>i feel drunk but in control. im on the dance floor and im moving but im really watching. im feeling. i look at her sometimes but not too much. shes looking at me. the room is bright then dark. strobe to disorient. the floor is concrete, not yet filthy, and theres a thick concrete beam in the middle of the floor. i move my feet, two step, four step, left, right. i do the same 3 things with my hands. im trying not to think about it. im trying to make myself one with the room.</p>
<p>i cant help but recall the 8th grade dance. flashing lights, concrete floor, believe it or not roughly the same music. but familiar faces and no booze. i think thats the only difference that matters. i think of myself awkwardly shuffling against my date, moving myself to the music with my friends, swaying awkwardly, uncertain when some criteria like music or people or noise is off.</p>
<p>i am the room. she grabs me and dances with me. stupid hot sexy dancers dont have pockets, they hold their phones all night. she can't grab my right hand thanks to phone so i shove it in my arm pit, we shuffle, i smile, she smiles, we move to the music. she leads but i can't tell if im following. she twirls me and i twirl, i twirl her and she almost falls.</p>
<p>i am the room. two shots. and i thought i was a lightweight.</p>
<p>i set her upright and keep dancing. facing her but separate. i dont think she liked my body language, looking back on it. she turns arounds and grinds on me, i have no idea what to do so i hold her, she stops and goes back to dancing.</p>
<p>they're playing pitbull. they're playing shakira. they're playing tokyo drift. i am the room.</p>
<p>we drift through the room, being pushed and pulled as the dance pit fills. more men. this is a gay club, i think. that doesn't stop them. most of the drifting is trying to avoid them. like werewolves on a full moon halloween has brought them out, i think. i dont freeze anymore, i dont make eye contact.</p>
<p>i think back to white girl dancing. when pitbull tells me to put my hands in the air i do. and i bring them back down, patting the air, like jlo on just dance.</p>
<p>they play rihanna. where have you been. i know this one. just dance. muscle memory overtakes me. i do a space appropriate version. the dj stops it midway through. my feet hurt but i am the room.</p>
<p>in the real club there are tables. booths tucked away in corners and high tops surrounding the dancing pit. watching the dancers. all reserved on the face of it, but when my friend notices my feet hurt she doesn't seem to mind that when she brings me over to one and we sit down. we dont say much.</p>
<p>somehow, this is fine. the lights are fine, the music is fine, the people are fine. i am the room. the vibe is palpable, though not necessarily pleasing to the sober, and humid through my brain. through my eyes, ears, nose, mouth. like a thin wash of color.</p>
<p>three tequila shots.</p>
<p>she goes to take a picture. i hit a flinch. on instinct, i run through my options, cost. i run through my why and how and when and what. the camera goes on and i see myself and in an instant the calculation has completed. i tilt my head and look at the camera. i smile at her command.</p>
<p>i am the room.</p>
<p>we keep dancing, people keep pouring in, a performance is called. a drag queen emerges from the crowd. her heels are higher than mine. i immediately feel sorry for her. her and her two male scantily clad henchmen dance and prance around the circle. lady gaga style. tippers come to the center and she goes to them, grinding and show kissing before sending them off.</p>
<p>she does a show to bad romance. i am 7 years old. below light pine washed stairs, hands on my keyboard and eyes on the youtube search bar. "bad romance". i watch lady gaga move. dance. my moms upset. i dont get it. i watch it in black and white and then color.</p>
<p>i am the room.</p>
<p>another drag queen emerges from the crowd, this one the typical club hostess. she does a routine to britney spears. both talented, both showy, both quoted dolly parton.</p>
<p>the queens finish and the crowd returns to the center. it is full. im pulled to the bar by my friend who seems to have enjoyed the show.</p>
<p>4 tequila shots.</p>
<p>this one burns. i dont know what changed. maybe a different kind of tequila. im not asking questions. i try sucking on the lemon. it helps. it feels like i just vomitted in reverse.</p>
<p>this time i pull my friend to the floor. its so crowded theres hardly space. she grinds on me this time and this time i pretend that i know what to do. in schrodingers club i know exactly what to do. they play bad bunny. they play more pitbull. they play more spanish music i dont know.she seems less enthusiastic. my feet are starting to really kill.</p>
<p>we go to the washroom. i sit in a stall. i can see the girl in the stall right of me poke her foot into my stall. i think about the contortions required to do that. i wonder if im too drunk.</p>
<p>1:17. i leave. shes taking pictures. calculation complete. drunk woman (butch - i feel fond) who got thrown up on takes the picture with us. she tells me to smile and i do. im counting the fucking minutes.</p>
<p>i am the room. i focus on the music. i focus on the lights. i focus on the people. i am the room</p>
<p>1:39. lets go. coat check easy, walk out easy.</p>
<p>I ask "are you getting an uber"
"yeah but not right now"
"want to go to local shithole divebar"</p>
<p>shithole bar is as expected - shit. she seems surprised (in spite of the disclaimer) but im not. its 1:55 and several people remind us as we walk in that last call is in 5 - we order before we sit down. tequila and my usual vodka with iced tea.</p>
<p>4 shots of tequila, 1 shot of vodka</p>
<p>"so if you're not a catfish, why do you only have two pictures on your profile?"</p>
<p>they say being drunk makes it impossible to lie. i say you can't lie about what you don't know. in this moment i don't know that my skin used to be covered in disgusting lesions. i don't know that i looked like a 13 and 30 year old man simultaneously for the vast majority of my teenaged life. i don't know all my hipster contrived value statements about how pictures take away from enjoying the moment and how excessive selfies are narcissistic.</p>
<p>"i just don't really think to take them. to be honest all the pictures i've taken are really from the last week" and its the drunken truth. "why didn't you facetime me if you thought i was a catfish? why would you come an hour and a half to see someone you thought was a catfish?"</p>
<p>to be honest, i wasn't expecting her to show up at all. if she didn't, i almost certainly would've left. gone right home. past my chemical romance live cover band, past the vomiting middle aged skittle, past the beautiful dancing alcoholics lining up at various clubs.</p>
<p>she shrugged.</p>
<p>the bar kept fucking with the music. cutting it out, switching songs midway through. the walls are covered in graffiti - phone numbers, signatures, profanity, stickers. i wonder if it was added organically through the years or if they did it on purpose to add to the general festival restroom converted to a bar atmosphere.</p>
<p>i am the festival toilet inspired bar.</p>
<p>she tells me she likes to play games, and hands me her phone to show me her minecraft world. in a gated enclosure, she keeps pigs, cows, sheep. she has 3 dogs she doesn't name.</p>
<p>she laughs at me when i tell her i name my dogs. i tell her i name everything.</p>
<p>she tells me im beautiful and should take more pictures. she tells me about a cowboy bar we should go to next time. she cant remember the name of it. she tells me about how the first time she went clubbing, she went alone and made out with a girl who got married right after. she tells me she feels bad about it and doesn't know if she did the right thing.</p>
<p>i tell her thats kind. i tell her we should try it. i tell her i don't think theres anything she could have done about that.</p>
<p>i try to understand the set of actions you'd take to go from showing up a club alone to making out with a girl on the dance floor. the right night, the right drinks, the right music, the right dance moves. regardless of the sequence, at club schrondinger i am the tall fat guy, repeatedly dancing toward women who run away from me.</p>
<p>she tells me she probably wont remember any of this in the morning. she tells me she downloaded bumble bff because none of her friends ever want to go out. she tells me she wants to go out again. she says theres nothing to do north of toronto. she tells me she downloaded hinge last month and that none of the men are her type.</p>
<p>i tell her i'll remember. i tell her i get it. i tell her im down. i tell her i'll pitch her at hingedeck. she has no idea what that is. i explain its where you go on stage at a bar and pitch the best qualities of your friend to prospective matches. real time matchmaking. she looks at me like i was licking the table.</p>
<p>she asks me why i tried bumblebff. she asks me if i come here often. she asks me, again, why i dont take more pictures. she asks me if im seeing anyone. she asks me why i dont go out more.</p>
<p>i tell my drunken truth, memory transcendent.</p>
<p>3:57am. the bar empties. i can see the waitress glaring at us halfway across the room. they're not even bothering to work the A/V properly at this point - both the TV's and speakers seem to be hooked up to some guys phone, playing shorts. i tell her its time to go and we leave.</p>
<p>the next streetcar is 10 minutes away. the street is lined with little red riding hoods, convicts, and at least 4 dexter morgans. a joker with a harley quinn on his lap tells his friend over the phone that the ttc was bugging man and that he should have come to the function and that his girl was a strung up bitch.</p>
<p>as if summoned, the streetcar arrived 5 minutes early.</p>
<p>she tells me shes glad im not a catfish. she tells me shes tired. the guy next to me tells me he needs to get to broadview station. i tell him to open his phone which is turned on and check his map. he does. he asks me what streetcar he's on. i say 306 - same as the 506 during the day. i tell him hes on his way and that he just needs to get off when his map tells me to. he looks at me, like a child, and says he's really drunk. i tell him to get home safe and that he'll be okay.</p>
<p>she watches me. a girl dressed as a bumble bee watches me. a homeless man watches me. i am the streetcar. she gets off, planning to lyft home. im just 3 stops down. ive taken my shoes off and i can feel the ttc grime under my feet, at this point too drunk to care.</p>
<p>i stagger up to my apartment, debating taking my shoes off before i'm even in the building, neither my ankles nor my brain working. somehow my shoes are back on ,as when i get into the elevator, i stand in front of the open doors fixing my heels, completely oblivious to the person inside waiting for me to get in.</p>
<p>4:47am, drunk but full of energy, i take my heels off for the final fucking time and collapse in my bathroom. i am the room.</p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/spectre/hedoesntknow.webp" alt="hedoesntknow"></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 19:02:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763321802423690</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Locust at Michigan Fest: A Unique Experience</title>
			<link>https://brokenstar.blog/2025/11/16/the-locust-at-michigan-fest-a-unique-experience/</link>
						<dc:creator>vida</dc:creator>
			<category>Music</category>
			<category>music</category>
			<category>nostalgia</category>
			<category>punk</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Growing up in the punk and hardcore scene in the 1990s, I was lucky to see a lot of amazing bands and meet incredibly passionate and talented people playing music, putting on shows,<a href="http://www.heartattackarchive.com/"> publishing zines</a>, etc. Those experiences exposed me to foundational ideas in my life (like <a href="https://haenfler.sites.grinnell.edu/straight-edge/">straight edge</a>) and gave me a place of belonging. It taught me that in many ways, culture is something that we can co-create, rather than something handed down from corporations.</p>



<p>Reflecting on that time, every once in a while, a memory will pop into my head and I’ll recall a band I had the privilege of seeing before they became huge. One such band was The Locust. I remember seeing them at Michigan Fest and it was one of my more memorable experiences in punk. There was a lot of hype around The Locust and the crowd went wild: people had placards, there were some costumes, and everything erupted. I remember the chandelier getting smashed by garbage (<a href="https://youtu.be/EC2zSZWhfe8">captured on video</a>). It was one</p>



<p>I saw The Locust at least a couple more times in this era, but they weren’t a band I listened to or really sought out. Some years later I remember being surprised to learn from a friend outside of hardcore that The Locust was well-known. I’m sure at the time I probably had some pithy response about how they were better when I saw them. Now, I just cherish the memory. </p>



<figure data-sanitized-class="wp-block-boldblocks-youtube-block"><div data-video-id="EC2zSZWhfe8" data-title="Play" data-sanitized-id="yb-video-EC2zSZWhfe8" data-sanitized-class="yb-player"><button data-sanitized-class="yb-btn-play"><span data-sanitized-class="visually-hidden">Play</span></button></div><figcaption data-sanitized-class="yb-caption">The Locust – Live at Michigan Fest 3-24-2000 •• Master Tape •• Soundboard Audio</figcaption></figure>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 08:40:22 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763321802423689</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sunday Morning Window</title>
			<link>https://dallincrump.com/sunday-morning-window?pk_campaign=rss-feed</link>
						<description><![CDATA[<p>I like to sit in the living room every morning while eating breakfast and looking east out the window. Weekday mornings this time of year I don't see much. It's still dark. But on weekends, when I can stay in bed and eat breakfast later, I see more. </p>

<p>Breakfast is almost always a bowl of cereal. The cereal is almost always high-fiber – I'm so middle-age. <em>Cracklin' Oat Bran</em>, <em>Raisin Bran</em>, anything bran. And unsweetened vanilla almond milk. I actually like the taste better than cow's milk but my wife can't stand it.</p>

<p>My cat, Oreo, jumps up on the sectional sofa next to me and lays on or next to my lap. She always hopes I have the kind of milk she likes and that I'll share.</p>

<p>Depending where I sit on the sofa I see different houses. But I'm usually more interested in the trees and mountains behind them.</p>

<p>The houses are boring. We're in a modest neighborhood of homes with vinyl siding and half-brick facades in front, built in the 1990s. They all look similar and are not extravagant or very large, but nice. Yet so...artificial. Our 1,600 square foot house is the smallest on our street – probably the smallest single family home in our neighborhood, as I haven't seen another like it. We wanted it that way. Our family is small, and we don't <em>need</em> anything larger. I'm very thankful to have a place to live and to be in a nice, safe neighborhood in a good location. But the way we build things here just seems out of place.</p>

<p>Today the trees are way past Autumn peak colors. But most of them still have leaves. Muted dark orange and brown now, but still a bit of yellow. I should have raked the yard yesterday when it was unseasonably warm, but I read somewhere that leaving the leaves can actually be good for your lawn and for the environment as long as they aren't completely covering it. Yeah, that sounds like a good excuse.</p>

<p>And then there are the mountains. So majestic. So dependable. So unmovable.</p>

<p>This morning is cloudy. Sunshine illuminates the edges of breaks in the canopy accented by light blue sky.</p>

<p>The mountains quietly observe the march of human “progress” here. The sprawl of strip malls and parking lots and schools and churches and subdivisions full of houses and town homes and apartments in the valley below them. To them, a couple hundred years is the blink of an eye.</p>

<p>The mountains were here first. They'll be here long after we're gone.</p>

<p>The clouds are clearing a bit. Occasional rays of sunshine stream through the window. I feel the warmth on my skin. I can see our windows are dirty and need a good cleaning.</p>

<p>I should take a shower and get ready for church. But I'll wait a bit longer and enjoy my Sunday morning window.</p>

<p><a href="https://remark.as/p/dallincrump.com/sunday-morning-window">Discuss...</a></p>

<p><a href="https://dallincrump.com/tag:100DaysToOffload" data-sanitized-class="hashtag"><span>#</span><span data-sanitized-class="p-category">100DaysToOffload</span></a> (No. 105) <a href="https://dallincrump.com/tag:gratitude" data-sanitized-class="hashtag"><span>#</span><span data-sanitized-class="p-category">gratitude</span></a> <a href="https://dallincrump.com/tag:life" data-sanitized-class="hashtag"><span>#</span><span data-sanitized-class="p-category">life</span></a> <a href="https://dallincrump.com/tag:Utah" data-sanitized-class="hashtag"><span>#</span><span data-sanitized-class="p-category">Utah</span></a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 08:18:27 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763321802423688</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>TIL: Links in RSS feeds should be absolute</title>
			<link>https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-16-18-relative-urls</link>
						<dc:creator>Auguste Baum</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<header data-sanitized-id="title-block-header">
    <h1 data-sanitized-class="title">TIL: Links in RSS feeds should be absolute</h1>
                <div>
      <time>2025-11-16</time>
    </div>
          </header>
    
  <p>So I recently got this site added to <a href="https://powrss.com/">PowRSS</a>, an RSS feed aggregator for
  Indie Web sites. Nice! Except, no. None of the links to my posts work
  currently: they all point to something like
  <code>https://powrss.com/posts/my-post</code> which is wrong.</p>
  <p>The reason for this is that in the RSS feed for this blog, meaning
  the XML file, links to each post are relative:</p>
  <div data-sanitized-id="cb1" data-sanitized-class="sourceCode"><pre data-sanitized-class="sourceCode html"><code data-sanitized-class="sourceCode html"><span data-sanitized-id="cb1-1"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-16-18-relative-urls#cb1-1" aria-hidden="true"></a><span data-sanitized-class="dt">&lt;</span><span data-sanitized-class="kw">link</span><span data-sanitized-class="ot"> href</span><span data-sanitized-class="op">=</span><span data-sanitized-class="st">"/posts/my-post"</span><span data-sanitized-class="ot"> rel</span><span data-sanitized-class="op">=</span><span data-sanitized-class="st">"alternate"</span><span data-sanitized-class="dt">/&gt;</span></span></code></pre></div>
  <p>Whereas they should be absolute</p>
  <div data-sanitized-id="cb2" data-sanitized-class="sourceCode"><pre data-sanitized-class="sourceCode html"><code data-sanitized-class="sourceCode html"><span data-sanitized-id="cb2-1"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-16-18-relative-urls#cb2-1" aria-hidden="true"></a><span data-sanitized-class="dt">&lt;</span><span data-sanitized-class="kw">link</span><span data-sanitized-class="ot"> href</span><span data-sanitized-class="op">=</span><span data-sanitized-class="st">"https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/my-post"</span><span data-sanitized-class="ot"> rel</span><span data-sanitized-class="op">=</span><span data-sanitized-class="st">"alternate"</span><span data-sanitized-class="dt">/&gt;</span></span></code></pre></div>
  <p>I’ve fixed this on my side now. Let’s hope PowRSS picks up the
  change!</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763321802423687</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>TIW: How do I get Nix to cache tarballs?</title>
			<link>https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-15-17-nix-cache-tarballs</link>
						<dc:creator>Auguste Baum</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<header data-sanitized-id="title-block-header">
    <h1 data-sanitized-class="title">TIW: How do I get Nix to cache tarballs?</h1>
                <div>
      <time>2025-11-15</time>
    </div>
          </header>
    
  <p>Today I wondered: every new code project I create has a file called
  <code>shell.nix</code> starting with something like:</p>
  <div data-sanitized-id="cb1" data-sanitized-class="sourceCode"><pre data-sanitized-class="sourceCode nix"><code data-sanitized-class="sourceCode nix"><span data-sanitized-id="cb1-1"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-15-17-nix-cache-tarballs#cb1-1" aria-hidden="true"></a><span data-sanitized-class="kw">let</span></span>
<span data-sanitized-id="cb1-2"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-15-17-nix-cache-tarballs#cb1-2" aria-hidden="true"></a>  <span data-sanitized-class="va">nixpkgs</span> <span data-sanitized-class="op">=</span> <span data-sanitized-class="bu">fetchTarball</span></span>
<span data-sanitized-id="cb1-3"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-15-17-nix-cache-tarballs#cb1-3" aria-hidden="true"></a>    <span data-sanitized-class="st">"https://github.com/NixOS/nixpkgs/tarball/nixos-25.05"</span><span data-sanitized-class="op">;</span></span>
<span data-sanitized-id="cb1-4"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-15-17-nix-cache-tarballs#cb1-4" aria-hidden="true"></a>  <span data-sanitized-class="va">pkgs</span> <span data-sanitized-class="op">=</span> <span data-sanitized-class="bu">import</span> nixpkgs <span data-sanitized-class="op">{};</span></span>
<span data-sanitized-id="cb1-5"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-15-17-nix-cache-tarballs#cb1-5" aria-hidden="true"></a><span data-sanitized-class="kw">in</span></span>
<span data-sanitized-id="cb1-6"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-15-17-nix-cache-tarballs#cb1-6" aria-hidden="true"></a>  ...</span></code></pre></div>
  <p>Then I use <code>direnv</code> to ensure that this file is loaded
  whenever I’m in the project:</p>
  <div data-sanitized-id="cb2" data-sanitized-class="sourceCode"><pre data-sanitized-class="sourceCode sh"><code data-sanitized-class="sourceCode bash"><span data-sanitized-id="cb2-1"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-15-17-nix-cache-tarballs#cb2-1" aria-hidden="true"></a><span data-sanitized-class="ex">use</span> nix</span></code></pre></div>
  <p>Direnv caches things quite well, but fairly often <em>Nix has to
  re-download whatever version of Nixpkgs I’m using</em> (all 40+ MB of
  it); and it never happens when I expect it (usually when I’m hacking
  in a train with no Internet connection).</p>
  <p>The point of Nix is to hash everything so that it can be cached,
  but it doesn’t seem to be doing that at the repository scale. Could it
  be because <code>nixos-25.05</code> is not specific enough?</p>
  <p>I also tend to use <code>npins</code> in some projects. I haven’t
  paid attention to whether it works better.</p>
  <p>I can see in <code>/nix/store</code> that I have a
  <code>&lt;hash&gt;-nixpkgs-src</code> directory, and also
  <code>&lt;hash&gt;-nixpkgs-stable-src</code>. Hmm…</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763321802423686</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>My ideal browser</title>
			<link>https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-14-16-my-ideal-browser</link>
						<dc:creator>Auguste Baum</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<header data-sanitized-id="title-block-header">
    <h1 data-sanitized-class="title">My ideal browser</h1>
                <div>
      <time>2025-11-14</time>
    </div>
          </header>
    
  <p>I love <a href="https://www.qutebrowser.org/">Qutebrowser</a>. It’s
  a very cool, minimal, get-out-of-my-way kind of tool. Most
  importantly, it is designed to be used exclusively with the keyboard.
  But I am missing a few things, mostly things that you can get with
  add-ons in the classic browsers: Bitwarden integration, tree-style
  tabs like with Sidebery (there is a PR for it, which I’m already
  running), dark-mode like with Dark Reader, i.e. that doesn’t require
  restarting the browser every time. There is also the issue that I
  cannot fully trust the app not to crash.</p>
  <p>I like Firefox, because of the add-ons, but I often get issues with
  Google Meet (using Linux doesn’t help). I’ve tried Tridactyl to
  control it with the keyboard, but there’s always something that
  doesn’t work. It also sucks that Firefox exists only because <a href="https://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2025/09/google-antitrust-ruling-firefox-search-deal">Google
  pays it to make Google Search the default search engine</a>. I
  currently run a privacy-focused fork called <a href="https://floorp.app/">Floorp</a>.</p>
  <p>I like that <a href="https://ungoogled-software.github.io/">Ungoogled-Chromium</a>
  exists, but it doesn’t do Wayland it seems? And I also can’t control
  it with the keyboard.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763321802423685</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Use unique email addresses</title>
			<link>https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-13-15-unique-emails</link>
						<dc:creator>Auguste Baum</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<header data-sanitized-id="title-block-header">
    <h1 data-sanitized-class="title">Use unique email addresses</h1>
                <div>
      <time>2025-11-13</time>
    </div>
          </header>
    
  <p>It would be nice to be able to quickly create a unique email
  address for each new service I sign up to. That way, I could easily
  avoid spam (just delete the address) and tell which credentials to
  change in the event of a data breach.</p>
  <p>I already use Bitwarden to generate a unique long password for
  every service, and it allows you to connect to such a forwarding
  service to generate a new unique address at the same time.</p>
  <p>So I did a bit of research on the different options, and I just
  signed up to DuckDuckGo’s free Email Protection service; we’ll see how
  it goes!</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763321802423684</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Meta will read your DMs. Use Signal!</title>
			<link>https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-12-14-use-signal</link>
						<dc:creator>Auguste Baum</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<header data-sanitized-id="title-block-header">
    <h1 data-sanitized-class="title">Meta will read your DMs. Use Signal!</h1>
                <div>
      <time>2025-11-12</time>
    </div>
          </header>
    
  <p>In a turn of events, <a href="https://www.thecanary.co/skwawkbox/2025/11/07/meta-ai-chats/">Meta
  will now openly scan DMs on Facebook, Instagram and Whatsapp</a>. This
  is a blatant invasion of your privacy and will further allow Meta to
  police what users can share on their platforms and most importantly,
  to sell their user’s personal conversations to the highest bidder.</p>
  <p>This is as good an opportunity as ever to tell you, dear reader, to
  start using <a href="https://signal.org/#signal">Signal</a>. Signal
  encrypts messages in a way that they themselves cannot decrypt, even
  if law enforcement asked them to.</p>
  <p>Besides, it’s a neat app!</p>
  <p>PS: Why not Telegram, you ask? Telegram is not end-to-end
  encrypted, meaning that they can read your messages if they want to
  (or if the Russian government asks them to); less importantly,
  Telegram’s encryption is custom-built, whereas Signal’s relies on
  battle-tested technology and is therefore more trustworthy.</p>
  <p>See <a href="https://www.protectstar.com/en/blog/telegram-encryption">here</a>
  for a source on this with more details.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763321802423683</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Google wants XSLT dead</title>
			<link>https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-11-13-google-wants-xslt-dead</link>
						<dc:creator>Auguste Baum</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<header data-sanitized-id="title-block-header">
    <h1 data-sanitized-class="title">Google wants XSLT dead</h1>
                <div>
      <time>2025-11-11</time>
    </div>
          </header>
    
  <p>Yesterday I talked about <a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-10-12-google-wants-rss-dead/">RSS</a>.
  RSS feeds tend to be powered by XML, a language sort of like HTML, but
  not exactly. That is why, when you click on a “RSS” link on a website,
  your browser either downloads a file, or shows you a wall of text: the
  browser does not know how to display the XML.</p>
  <p>However, you can actually add a translation layer to convert the
  XML to HTML, so that the browser can display it. This is what I do in
  my blog: if you visit <a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/index.xml">the “posts” page</a>,
  the browser should show you a normal-looking list of my posts, but the
  link address ends with <code>xml</code>. What is this sorcery, you
  ask?</p>
  <p>This sorcery is <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XSLT">XSLT</a>, another
  XML-related format, that lets you <em>transform</em> an XML document
  into another XML document. The power of XML is in full display
  here.</p>
  <p>Unfortunately for me, Google is trying its best to <a href="https://mjtsai.com/blog/2025/08/21/removing-xslt-from-the-web-platform/">make
  XSLT disappear</a>, which means I’ll have to re-code that “posts”
  page, but also that a Web Standard is being made artificially
  obsolete, just like in the RSS case.</p>
  <p>See <a href="https://wok.oblomov.eu/tecnologia/google-killing-open-web-2/">here</a>
  for a more scathing critique of Google on this issue:</p>
  <blockquote>
  <p>So, do not comply.</p>
  <p>Resist.</p>
  <p>Force the unwanted tech through.</p>
  <p>Use RSS.</p>
  <p>Use XSLT.</p>
  <p>Adopt JPEG XL as your primary image format.</p>
  <p>And report newly broken sites for what they are: a browser fault,
  not a content issue.</p>
  </blockquote>
  <p>See also <a href="https://meyerweb.com/eric/thoughts/2025/08/22/no-google-did-not-unilaterally-decide-to-kill-xslt/">here</a>
  for an attempt to defend the WHATWG (the authority that discusses and
  decides such matters), and calm things down.</p>
  <blockquote>
  <p>Just in case your eyes glazed over and you quickly skimmed to see
  if there was a TL;DR, here it is:</p>
  <p>The discussion was opened by a Google employee in response to
  interest from multiple browser vendors in removing built-in XSLT,
  following a process that is opaque to most outsiders. It’s a first
  step in a multi-step evaluation process that can take years to
  complete, and whose outcome is not predetermined. Tempers flared and
  the initial discussion was locked; the conversation continues
  elsewhere. There are good reasons to drop native XSLT support in
  browsers, and also good reasons to keep or update it, but XSLT is not
  itself at risk.</p>
  </blockquote>
  <p>Still not convinced that Google is not trying to kill another piece
  of the open web.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763321802423682</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Google wants RSS dead</title>
			<link>https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-10-12-google-wants-rss-dead</link>
						<dc:creator>Auguste Baum</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<header data-sanitized-id="title-block-header">
    <h1 data-sanitized-class="title">Google wants RSS dead</h1>
                <div>
      <time>2025-11-10</time>
    </div>
          </header>
    
  <p>I really like RSS. It’s a piece of technology that really embodies
  the beauty of the web: small, simple, but powerful and ubiquitous as a
  result. I use RSS every day to find new things to read, by way of
  Miniflux and NetNewsWire.</p>
  <p>Here is what I do to subscribe to a website:</p>
  <ul>
  <li>I go to the author’s main website</li>
  <li>I look for a link with some combination of the words “RSS”,
  “Atom”, “feed”, “XML”</li>
  <li>if I find it, I copy it and paste it into NetNewsWire</li>
  <li>if not, either
  <ul>
  <li>I keep looking
  <ul>
  <li>There could be one in the “posts” or “archive” page of the blog
  rather than the main page, or</li>
  <li>It could be in the source code of the page: Right-click, “View
  page source”, then do a text search for one of the above words</li>
  </ul></li>
  <li>I give up in disgust</li>
  </ul></li>
  </ul>
  <p>It’s not the simplest that it could be, but it fits my needs and
  there is also a sense of pride in using this classic, open web
  technology. I feel like a wizard.</p>
  <p>Unfortunately for me, Google is trying its best to <a href="https://openrss.org/blog/how-google-helped-destroy-adoption-of-rss-feeds">make
  RSS disappear</a>. If you were a search company, making money by
  people finding links on your site, then a service that delivers new
  links directly to people without them having to search would be a bit
  of an existential threat, admittedly.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763321802423681</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>On the Works in Progress magazine</title>
			<link>https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-09-11-on-the-works-in-progress-magazine</link>
						<dc:creator>Auguste Baum</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<header data-sanitized-id="title-block-header">
    <h1 data-sanitized-class="title">On the Works in Progress magazine</h1>
                <div>
      <time>2025-11-09</time>
    </div>
          </header>
    
  <p>So since I published <a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-08-10-magical-systems-thinking/">TIR:
  Magical systems thinking</a>, I thought “Hey I only learned about this
  Works in Progress magazine yesterday, like 3 hours before publishing
  the post. Where does it come from?”</p>
  <p>It turns out that the magazine is owned by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stripe,_Inc.">Stripe</a>, a
  payments engine company, and its founding editor, Sam Bowman, is also
  a member of the Mercatus Center’s board of directors.</p>
  <p>But what is the Mercatus Center? It is a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mercatus_Center">libertarian,
  free-market-oriented think tank</a>, privately funded (mostly by the
  Koch brothers) and chaired by (as of writing) <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mercatus_Center#Board_of_directors">libertarian
  economists, a Koch brother, a former Koch Industries VP and a general
  partner at a16z</a>.</p>
  <p>Given that background, it is not so surprising that the article
  elevates occurrences of government “fast-tracking” like the US Covid
  vaccine approval process and the Notre-Dame reconstruction process, or
  the digitalization of administration in Estonia.</p>
  <p>So yeah, not super comfortable about that.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763321802423680</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>TIR: Magical systems thinking</title>
			<link>https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-08-10-magical-systems-thinking</link>
						<dc:creator>Auguste Baum</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<header data-sanitized-id="title-block-header">
    <h1 data-sanitized-class="title">TIR: Magical systems thinking</h1>
                <div>
      <time>2025-11-08</time>
    </div>
          </header>
    
  <p>Today I read <a href="https://worksinprogress.co/issue/magical-systems-thinking/">Magical
  systems thinking</a>, by Ed Bradon in the Works in Progress magazine.
  What a cool-looking magazine!</p>
  <p>The article discusses the aura of systems thinking in today’s upper
  level management and political circles; how it tends to be viewed as a
  silver bullet that can solve all of our systemic problems.</p>
  <p>There is a mention of Le Chatelier’s principle (also known as the
  “moderation principle” in French):</p>
  <blockquote>
  <p>The system always kicks back.</p>
  </blockquote>
  <p>The principle applies to chemical systems, but might apply to
  systems more generally?</p>
  <p>The answer to that might be found in Gall’s book
  <em>Systemantics</em>, which includes a number of similar principles.
  Of note are:</p>
  <blockquote>
  <p>The system does not do what it says it is doing.</p>
  </blockquote>
  <p>and</p>
  <blockquote>
  <p>The name is emphatically not the thing.</p>
  </blockquote>
  <p>I would like to better remember these; they are a reminder that
  language orients thought. Names can clarify as well as deceive.</p>
  <p>Gall’s book also includes what we now call Gall’s law:</p>
  <blockquote>
  <p>A complex system that works necessarily evolved from a simple
  system that works.</p>
  </blockquote>
  <p>Another part of Gall’s law is that if your complex system does not
  work, your best bet to get something that works is to start fresh.
  This can be done in parallel to the pre-existing system.</p>
  <p>There are real-life examples of bypassing classic bureaucratic
  complexity, such as Operation Warp Speed for Covid vaccines in the US,
  or the reconstruction of Notre-Dame in Paris.</p>
  <p>But this comes into conflict with other sources of mine that say <a href="https://swizec.com/blog/you-can-t-stop-the-business-or-why-rewrites-fail/">rewriting
  code projects is rarely worth it</a>.</p>
  <hr>
  <p>EDIT (2025-11-09): I have thoughts on the Works in Progress
  magazine; read about them <a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-09-11-on-the-works-in-progress-magazine">here</a>.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763321802423679</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Split a jj revision based on its history</title>
			<link>https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-07-09-jj-split-rev</link>
						<dc:creator>Auguste Baum</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<header data-sanitized-id="title-block-header">
    <h1 data-sanitized-class="title">Split a jj revision based on its history</h1>
                <div>
      <time>2025-11-07</time>
    </div>
          </header>
    
  <p>Has this ever happened to you?</p>
  <p>You’re working on a change:</p>
  <div data-sanitized-id="cb1" data-sanitized-class="sourceCode"><pre data-sanitized-class="sourceCode txt"><code data-sanitized-class="sourceCode default"><span data-sanitized-id="cb1-1"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-07-09-jj-split-rev#cb1-1" aria-hidden="true"></a># hello.md</span>
<span data-sanitized-id="cb1-2"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-07-09-jj-split-rev#cb1-2" aria-hidden="true"></a>aaa</span></code></pre></div>
  <p>You make a new change:</p>
  <div data-sanitized-id="cb2" data-sanitized-class="sourceCode"><pre data-sanitized-class="sourceCode txt"><code data-sanitized-class="sourceCode default"><span data-sanitized-id="cb2-1"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-07-09-jj-split-rev#cb2-1" aria-hidden="true"></a># hello.md</span>
<span data-sanitized-id="cb2-2"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-07-09-jj-split-rev#cb2-2" aria-hidden="true"></a>aaabbb</span></code></pre></div>
  <p>But you forgot to <code>jj new</code>! Thus, you find yourself with
  a change that is really two changes.</p>
  <p>If the two changes touched separate lines you could get away with
  <code>jj split</code>, but in this case that won’t work.</p>
  <p>However, you did run some <code>jj</code> commands between the two
  edits, so <code>jj</code> has them stored as intermediate commits
  which you can see with <code>jj evolog</code>:</p>
  <pre><code>$ jj evolog
@  skwmqsxo 9fac1a23
│  (no description set)
○  skwmqsxo d9eea6a7
│  (no description set)
○  skwmqsxo 682f749a
   (empty) (no description set)</code></pre>
  <p>Suppose that adding <code>bbb</code> was done in commit
  <code>9fac1a23</code>. Then what we’d like is to split the revision
  <code>skwmqsxo</code> into a revision containing every commit before
  that (i.e. up to and including <code>d9eea6a7</code>) and a revision
  containing the rest.</p>
  <p>This can be done with the following revolutionary script (add it to
  the <code>aliases</code> section in your
  <code>config.toml</code>):</p>
  <div data-sanitized-id="cb4" data-sanitized-class="sourceCode"><pre data-sanitized-class="sourceCode toml"><code data-sanitized-class="sourceCode toml"><span data-sanitized-id="cb4-1"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-07-09-jj-split-rev#cb4-1" aria-hidden="true"></a><span data-sanitized-class="dt">split-rev</span> <span data-sanitized-class="op">=</span> <span data-sanitized-class="op">[</span><span data-sanitized-class="st">"util"</span><span data-sanitized-class="op">,</span> <span data-sanitized-class="st">"exec"</span><span data-sanitized-class="op">,</span> <span data-sanitized-class="st">"--"</span><span data-sanitized-class="op">,</span> <span data-sanitized-class="st">"bash"</span><span data-sanitized-class="op">,</span> <span data-sanitized-class="st">"-c"</span><span data-sanitized-class="op">,</span> <span data-sanitized-class="st">"""</span></span>
<span data-sanitized-id="cb4-2"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-07-09-jj-split-rev#cb4-2" aria-hidden="true"></a><span data-sanitized-class="st">set -euo pipefail</span></span>
<span data-sanitized-id="cb4-3"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-07-09-jj-split-rev#cb4-3" aria-hidden="true"></a><span data-sanitized-class="st">jj new --after @</span></span>
<span data-sanitized-id="cb4-4"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-07-09-jj-split-rev#cb4-4" aria-hidden="true"></a><span data-sanitized-class="st">jj restore --from $1 --to @- --restore-descendants</span></span>
<span data-sanitized-id="cb4-5"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-07-09-jj-split-rev#cb4-5" aria-hidden="true"></a><span data-sanitized-class="st">"""</span><span data-sanitized-class="op">,</span> <span data-sanitized-class="st">""</span></span>
<span data-sanitized-id="cb4-6"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-07-09-jj-split-rev#cb4-6" aria-hidden="true"></a><span data-sanitized-class="op">]</span></span></code></pre></div>
  <p>which you should use as follows:</p>
  <div data-sanitized-id="cb5" data-sanitized-class="sourceCode"><pre data-sanitized-class="sourceCode sh"><code data-sanitized-class="sourceCode bash"><span data-sanitized-id="cb5-1"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-07-09-jj-split-rev#cb5-1" aria-hidden="true"></a><span data-sanitized-class="ex">$</span> jj edit skwmqsxo</span>
<span data-sanitized-id="cb5-2"><a href="https://blog.augustebaum.com/posts/2025-11-07-09-jj-split-rev#cb5-2" aria-hidden="true"></a><span data-sanitized-class="ex">$</span> jj split-rev d9eea6a7</span></code></pre></div>
  <p>That’s all folks!</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763321802423678</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
