<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >
	<channel>
		<title> | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>http://192.168.1.206/FreshRSS/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of  | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 04:33:56 -0700</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 11:33:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="/i/?a=rss&amp;sort=date&amp;order=DESC&amp;state=2" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
				<item>
			<title>Algorithmically, I thought I should know Peel Dream Magazine by now. Their…</title>
			<link>https://www.nicksimson.com//notes/2025-11-16-peel-dream-magazine.html</link>
						<description><![CDATA[<p>Algorithmically, I thought I should know <a href="https://peeldreammagazine.bandcamp.com/">Peel Dream Magazine</a> by now. Their music has been compared to some of my personal favorites Broadcast, Stereolab, and Yo La Tengo. The “Peel” in their name is a dedication to the late BBC Radio1 deejay <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Peel">John Peel</a>. I’m just old enough that the phrase “Peel Session” means something to me. They are on a favorite label, <a href="https://www.topshelfrecords.com/">Top Shelf Records</a> (I’m in the Discord).</p>
<p>Ah well. I found my way to this music via the <a href="https://simplebits.com/notebook/studio-notes-58/">SimpleBits Studio Notes</a> newsletter. Dan writes he heard them on SiriusXM. Long live the radio and the personal recommendation.</p>
<p><a href="https://peeldreammagazine.bandcamp.com/album/rose-main-reading-room"><i>Rose Main Reading Room</i></a> is a great name for a concept album about New York City and its landmarks. This is a “headphones record”; baroque pop meets Y2K dream pop sounds. I love everything I’ve heard so far, and my ears are hungry for more.</p>
<p><small>Also <a href="https://app.crucialtracks.org/profile/nsmsn/20251116">posted to Crucial Tracks</a>.</small></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 02:11:20 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203175</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Why I Don't Need a Steam Machine</title>
			<link>https://brainbaking.com/post/2025/11/why-i-dont-need-a-steam-machine/</link>
						<dc:creator>Wouter Groeneveld</dc:creator>
			<category>steam</category>
			<category>games</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>For those of you who are living under a rock, Valve announced <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/sale/steammachine">three new hardware devices</a> joining their Steam Deck line-up: a new controller, a VR headset, and the GameCube—no wait, GabeCube—no wait, Steam Machine. The shiny little cube is undoubtedly Valve’s (second) attempt to break into the console market. This time, it might just work.</p>
<p>The hardware is ready to arrive in at your living room spring next year. The biggest question is: will it arrive at <em>our</em> living room? Reading all the hype has certainly enthused me (e.g. Brendon’s <a href="https://wavelengths.online/posts/the-steam-machine-is-the-future">The Steam Machine is the Future</a>, PC Gamer’s <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/hardware/vr-hardware/steamos-launching-for-arm-fex-translation-layer/">Valve is all over ARM</a>, Eurogamer’s <a href="https://www.eurogamer.net/tech-steam-machine-preview-a-powerful-customisable-mini-pc-for-couch-gaming">Steam Machine preview</a>, ResetEra’s <a href="https://www.resetera.com/threads/the-steam-hardware-family-officially-expands-in-early-2026-steam-controller-steam-machine-steam-frame.1351453/">Steam Hardware thread</a>); especially the part where the Machine is just a PC that happens to be tailored towards console gaming. According to Valve, you can install anything you want on it—it’s just SteamOS just like your trusty Deck, meaning you can boot into KDE and totally do your thing. Except that this shiny little cube is six times as powerful. I’m sure Digital Foundry will validate that next year.</p>
<p>
<figure><a href="https://brainbaking.com/post/2025/11/why-i-dont-need-a-steam-machine/steam-machine.jpg" data-sanitized-class="lbox">
		<img src="https://brainbaking.com/post/2025/11/why-i-dont-need-a-steam-machine/steam-machine.jpg" title="Valve's newly announced Steam Machine: a mysterious looking sleek black box." data-pagefind-index-attrs="title">
	</a>
	
		<figcaption>Valve's newly announced Steam Machine: a mysterious looking sleek black box.</figcaption></figure>
</p>
<p>However, this post isn’t about specs, expectations, or dreams: it’s about tempering my own enthusiasm. I’d like to tell myself why I don’t really need a Steam Machine. The following list will hopefully make it easier to say no when the buy buttons become available.</p>
<ul>
<li><em>You’re a retro gamer.</em> <br>You don’t need the power of six Steam Decks. To do what, run DOSBox?</li>
<li><em>Your TV doesn’t support 4K</em>.<br>Again, no need for those 4K 60 FPS.</li>
<li><em>You generally dislike AAA games.</em> <br>With The Steam Machine, you might be able to finally properly run <em>DOOM Eternal</em> and all of the <em>Assassin’s Creed</em> games. That you don’t like playing.</li>
<li><em>You don’t have time to play games anyway.</em><br>Ouch, that hurts but it’s not untrue.</li>
<li><em>The TV will be occupied anyway.</em><br>The Steam Machine is not a Switch: you can’t switch to handheld mode. When are you going to play on the Machine if the TV is being used to watch your wife’s favourite shows?</li>
<li><em>You already have too many gaming related hardware pieces.</em><br>That’ll mean you’ll have to divide your time by an even bigger number to devote an equal amount to playing them.</li>
<li><em>There’s no room for yet another nondescript box under the TV.</em><br>See above: why don’t you first try to do something with that SNES Mini and PlayStation Mini besides letting it collect dust?</li>
<li><em>You’re a physical gamer.</em><br>This is Steam. There will be no insertion of cartridges, no blowing of carts, and no staring at game collections on a shelf.</li>
<li><em>It’s Steam, not Good Old Games.</em><br>Sure it can run GOG games but the Machine is primarily designed to run Steam. You avoid purchasing from Steam like the plague, yet you’re willing to buy a Machine dedicated to it? Are you crazy?</li>
<li><em>The last time you booted Steam was over a year ago.</em><br>Don’t tell me you’re suddenly interested in running the platform on a dedicated machine.</li>
<li><em>You don’t have time to fiddle with configuration.</em><br>Button and trackpad mappings to get the controls just right enough to play strategy games designed to be played with keyboard and mouse will only leave you frustrated.</li>
<li><em>Your MacBook can emulate Windows games just fine.</em><br>You recently bought CrossOver and played <em>Wizordum</em> and older Windows 98/XP stuff on it. It even runs <em>Against The Storm</em> flawlessly. No need for Proton or whatever.</li>
<li><em>In two years, you’ll upgrade your M1 to an M4+: there’s the power upgrade.</em><br>If CrossOver is struggling to run that particular game you so badly want to play, it’ll be buttery smooth in a few years. You’re going to do the laptop upgrade anyway regardless of the Steam Machine.</li>
<li><em>You already have a huge gaming backlog.</em><br>Thanks to your buddy Joel you bought too many physical Switch games that are still waiting to be touched. Are you really ready to open up another can of worms?</li>
<li><em>You dislike a digital backlog.</em><br>It’s easy to have hundreds of games on there: see your GOG purchases. Why don’t you try to count the ones that you actually played, let alone finished.</li>
<li><em>You’re not going to use the Machine to run office software.</em><br>Your laptop and other retro machines are good enough at handling that task. What are you really going to do with this cube besides gaming?</li>
<li><em>Those cool looking indie games will be released for Switch in due time anyway.</em><br>Remember <em>Pizza Tower</em>? It’s out on Switch now. Remember to buy the cart on Fangamer, together with the <em>Anton Blast</em> one.</li>
<li><em>It’s rumoured to cost more than</em> <code>€600</code>.<br>Save that money for a Switch 2 if the games are starting to become interesting to justify that upgrade, as currently, they’re not. Also, see the backlog point above.</li>
<li><em>All HDMI ports both on the TV and your external monitors are occupied</em>.<br>Unless you’re willing to constantly switch cables, you’ll need to invest in a HDMI switch. Another <code>€100+</code>.</li>
<li><em>You can’t buy this without buying the Steam Controller.</em><br>That’s easily another <code>€80+</code> you already spent buying the Mobapad controller for your Switch as a replacement for the semi-broken Joy Cons.</li>
<li><em>You can’t buy this as an expense on the company.</em><br>You’re closing down the company, remember. (More on that later)</li>
<li><em>The cool looking LED and programmable front display don’t justify an expensive purchase.</em><br>After the initial excitement wears off, the LED will become annoying and you’ll simply turn it off.</li>
</ul>
<p>So you see, I don’t really need a Steam Machine…</p>
<p>Fuck it, I’m getting one.</p>


          
          <p>
            Related topics: /
                  <a href="https://brainbaking.com/tags/steam">steam</a> /
                  <a href="https://brainbaking.com/tags/games">games</a> /
          </p>
          
          <p>
            By <a href="https://brainbaking.com/about">Wouter Groeneveld</a> on 16 November 2025. 
            <a href="mailto:hifromrss@brainbaking.com?subject=Re:%20Why%20I%20Don%27t%20Need%20a%20Steam%20Machine">Reply via email</a>.
          </p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203179</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Another video of Canadian youths biking unwisely</title>
			<link>https://blog.lauramichet.com/another-video-of-canadian-youths-biking-unwisely/</link>
						<dc:creator>lauram</dc:creator>
			<category>bicycles</category>
			<category>youtube</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>I posted another video from this channel previously - a video where two Canadians (possibly college students??) made a bikepacking rig out of stuff they bought and taped together from the hardware store. I appreciated their deranged commitment to the low-cost bit.</p>
<p>I have to also recommend this video of them going bikepacking without any food... and eating out of trash cans and animals they grab out of the ocean with their hands.</p>
<p>You will have to watch the video to learn which animal they eat out of the ocean:</p>
<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/kLSMJBRyV_k?si=2rAZFsBLzCu7cjX-" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" sandbox="allow-scripts allow-same-origin"></iframe>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 23:41:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203197</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Confessions of a Charm School Dropout</title>
			<link>https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/2025/11/15/confessions-of-a-charm-school-dropout/</link>
						<dc:creator>Musings from a Tangled Mind</dc:creator>
			<category>Everyday Musings</category>
			<category>life</category>
			<category>humor</category>
			<category>making friends</category>
			<category>social anxiety</category>
			<category>personality quirks</category>
			<category>dailyprompt</category>
			<category>funny blog post</category>
			<category>dailyprompt-2124</category>
			<media:content url="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/31ec7a2e33056eb9b17551f99a60a9ba20d8b41e7681ea12d7fe7911294c5215?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image"><media:title type="html">surojabu11</media:title></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>It’s funny that today’s writing prompt is, <em>“What’s the first impression I want to give people?”</em> Because I swear the universe is messing with me — this exact topic blindsided me yesterday while I was shopping with a friend. I was minding my business, smelling a candle, and she just hits me with, “So… what vibe do you <em>think</em> you give off to strangers?”</p>



<p>I just stared at her. I mean… <em>what</em>? Why are we doing interview questions in Aisle 3? I thought we were just trying to find the bathroom in Target.</p>



<p>And she clearly expected me to say something inspirational like, “I hope people see my inner glow,” or “I try to radiate compassion.” No. I don’t glow. I don’t radiate. At best, I mildly hum, but more in a “she’s getting ready to explode” kind of a way… you know, like <em>Perfection</em> right before it detonates.</p>



<p>Then, before I can even stop spluttering long enough to formulate a socially acceptable answer, she shrugged and went, “Welp… whatever the answer is, that’s <em>not</em> the face you’re giving off.” What the hell, Brenda?</p>



<p>Then I narrowed my eyes and asked, “Does this have anything to do with that old man in the seasonal section? He startled me. You saw it. There were gourds, Brenda.”</p>



<p>Look, I know I should probably make a better first impression. But I’m also self-aware enough to know that I absolutely don’t. At best, I give off a general aura of, “Hey, I’m sure you’re lovely, but maybe… don’t talk to me?”</p>



<p>The thing is, I don’t have <em>resting</em> bitch face. This is literally just my face. This is the factory default. This is what it looks like when I’m standing still.</p>



<p>People assume I’m mad, but no. I’m probably thinking about pasta. Or trying to remember whether I left laundry in the washer in 2014. I’ve got a whole inner world happening here that has absolutely nothing to do with anyone around me, and it’s hard to convey that without making things worse.</p>



<p>And then there’s the smiling thing. I forget to do it. Unless I’m laughing at something in my own head (because I’m a delight) or there’s a baby or an animal involved, it just doesn’t occur to me.</p>



<p>There is always — ALWAYS — some overly cheerful human who hits me with the “You should smile more!” Ma’am. Sir. Please. If you saw my intentional smile, you would take that back immediately. </p>



<p>You know how a dog looks when someone teaches it to “smile?” That stiff, awkward teethy “I’m doing this for a treat and I hate every moment” grimace? That’s exactly what I look like when I force a smile. Nobody needs that energy aimed at them in a grocery store. It’s very “I swear I’m normal, please don’t call security.”</p>



<p>The point is, while other people are out here trying to give off approachable, bubbly, sunshine-on-a-stick energy, I am… not. I’m aiming more for “friendly raccoon that might run away if you make eye contact.” But also, I might bite. It’s hard to say.</p>



<p>I’m not unfriendly. I’m just… cautious. Socially allergic. Pick your adjective. I don’t care what you call me so long as you don’t call me.</p>



<p>So what first impression do I WANT to give? I want to look like someone who is perfectly nice once you know me but maybe doesn’t need to be spoken to immediately upon entry. I want to give off “Give me a minute” energy. Sometimes several minutes. Sometimes days. It depends on how early in the morning it is.</p>



<p>In short, I would very much like to be left alone.<br>Respectfully.<br>Gently.<br>The way you’d leave a sleeping cat alone even though it looks cute and you want to pet it.</p>



<p>And if you catch me looking like I’m judging you, I promise I’m not. My face is just buffering. But also… don’t feel pressured to talk to me while it loads.</p>



<p data-sanitized-class="has-white-color has-text-color has-link-color wp-elements-7e4ac651328708ea719ac0894fa30934">.</p>



<p></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 21:43:47 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203181</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>How Many Posts Is Too Many?</title>
			<link>https://mtwb.blog/posts/2025/how-many-posts-is-too-many/</link>
						<category>blogging</category>
			<category>writing</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>I have been publishing a new post every day since mid September. I’ve had a good time doing it, and I’m going to continue on into next year unless something happens. But I do have to wonder, does publishing too much bug those of you who subscribe to my RSS feed? Do the people who post four or five times a day, usually short posts, come across as spammy? Is there such a thing as too many posts?</p>
<p>The other day, I published three in one day. Now it was a link and a video along with a regular post, but there was still a voice in the back of my head that asked if it was too much. I subscribe to a few bloggers who use their blogs as more of a daily note type thing, which means they post many times a day. It doesn’t really bother me, but I don’t read all of their posts. Maybe that’s the expectation, so nothing is really wrong here. But it is something I think about as I continue to work towards my 200th post this year.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 19:28:24 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203180</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Walk with me: On my soapbox</title>
			<link>https://gabe.rocks/health/wwm-filler-episode/</link>
						<media:content url="https://gabe.rocks//audio/2025-11-15.opus"></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>I hope you’ll enjoy this stream-of-consciousness reflection on the last crazy year as I prepare for 2026.
Apologies for the lack of a write-up, I am crunched for time at the moment.
I hope this before and after makes up for it!</p>
<div data-sanitized-class="image-container">
    
<img src="https://gabe.rocks/images/nov24-25.avif">



</div>
<p>Thank you for reading this through RSS 📡</p>
        <p>Your thoughts and feedback are both very important to me.<br><a href="https://gabe.rocks//get-in-touch">Get in touch!</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 14:08:44 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203176</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Ron Seems Sentient</title>
			<link>https://ronseemssentient.blogspot.com/?m=0</link>
						<dc:creator>hello@manuelmoreale.com (Manuel Moreale)</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<ul>
                    <li><strong>Title:<strong> Ron Seems Sentient</strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>Website:<strong> <a href="https://ronseemssentient.blogspot.com/?m=0">ronseemssentient.blogspot.com</a></strong></strong></li>
                                    </ul>
                <hr>
                <p>Absurd humor and surreal office tales that spiral into the existential.</p>                <hr>
                <p>RSS users are my people 🫶 If you appreciate what I'm doing <a href="https://ko-fi.com/manuelmoreale">consider becoming a supporter for 1$ a month</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 19:50:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203187</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Maique</title>
			<link>https://maique.eu/</link>
						<dc:creator>hello@manuelmoreale.com (Manuel Moreale)</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<ul>
                    <li><strong>Title:<strong> Maique</strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>Website:<strong> <a href="https://maique.eu/">maique.eu</a></strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>RSS Feed:<strong> <a href="https://maique.eu/">maique.eu/feed</a></strong></strong></li>                </ul>
                <hr>
                <p>Hey there, my name is maique. I’m a geeky photographer, who toots.</p>                <hr>
                <p>RSS users are my people 🫶 If you appreciate what I'm doing <a href="https://ko-fi.com/manuelmoreale">consider becoming a supporter for 1$ a month</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 23:35:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203183</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Garry Newman</title>
			<link>https://garry.net/</link>
						<dc:creator>hello@manuelmoreale.com (Manuel Moreale)</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<ul>
                    <li><strong>Title:<strong> Garry Newman</strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>Website:<strong> <a href="https://garry.net/">garry.net</a></strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>RSS Feed:<strong> <a href="https://garry.net/">garry.net/posts/rss</a></strong></strong></li>                </ul>
                <hr>
                <p>Hello I'm Garry. I'm a video game developer and owner of facepunch.</p>                <hr>
                <p>RSS users are my people 🫶 If you appreciate what I'm doing <a href="https://ko-fi.com/manuelmoreale">consider becoming a supporter for 1$ a month</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 23:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203188</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>raincastle.blog</title>
			<link>https://raincastle.blog/</link>
						<dc:creator>hello@manuelmoreale.com (Manuel Moreale)</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<ul>
                    <li><strong>Title:<strong> raincastle.blog</strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>Website:<strong> <a href="https://raincastle.blog/">raincastle.blog</a></strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>RSS Feed:<strong> <a href="https://raincastle.blog/">raincastle.blog/blog.rss</a></strong></strong></li>                </ul>
                <hr>
                <p>Laufen in Straubing und im Bayerischen Wald.</p>                <hr>
                <p>RSS users are my people 🫶 If you appreciate what I'm doing <a href="https://ko-fi.com/manuelmoreale">consider becoming a supporter for 1$ a month</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 01:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203185</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Linda Ma</title>
			<link>https://midnightpond.com/</link>
						<dc:creator>hello@manuelmoreale.com (Manuel Moreale)</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<ul>
                    <li><strong>Title:<strong> Linda Ma</strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>Website:<strong> <a href="https://midnightpond.com/">midnightpond.com</a></strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>RSS Feed:<strong> <a href="https://midnightpond.com/">midnightpond.com/rss.xml</a></strong></strong></li>                </ul>
                <hr>
                <p>Linda Ma writes about self-understanding, people patterns, and other interests.</p>                <hr>
                <p>RSS users are my people 🫶 If you appreciate what I'm doing <a href="https://ko-fi.com/manuelmoreale">consider becoming a supporter for 1$ a month</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 23:20:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203190</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Kai Gulliksen</title>
			<link>https://kaigulliksen.com/</link>
						<dc:creator>hello@manuelmoreale.com (Manuel Moreale)</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<ul>
                    <li><strong>Title:<strong> Kai Gulliksen</strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>Website:<strong> <a href="https://kaigulliksen.com/">kaigulliksen.com</a></strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>RSS Feed:<strong> <a href="https://kaigulliksen.com/">kaigulliksen.com/feed</a></strong></strong></li>                </ul>
                <hr>
                <p>A personal blog where I share my art and write about life, tech and anything else that is on my mind.</p>                <hr>
                <p>RSS users are my people 🫶 If you appreciate what I'm doing <a href="https://ko-fi.com/manuelmoreale">consider becoming a supporter for 1$ a month</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 08:35:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203193</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Matt Vestengen-Cox</title>
			<link>https://coxy.co/</link>
						<dc:creator>hello@manuelmoreale.com (Manuel Moreale)</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<ul>
                    <li><strong>Title:<strong> Matt Vestengen-Cox</strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>Website:<strong> <a href="https://coxy.co/">coxy.co</a></strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>RSS Feed:<strong> <a href="https://coxy.co/">coxy.co/feed</a></strong></strong></li>                </ul>
                <hr>
                <p>A designer at heart, Matt currently shapes the future of AI at Microsoft as part of the core Microsoft 365 Copilot team.</p>                <hr>
                <p>RSS users are my people 🫶 If you appreciate what I'm doing <a href="https://ko-fi.com/manuelmoreale">consider becoming a supporter for 1$ a month</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 09:35:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203196</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>May 2025</title>
			<link>https://thu-le.com/now/may-2025</link>
						<description><![CDATA[Trying a new format for my /Now updates.]]></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 09:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203177</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Gui</title>
			<link>https://www.glbck.com/</link>
						<dc:creator>hello@manuelmoreale.com (Manuel Moreale)</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<ul>
                    <li><strong>Title:<strong> Gui</strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>Website:<strong> <a href="https://www.glbck.com/">glbck.com</a></strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>RSS Feed:<strong> <a href="https://www.glbck.com/">glbck.com/feed.rss</a></strong></strong></li>                </ul>
                <hr>
                <p>Hi, my name’s Gui and this is my Digital Garden.</p>                <hr>
                <p>RSS users are my people 🫶 If you appreciate what I'm doing <a href="https://ko-fi.com/manuelmoreale">consider becoming a supporter for 1$ a month</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 02:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203194</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Emmanuel Odongo</title>
			<link>https://odongo.pl/</link>
						<dc:creator>hello@manuelmoreale.com (Manuel Moreale)</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<ul>
                    <li><strong>Title:<strong> Emmanuel Odongo</strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>Website:<strong> <a href="https://odongo.pl/">odongo.pl</a></strong></strong></li>
                                    </ul>
                <hr>
                <p>Emmanuel Odongo's personal website.</p>                <hr>
                <p>RSS users are my people 🫶 If you appreciate what I'm doing <a href="https://ko-fi.com/manuelmoreale">consider becoming a supporter for 1$ a month</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 01:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203186</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Brad Barrish</title>
			<link>https://bradbarrish.com/</link>
						<dc:creator>hello@manuelmoreale.com (Manuel Moreale)</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<ul>
                    <li><strong>Title:<strong> Brad Barrish</strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>Website:<strong> <a href="https://bradbarrish.com/">bradbarrish.com</a></strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>RSS Feed:<strong> <a href="https://bradbarrish.com/">bradbarrish.com/feed</a></strong></strong></li>                </ul>
                <hr>
                <p>My name is Brad Barrish. I grew up in Overland Park, Kansas and have lived in Los Angeles, California longer than I’ve lived anywhere else. I live with my wife Laura Hess, our daughter, Cassidy and son, Ozzie.</p>                <hr>
                <p>RSS users are my people 🫶 If you appreciate what I'm doing <a href="https://ko-fi.com/manuelmoreale">consider becoming a supporter for 1$ a month</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 23:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203195</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Chuck Grimmett</title>
			<link>https://cagrimmett.com/</link>
						<dc:creator>hello@manuelmoreale.com (Manuel Moreale)</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<ul>
                    <li><strong>Title:<strong> Chuck Grimmett</strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>Website:<strong> <a href="https://cagrimmett.com/">cagrimmett.com</a></strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>RSS Feed:<strong> <a href="https://cagrimmett.com/">cagrimmett.com/feed</a></strong></strong></li>                </ul>
                <hr>
                <p>Hi! I’m Chuck Grimmett. My wife Amanda and I have a son named Charlie. We live in Peekskill, NY. I work at Automattic on the Special Projects Team.</p>                <hr>
                <p>RSS users are my people 🫶 If you appreciate what I'm doing <a href="https://ko-fi.com/manuelmoreale">consider becoming a supporter for 1$ a month</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 23:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203192</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Arcade Blogger</title>
			<link>https://arcadeblogger.com/</link>
						<dc:creator>hello@manuelmoreale.com (Manuel Moreale)</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<ul>
                    <li><strong>Title:<strong> The Arcade Blogger</strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>Website:<strong> <a href="https://arcadeblogger.com/">arcadeblogger.com</a></strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>RSS Feed:<strong> <a href="https://arcadeblogger.com/">arcadeblogger.com/feed</a></strong></strong></li>                </ul>
                <hr>
                <p>A blog celebrating the history and preservation of Classic Arcade Video Games from the 70s and 80s.</p>                <hr>
                <p>RSS users are my people 🫶 If you appreciate what I'm doing <a href="https://ko-fi.com/manuelmoreale">consider becoming a supporter for 1$ a month</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2023 06:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203182</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sara Joy</title>
			<link>https://sarajoy.dev/</link>
						<dc:creator>hello@manuelmoreale.com (Manuel Moreale)</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<ul>
                    <li><strong>Title:<strong> Sara Joy</strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>Website:<strong> <a href="https://sarajoy.dev/">sarajoy.dev</a></strong></strong></li>
                    <li><strong>RSS Feed:<strong> <a href="https://sarajoy.dev/">sarajoy.dev/rss.xml</a></strong></strong></li>                </ul>
                <hr>
                <p>Personal blog with web-development</p>                <hr>
                <p>RSS users are my people 🫶 If you appreciate what I'm doing <a href="https://ko-fi.com/manuelmoreale">consider becoming a supporter for 1$ a month</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 00:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1763292791203191</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
