<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >
	<channel>
		<title> | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>http://192.168.1.206/FreshRSS/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of  | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:49:17 -0700</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:49:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="/i/?a=rss&amp;state=2" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
				<item>
			<title>job market websites suck</title>
			<link>https://blog.avas.space/job-market/</link>
						<dc:creator>avas</dc:creator>
			<category>2025</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Both my wife and I are going through the annoying process of trying to search for new jobs. I’m still at my current one, but I want to see if something better is out there in the region we wanna move to.</p>
<p>But it is absolutely <em>nuts</em>. How have these services not gone out of business?</p>
<p>My experience, almost entirely the same across many websites like StepStone, Indeed, and more:</p>
<ul>
<li>The on-site search is terrible to use. Search engine is easier.</li>
<li>Most of the results are ads.</li>
<li>Anything after the first 3 results is completely unrelated to the field you want.</li>
<li>You aren’t allowed to see the job posting without an account, or only as “Recruiter”. The preview is almost completely useless.</li>
<li>Partially blurred-out information that you are only allowed to see with an account.</li>
</ul>
<p>And for what? So that you’ll make an account and give up all that data and get harassed via e-mail for information that is freely available on the company’s own career page!</p>
<p>What are we doing? This is silly. Companies have already revealed that they hate and don’t consider the “Quick Apply” options these platforms offer, so what gives? And why are companies still using these slop platforms? It can’t be about getting more applicants, because these websites do anything they can to not show you the relevant job postings or information about them. If the search sucks, the preview is half-blurred and I can’t click on it without a pop-up urging me to make an account, you guessed it: I am actively discouraged from applying, prevented even, in many cases. I shouldn’t have to make an account with a third party just to even consider an employer! No, I will not create an account, and I will also not make a LinkedIn or Xing.</p>
<p>These services are not helping anyone, they are leeches. They have an interest in keeping you on their site searching jobs for a long time, and that goal is antithetical to connecting you with potential employers quickly. Companies are better off advertising elsewhere and keeping it on their own website so all potential candidates can access it. It’s a bad look seeing you on these enshittified platforms.</p>
<p>The way I have been coping with this job search is just using these websites to get a list of companies that have jobs in my niche and then researching them separately, using their own career pages and application portals. Also, relying on job listing websites ran by the government as these don’t use deceptive tactics to get you to sign up.</p>
<p>If you’re lucky, your professional niche has their own jobmarket websites (see, for example, <a href="https://www.rustjobs.fyi/">rustjobs.fyi</a>), or popular magazine publishers that are relevant in your field have a career sub-category on their website.</p>
<p>If you have any other tips I missed, let me know (email or your own post is fine!) and I’ll add it.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><a href="mailto:avas.space@pm.me">Reply via email</a><br>
Published <time datetime="2025-11-28T17:30Z">
    28 Nov, 2025
</time></p>
</blockquote>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878111</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Today: a Charity Donation, Shoplifting, and Laughing</title>
			<link>https://forkingmad.blog/today-a-charity-donation-shoplifting-laughing/</link>
						<dc:creator>forkingmad</dc:creator>
			<category>Life</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Today when I visited the supermarket, there was a lady at the entrance handing out leaflets.  She was asking people to buy a few extra items and place those in the box to be donated to the local foodbank. The leaflet gave ideas on the type of foods that were appropriate.</p>
<p>I was only in for a few items myself, but I decided I would get some things for the foodbank.</p>
<p>In the end I had more for them than me!  I had chosen to scan-as-I-go with my groceries, so I scanned everything as I put them in my basket, completed my transaction at the designated checkout, and wandered over to the foodbank lady to add to her box.</p>
<p>I gave her: two boxes of tea bags, three cartons of long-life fruit juice, two tins of soup, a tin of stew, dried oats, two packets of dried soup mix, a packet of pasta, a jar of pasta sauce.  Hopefully it will go some way to help someone in need.</p>
<h2 data-sanitized-id="apprehended-in-the-car-park">Apprehended in the Car Park</h2><p>I returned to the car with my own bag of shopping.  I was about to drive off when one of the supermarket employees came running up to the car and tapped my window.  She said my payment had failed and could I return to the shop.</p>
<p>How embarrassed was I?  Thinking I was doing a good deed, and then apparently running off without paying.</p>
<h2 data-sanitized-id="what-had-actually-happened">What had actually happened?</h2><p>When I was at the checkout, I had scanned the barcode to complete. I presented my card as normal for contactless payment.  I then left to give the foodbank groceries to her.</p>
<p>Unnoticed by me, my contactless payment was one of those random times when it actually wants you to insert your card!  I had walked away, oblivious to the fact I had not paid my bill.</p>
<h2 data-sanitized-id="crisis-averted">Crisis averted</h2><p>I returned to the shop and the checkout I had used was still waiting for my card.  I popped it in, entered my pin, and all was well.</p>
<p>I was so embarrassed.  At least we (the staff and the foodbank lady) had a laugh in the end.</p>
<div data-sanitized-class="komments">
<p>Leave a <a href="https://komments.cloud/389a17d0ee027aaa8e536e">Comment</a>; Or copy this <a>post id</a>and search for it in your Fediverse client to reply; Or <a href="https://forkingmad.blog/contact">send a message</a> if you have replied with your own blog post and I will mention it here.</p>
<div data-sanitized-id="fedi">
<p>https://gofer.social/@daj/statuses/01KB5QQ447GYC2KJV68EVKX5GV</p>
</div>
</div>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:11:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878110</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Revisit your old hobbies</title>
			<link>https://racc.blog/revisit-your-old-hobbies/</link>
						<dc:creator>raccoon</dc:creator>
			<category>2025</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Recently I’ve been returning to hobbies I grew away from, not because I stopped enjoying them, but because my time was limited I distanced myself from them and I couldn’t get myself back. Life moved on, schedules grew tight, and those little passions that once felt natural gradually faded into the background, and ultimately disappeared. Now I’ve picked them up again - gaming and reading, which had always been an on/off thing for me. Rediscovering them feels like opening a box you thought you’d lost. It’s familiar, comforting, and surprisingly refreshing.</p>
<p>There’s something satisfying in revisiting what once mattered the world for you. Old hobbies carry pieces of who we were: the excitement, the curiosity, the version of ourselves that had time to get lost in them. Returning to them feels like reconnecting with that earlier self, even if only for an hour at night or a quiet Thursday night. They don’t have to be permanent, they don’t have to define us, and there’s no shame in letting them go forever if they no longer fit who we are. But giving them another chance every now and then can be comforting.</p>
<p>If something once brought you joy, there was a reason. Maybe that reason still exists beneath everything new you’ve taken on. I’ve found a quiet satisfaction in rediscovering the things I left behind, and even if I move on once again, the return itself has value. Sometimes the best part is simply remembering that you’re allowed to pick things back up whenever you want. :]</p>
<hr>
<p>Enjoyed the article? Subscribe to my <a href="https://raccoon.bearblog.dev/feed/?type=rss"><strong>RSS feed</strong></a> :D</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 09:55:23 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878109</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Prologue in Sermons: November 28</title>
			<link>http://www.mystagogyresourcecenter.com/2025/11/prologue-in-sermons-november-28.html</link>
						<dc:creator>Unknown</dc:creator>
			<category>Archpriest Victor Guryev</category>
			<category>Saints and Feasts of November</category>
			<category>Slander</category>
			<category>St. John Chrysostom</category>
			<media:thumbnail url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhSP6sm7R5sxs0Vp1RkItPerGwSOr6IYvXfDNOcetETzUXx66sD5tchtC-maaj3n1Yl8RpEL_o_d4t2nKf4upN9hUqQEvyd9dopJg9ioBoj3tBU3pIqK2kC02b7sTyzG5LvKqHQ1pHx0JuQmolqdWfbi31VF80fdl9xKmcjncaR7wfVET9a4XQ906FGJyg/s72-w416-h640-c/558248257c2893e7803cc95822ec557e.jpg" width="72" height="72" />
			<media:content url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhSP6sm7R5sxs0Vp1RkItPerGwSOr6IYvXfDNOcetETzUXx66sD5tchtC-maaj3n1Yl8RpEL_o_d4t2nKf4upN9hUqQEvyd9dopJg9ioBoj3tBU3pIqK2kC02b7sTyzG5LvKqHQ1pHx0JuQmolqdWfbi31VF80fdl9xKmcjncaR7wfVET9a4XQ906FGJyg/s72-w416-h640-c/558248257c2893e7803cc95822ec557e.jpg" medium="image" height="72" width="72"></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[<div><b><div data-sanitized-class="separator"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhSP6sm7R5sxs0Vp1RkItPerGwSOr6IYvXfDNOcetETzUXx66sD5tchtC-maaj3n1Yl8RpEL_o_d4t2nKf4upN9hUqQEvyd9dopJg9ioBoj3tBU3pIqK2kC02b7sTyzG5LvKqHQ1pHx0JuQmolqdWfbi31VF80fdl9xKmcjncaR7wfVET9a4XQ906FGJyg/s1080/558248257c2893e7803cc95822ec557e.jpg"><img border="0" data-original-height="1080" data-original-width="702" height="640" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhSP6sm7R5sxs0Vp1RkItPerGwSOr6IYvXfDNOcetETzUXx66sD5tchtC-maaj3n1Yl8RpEL_o_d4t2nKf4upN9hUqQEvyd9dopJg9ioBoj3tBU3pIqK2kC02b7sTyzG5LvKqHQ1pHx0JuQmolqdWfbi31VF80fdl9xKmcjncaR7wfVET9a4XQ906FGJyg/w416-h640/558248257c2893e7803cc95822ec557e.jpg" width="416"></a></div> </b></div><div><b>The More a Person is Slandered by Slanderers, the More the Lord Glorifies Them</b><br><br><span>November 28</span>*<br><i><br>(From the Life of Saint John Chrysostom)</i><br><br>By Archpriest Victor Guryev<br></div><div><br>When our enemies and slanderers begin to slander us among others, spreading bad rumors about us and vilifying our name, we usually become despondent, fainthearted, and say, "Now I'm lost, now everyone will consider me a bad person and will despise me." But in reasoning like this, we are mistaken. When we hear negative words spoken about ourselves, we must always remember that there is an all-seeing and just God above us, that He will not allow our enemies to triumph over us, and that the evil they do to us is always ready to turn and will turn to our good.<br><br><span></span></div><a href="http://www.mystagogyresourcecenter.com/2025/11/prologue-in-sermons-november-28.html#more"></a>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 09:46:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878108</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pink Friday - a Bear theme for dodging the mania</title>
			<link>https://robertbirming.com/pink-friday-bear-theme/</link>
						<dc:creator>birming</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Are you also tired of the Black Friday shopping mania? Let’s make it fun in a free way instead of stressful in a “don’t really need it, but my gosh it’s cheap” way.</p>
<p>Simply copy the theme styles below, head over to your Bear theme settings, paste them in, and let the party begin. 🥳</p>
<p>If you’re using the wonderful <a href="https://guestbooks.meadow.cafe/">Guestbooks</a> by Meadow, the theme will take care of that too. Check <a href="https://robertbirming.com/guestbook/">my guestbook</a> to see how it looks. If you’re in the mood, and who isn’t after some Pink Friday vibes, feel free to write me something.</p>
<p>To give you a taste of how lovely the quotes look, here are a few fitting lines from the beautiful song <em>Society</em> by Eddie Vedder:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Oh, it's a mystery to me<br>
We have a greed, with which we have agreed<br>
And you think you have to want more than you need<br>
Until you have it all you won't be free</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em>Disclaimer: While there’s no technical limitation stopping you from using this theme to celebrate Black Friday, it’s considered bad karma. This may result in your posts getting fewer upvotes. Just saying...</em></p>
<p><button data-sanitized-class="pf-copy-btn">
<span data-sanitized-class="pf-copy-icon">🦄</span>
<span data-sanitized-class="pf-copy-text">Copy theme</span>
<span data-sanitized-class="pf-copy-done">Theme copied!</span>
</button></p>
<pre data-sanitized-id="pf-theme-code">
/*
 * Pink Friday — a joyful antidote to Black Friday madness
 * Version 1.0.0 | 2025-11-28
 * Author: Robert Birming
 * URL: https://robertbirming.com
 */

*,
*::before,
*::after {
  box-sizing: border-box;
}

:root {
  color-scheme: light dark;

  --bg:        #fff7fb;
  --txt:       #261321;
  --muted:     #8f6a7a;
  --line:      #f0d3e3;
  --accent:    #e45ba8;
  --accent-h:  color-mix(in srgb, var(--accent) 80%, var(--txt) 20%);
  --radius:    6px;
}

@media (prefers-color-scheme: dark) {
  :root {
    color-scheme: dark;

    --bg:       #1b1220;
    --txt:      #ffe9f8;
    --muted:    #c89bb4;
    --line:     #3c253f;
    --accent:   #ff7ec5;
    --accent-h: color-mix(in srgb, var(--accent) 80%, #ffffff 20%);
  }

  footer::before {
    background-image: linear-gradient(
      90deg,
      #ff9ad1,
      #ffcaee,
      #ff9ad1,
      #f9a9ff
    );
  }
}

::selection {
  background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--accent) 35%, var(--bg));
  color: var(--txt);
}

body {
  max-width: 640px;
  margin: 36px auto;
  padding: 0 20px;
  font-family: system-ui, sans-serif;
  font-size: 1.075rem;
  line-height: 1.66;
  letter-spacing: 0.01em;
  color: var(--txt);
  background: var(--bg);
  overflow-wrap: break-word;
}

main &gt; p:first-of-type {
  margin-top: 0.2em;
}

p {
  margin-block: 1.2em;
}

h1,
h2,
h3 {
  margin-block: 1.4em 0.6em;
  font-weight: 600;
  line-height: 1.2;
  letter-spacing: -0.01em;
  color: var(--txt);
}

h1 {
  margin-block: 0 0.4em;
}

h1 { font-size: 1.7rem; }
h2 { font-size: 1.45rem; }
h3 { font-size: 1.25rem; }

ul,
ol {
  margin-block: 1.2em;
  padding-left: 1.4em;
}

li + li {
  margin-top: 0.25em;
}

a {
  color: var(--accent);
  text-decoration: underline;
  text-decoration-thickness: 1px;
  text-underline-offset: 3px;
  transition:
    color 0.15s ease,
    text-decoration-thickness 0.15s ease;
}

a:hover {
  color: var(--accent-h);
  text-decoration-thickness: 2px;
}

blockquote {
  margin-block: 2em;
  margin-inline: 0;
  padding: 0.85em 1rem;
  border-left: 3px solid var(--accent);
  background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--bg) 85%, var(--accent) 15%);
  color: var(--muted);
  font-style: italic;
  border-radius: 10px;
  box-shadow: 0 2px 6px color-mix(in srgb, var(--txt) 10%, transparent);
}

blockquote p {
  margin: 0;
}

img {
  max-width: 100%;
  height: auto;
  display: block;
  margin-block: 1.4em;
  border-radius: 8px;
}

hr {
  border: none;
  border-top: 1px solid var(--line);
  margin-block: 2rem;
}

/* Header */
header {
  margin-bottom: 2.4rem;
  padding-bottom: 0;
  display: flex;
  flex-direction: column;
  align-items: flex-start;
  text-align: left;
  gap: 1.2rem;
}

header a.title {
  text-decoration: none;
  color: var(--txt);
  position: relative;
  display: inline-block;
}

header a.title h1 {
  margin: 0;
  padding: 0;
  font-size: 1.7rem;
  line-height: 1.2;
  letter-spacing: -0.01em;
  display: inline-block;
  filter:
    drop-shadow(0 0 2px color-mix(in srgb, var(--accent) 45%, transparent))
    drop-shadow(0 0 4px color-mix(in srgb, var(--accent-h) 35%, transparent));
  transition: filter 0.25s ease, transform 0.25s ease;
}

header a.title:hover h1 {
  filter:
    drop-shadow(0 0 4px color-mix(in srgb, var(--accent) 70%, transparent))
    drop-shadow(0 0 8px color-mix(in srgb, var(--accent-h) 55%, transparent));
  transform: scale(1.012);
}

header a.title h1::after {
  content: " *:･ﾟ✧";
  padding-left: 4px;
  background: linear-gradient(
    to right,
    var(--txt),
    var(--accent),
    color-mix(in srgb, var(--accent) 65%, var(--txt) 35%)
  );
  -webkit-background-clip: text;
  -webkit-text-fill-color: transparent;
          text-fill-color: transparent;
  vertical-align: baseline;
  opacity: 0.9;
}

/* Nav links */
header nav p {
  margin: 0;
  display: flex;
  flex-wrap: wrap;
  justify-content: center;
  gap: 0.6rem;
  font-size: 0.9rem;
}

header nav a {
  text-decoration: none;
  color: var(--accent);
  padding: 0.25rem 0.8rem 0.18rem;
  border-radius: 999px;
  background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--bg) 94%, var(--accent) 6%);
  border: 1px solid transparent;
  box-shadow: 0 1px 2px color-mix(in srgb, var(--txt) 10%, transparent);
  transition:
    background-color 0.18s ease,
    border-color 0.18s ease,
    box-shadow 0.18s ease,
    transform 0.18s ease;
}

@media (prefers-color-scheme: dark) {
  header nav a {
    background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--bg) 90%, var(--accent) 10%);
  }
}

header nav a:hover {
  color: var(--bg);
  background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--accent) 80%, var(--bg) 20%);
  border-color: color-mix(in srgb, var(--accent) 55%, var(--line));
  box-shadow: 0 4px 10px color-mix(in srgb, var(--txt) 16%, transparent);
  transform: translate(1px, 2px) rotate(2.5deg);
}

header nav a:active {
  transform: translate(0, 0) rotate(0deg);
  box-shadow: 0 1px 3px color-mix(in srgb, var(--txt) 20%, transparent);
}

/* Footer */
footer {
  position: relative;
  margin-top: 1rem;
  padding: 30px 0 26px;
  text-align: center;
  color: var(--muted);
  font-size: 0.95rem;
}

footer::before {
  content: "✧";
  display: block;
  margin: 0 auto 1.8rem;
  text-align: center;
  color: var(--accent);
  font-size: 1.25rem;
  letter-spacing: 0.35em;
  opacity: 0.95;
  width: 70%;
  background:
    linear-gradient(to right, transparent, var(--line) 70%),
    linear-gradient(to left, transparent, var(--line) 70%);
  background-size: 48% 1.5px, 48% 1.5px;
  background-position: left center, right center;
  background-repeat: no-repeat;
}

footer a {
  color: var(--accent);
  text-decoration: none;
}

footer a:hover {
  text-decoration: underline;
}

/* Blog */
time {
  font-style: normal;
  color: var(--muted);
  font-variant-numeric: tabular-nums;
  font-size: 0.9rem;
}

p &gt; time,
p &gt; i &gt; time {
  display: inline-block;
  margin-top: 0.2rem;
}

ul.blog-posts {
  list-style: none;
  padding: 0;
  margin: 1.6rem 0 0;
}

ul.blog-posts li {
  display: flex;
  align-items: baseline;
  gap: 0.9rem;
  padding-block: 0.4em;
  border-bottom: 1px solid color-mix(in srgb, var(--line) 60%, transparent);
}

ul.blog-posts li:first-child {
  border-top: 1px solid color-mix(in srgb, var(--line) 60%, transparent);
}

ul.blog-posts li span {
  flex: 0 0 140px;
  color: var(--muted);
  font-size: 0.9rem;
}

ul.blog-posts li a {
  color: var(--accent);
  text-decoration: none;
  font-weight: 500;
  display: inline-block;
  transition:
    color 0.15s ease,
    text-decoration-thickness 0.15s ease;
}

ul.blog-posts li a:hover {
  text-decoration: underline;
  text-decoration-thickness: 2px;
  color: var(--accent-h);
}

@media (max-width: 540px) {
  ul.blog-posts li {
    flex-direction: column;
    align-items: flex-start;
    padding-block: 0.7em;
    gap: 0.25em;
  }

  ul.blog-posts li span {
    order: 1;
    flex: none;
    font-size: 0.85rem;
  }

  ul.blog-posts li a {
    order: 0;
  }
}

/* Upvote button */
:is(.post, .page) .upvote-button {
  display: inline-flex !important;
  flex-direction: row !important;
  align-items: center !important;
  gap: 0.35rem;
  padding: 0.18rem 0.55rem;
  border-radius: 999px;
  border: 1px solid color-mix(in srgb, var(--line) 80%, transparent);
  background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--bg) 96%, var(--accent) 4%);
  color: var(--txt);
  font: inherit;
  line-height: 1;
  cursor: pointer;
  white-space: nowrap;
  transition:
    background-color 0.15s ease,
    border-color 0.15s ease,
    transform 0.12s ease;
}

:is(.post, .page) .upvote-button svg {
  display: none !important;
}

:is(.post, .page) .upvote-button::before {
  content: "♡";
  font-size: 1.25rem;
  line-height: 1;
  color: var(--accent);
  transform: translateY(1px);
  transition:
    color 0.15s ease,
    transform 0.12s ease;
}

:is(.post, .page) .upvote-button .upvote-count {
  display: inline-block !important;
  width: auto !important;
  flex: 0 0 auto !important;
  margin: 0 !important;
  padding: 0 !important;
  font-size: 0.85rem;
  color: var(--muted);
  opacity: 0.85;
  white-space: nowrap;
  transform: translateY(1px);
}

:is(.post, .page) .upvote-button:hover {
  background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--bg) 90%, var(--accent) 10%);
  border-color: color-mix(in srgb, var(--accent) 50%, var(--line));
  transform: translateY(-1px);
}

:is(.post, .page) .upvote-button:hover::before {
  transform: translateY(0);
}

:is(.post, .page) .upvote-button:is(.upvoted, [aria-pressed="true"], [disabled])::before {
  content: "♥";
  color: var(--accent-h);
}

:is(.post, .page) .upvote-button[disabled] {
  cursor: default;
  opacity: 0.85;
}

:is(.post, .page) .upvote-button:focus-visible {
  outline: 2px solid var(--accent);
  outline-offset: 2px;
}

/* Guestbook */
#guestbooks___guestbook-form-container form {
  display: grid;
  gap: 0.6rem;
  margin: 1.6rem 0;
}

#guestbooks___guestbook-form-container :is(input, textarea, button) {
  font: inherit;
  padding: 0.6rem 0.7rem;
  border-radius: var(--radius);
  border: 1px solid var(--line);
  background: var(--bg);
  color: var(--txt);
}

#guestbooks___guestbook-form-container :is(input, textarea) {
  width: 100%;
  line-height: 1.5;
}

#guestbooks___guestbook-form-container :is(input, textarea):focus {
  outline: none;
  border-color: var(--accent);
  box-shadow: 0 0 0 1px color-mix(in srgb, var(--accent) 35%, transparent);
}

#guestbooks___guestbook-form-container :is(button, input[type="submit"]) {
  cursor: pointer;
  font-weight: 600;
  align-self: flex-start;
  background: var(--accent);
  color: var(--bg);
  border-color: var(--accent);
  transition:
    background-color 0.2s ease,
    transform 0.15s ease;
}

#guestbooks___guestbook-form-container :is(button, input[type="submit"]):hover {
  background: var(--accent-h);
  transform: translateY(-1px);
}

#guestbooks___guestbook-messages-container &gt; div {
  margin: 1.2rem 0;
  padding: 1rem 1.1rem;
  font-size: 0.95rem;
  border-radius: calc(var(--radius) + 2px);
  border: 1px solid color-mix(in srgb, var(--accent) 40%, var(--bg));
  background: color-mix(in srgb, var(--bg) 93%, var(--accent) 7%);
}

#guestbooks___guestbook-messages-container blockquote {
  margin: 0 0 0.4rem;
  padding: 0;
  border: 0;
  background: none;
  box-shadow: none;
  border-radius: 0;
  font-style: normal;
  color: var(--txt);
}

#guestbooks___guestbook-messages-container p {
  margin: 0 0 0.4rem;
}

#guestbooks___guestbook-made-with {
  margin-top: 0.8rem;
  font-size: 0.85rem;
  color: var(--muted);
}
</pre>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 09:32:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878107</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>U.S. Age Verification Laws – The Facts</title>
			<link>https://takebackourtech.org/u-s-age-verification-laws-the-facts/</link>
						<dc:creator>Take Back Our Tech</dc:creator>
			<media:content url="https://takebackourtech.org/content/images/2025/11/TBOT-EP18-US-Age-Verification-Laws.jpg" medium="image"></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://takebackourtech.org/content/images/2025/11/TBOT-EP18-US-Age-Verification-Laws.jpg" alt="U.S. Age Verification Laws – The Facts"><p>Are age-verification laws the beginning of the end for the open internet? Many people feel something serious is happening, but few understand the actual legislation or how far it now reaches. With the Supreme Court upholding Texas’ HB 1181, age-verification requirements are no longer theoretical—they’re becoming a structural part of the U.S. internet.</p><p><a href="https://tbot.substack.com/p/us-age-verification-laws-the-facts?ref=takebackourtech.org">Watch on Substack</a></p><p>These laws begin with adult websites, but the architecture being built around them sets the groundwork for a much broader identity-based internet. At the same time, states are targeting app stores with “accountability” laws, and Google is tightening its grip on how Android apps can be installed. Put together, the picture becomes much clearer.</p><h2 data-sanitized-id="the-new-age-verification-rules"><strong>The New Age Verification Rules</strong></h2><p>Across <a href="https://www.legis.state.tx.us/tlodocs/88R/billtext/html/HB01181F.HTM?ref=takebackourtech.org">Texas</a>, <a href="https://le.utah.gov/~2023/bills/sbillenr/SB0287.pdf?ref=takebackourtech.org">Utah</a>, <a href="https://legis.la.gov/legis/ViewDocument.aspx?d=1289498&amp;ref=takebackourtech.org">Louisiana</a>, and <a href="https://billstatus.ls.state.ms.us/documents/2023/html/SB/2300-2399/SB2346SG.htm?ref=takebackourtech.org">Mississippi</a>, the language is nearly identical. Any website where roughly a third of the content is considered “harmful to minors” must verify the age of every visitor before allowing access. Verification must be done through:</p><ul><li>a government-issued ID,</li><li>a digitized ID card,</li><li>or a third-party age-verification database using transactional data.</li></ul><p>Websites are instructed not to store identifying information after approval, but the identity check still takes place. The mechanism is now established: show your ID before viewing certain content.</p><figure data-sanitized-class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/%24s_!rKji!,w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fd873ffcb-9dbb-469e-98e2-07023edc2c2b_742x592.jpeg" alt="U.S. Age Verification Laws – The Facts" width="742" height="592" data-sanitized-class="kg-image"></figure><p>If you live in one of these states, you’ve already seen this in action. Adult sites now display warning banners and ID checks. The only current workaround is a VPN that places your IP outside the regulated states, because the site’s location check is based entirely on your IP.</p><p>The key point: the legal precedent has been set. States now have a tested, court-approved framework for requiring digital identification online.</p><h2 data-sanitized-id="expanding-into-app-stores"><strong>Expanding Into App Stores</strong></h2><p>While these age-verification laws focus on content, states like Texas and Utah have introduced a separate category of rules targeting app distribution. App stores must now verify the age of users when they create accounts. And “app store” is defined so broadly that it can include:</p><ul><li>websites that distribute apps,</li><li>alternative catalog front-ends,</li><li>open-source repositories like F-Droid,</li><li>or essentially any platform where software is downloaded.</li></ul><p>Even the phrase “mobile device” is defined broadly enough to include laptops.</p><p>This quietly pulls software distribution under the same identity-verification umbrella. Open-source platforms may be forced to either introduce account systems—<a href="https://f-droid.org/2022/02/28/no-user-accounts-by-design.html?ref=takebackourtech.org">something many deliberately avoid for privacy reasons</a>—or block users from certain states entirely. In Gitlab forums these possibilities are being openly discussed, including creating <a href="https://gitlab.com/fdroid/admin/-/issues/543?ref=takebackourtech.org">separate restricted repositories</a> or implementing geo-blocking.</p><p>This is a direct pressure on anonymous software access. It introduces liability concerns for developers and catalog maintainers and shifts the internet away from open download ecosystems and toward identity-locked platforms.</p><h2 data-sanitized-id="google-tightens-control-over-sideloading"><strong>Google Tightens Control Over Sideloading</strong></h2><p>In a surprising turn of events, Google is adjusting their <a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2025/11/android-developer-verification-early.html?m=1&amp;ref=takebackourtech.org">new developer verification requirements</a>. As I’ve covered on #TBOT 15 – <a href="https://tbot.substack.com/p/no-anonymous-apps-google-bans-sideloaded?utm_source=publication-search">these new rules would have prevented Android users from installing open-source apps</a> that don’t give up their IDs and signing keys to Google.</p><p>Now Google won’t be completely blocking these apps but will now require an “advanced flow.”</p><p>You can assume this to mean Dark UI, that makes it fairly annoying and difficult to install apps directly from the source, apparently this should only be trusted for developers and power users.</p><p>Previously Google pointed to their vague study of apps in the Android ecosystem, they looked at apps on the web and found there were more malicious than the proportion on the Play Store. They gave literally no numbers.</p><p>Now this is happening again, with one Southeast Asia malware app as an example, but left without a name or example of how widespread this is.</p><p>Instead of building a prison wall around current Android users, now they’ve downgraded to a barbed wire fence. It’s going to be a pain to get across.</p><p>Remember, this change will occur in 2027, and there’s no telling where they will stop. Once the system is rolled out to classify apps in this fashion, the security measure can easily be adjusted or locked out completely.</p><p>Now is the time to ditch official Android phones altogether and use a de-Googled counterpart.</p><hr><figure data-sanitized-class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/%24s_!kb5V!,w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F51603866-8995-4844-ba63-6087ea3491ed_941x521.png" alt="U.S. Age Verification Laws – The Facts" width="941" height="521" data-sanitized-class="kg-image"></figure><p>🛍️ <strong>Above’s Black Friday Sale is Back!</strong><br>Our best sale of the year is back—with some phones up to <strong>$500 off</strong>, plus deals on laptops and bundles.</p><p>If you’re ready to upgrade your privacy gear, now is the best time.</p><p>Don’t wait—supplies of our most popular devices are extremely limited!</p><p><a href="https://abovephone.com/blackfriday/?ref=takebackourtech.org">Shop Now!</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 08:54:51 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878106</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Accepting Applications For New BFF</title>
			<link>https://www.neuronetch.com/accepting-applications-for-new-bff/</link>
						<dc:creator>neuronetch</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>My best friend got married and is increasingly becoming "domesticated" and spending most of his free time with his beloved.</p>
<p>This is a <strong>tragedy</strong>.</p>
<p>I am looking for another person to bother everyday. Please send your applications by hitting the Mail Reply button or emailing: khem(AT)neuronetch(DOT)com</p>
<p>If you like any of the following, we'll probably get along:</p>
<ul>
<li>Weird rambling of interests.</li>
<li>Sci-fi, programming, hacker culture.</li>
<li>Books (any is fine).</li>
<li>Maybe sending and receiving trash internet articles.</li>
<li>Will put up with my bullsh*t.</li>
</ul>
<p>Race, looks, gender and religion does not matter. Only the conduct of your character.</p>
<p>This is not satire. Serious applications only.</p>
<h5>
   	<a href="mailto:khem@neuronetch.com?subject=Re:%20Accepting%20Applications%20For%20New%20BFF">
  		Mail reply
	</a>
</h5>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 08:41:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878105</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Black Friday for You and Me</title>
			<link>https://enocc.com/2025/11/28/black-friday.html</link>
						<dc:creator>Pablo Enoc</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday it was Thanksgiving and I had the privilege of spending the holiday with my family. We have a tradition of doing a toast going around the table and sharing at least one thing for which we are grateful.</p>

<p>I want to share with you a story that started last year, in January of 2024, when a family friend named Germán reached out to me for help with a website for his business.</p>

<p>Germán is in his 50s, he went to school for mechanical engineering in Mexico and about twenty years ago he moved to the United States. Today he owns a restaurant in Las Vegas with his wife and also runs a logistics company for distributing produce.</p>

<p>We met the last week of January, he told me that he was looking to build a website for his restaurant and eventually build up his infrastructure so most of his business could be automated. His current workflow required his two sons to run the business along with him. They managed everything manually on expensive proprietary software.</p>

<p>There were lots of things that could be optimized, so I agreed to jump on board and we have been collaborating ever since. What I assumed would be a developer type of position instead became more of a peer-mentorship relationship.</p>

<p>Germán is curious, intelligent, and hard working. It didn’t take long for me to notice that  he didn’t just want to have software or services running “in the background” while he occupied himself with other tasks. He wanted to have a thorough understanding of all the software he adopted.</p>

<p>“I want to learn but I simply don’t have the patience,” he told me during one of our first meetings. At first I admit I thought this was a bit of a red flag (sorry Germán haha) but it all began to make sense when he showed me his books.</p>

<p>He had paid thousands of dollars for a Wordpress website that only listed his services and contact information. The company he had hired offered an expensive SEO package for a monthly fee. My time in open source and the indieweb had blinded me to how abusive the “web development” industry had become. I’m referring to those local agencies that take advantage of unsuspecting clients and charge them for every little thing.</p>

<p>I began making Germán’s website and we went back and forth on assets, copy, menus, we began putting together a project and everything went smoothly. He was happy that he got to see how I built things. During this time I would journal through my work on his project and e-mail my notes to him. He loved it.</p>

<p>Next came a new proposition. While the static site was nice to have an online presence, what he was after was getting into e-commerce. His wife, Sarah, makes artisanal beauty products and custom clothes. Her friends would message her on Facebook to ask what new stuff she was working on and she would send pictures to them from her phone. She would have benefitted from having a website, but after the bad experience they had had with the agency, they weren’t too enthused about the prospect of hiring them for another project.</p>

<p>I met with both of them again for this new project and we talked for hours, more like coworkers this time around. We eventually came to the conclusion that it would be more rewarding for them to really learn how to put their own shop together. I acted more as a coach or mentor than a developer. We’d sit together and activate accounts, fill out pages, choose themes. I was providing a safe space for them to be curious about technology, make mistakes, learn from them, and immediately get feedback on technical details so they could stay on a safe path.</p>

<p>I’m so grateful for that opportunity afforded to me by Germán and his family. I’ve thought about how that approach would look if applied to the indieweb. It’s always so exciting for me to see what  the friends I’ve made here are working on. I know the open web becomes stronger when more independent projects are released, as we have more options to free ourselves from the corporate web that has stifled so much of the creativity and passion that I love and miss from the internet.</p>

<p>I want to keep doing this. If you are building something on your own, have been out of the programming world for a while but want to start again, or maybe you are almost done and need a little boost in confidence (or accountability!) to reach the finish line and ship, I’m here to help.</p>

<p>Check out my <a href="https://enocc.com/coaching">coaching page</a> to find out more.</p>

<p>I’m excited about the prospect of a community of builders who care about self-reliance and releasing software that puts people first.</p>

<p>Perhaps this Black Friday you could choose to invest in yourself :-)</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 08:33:21 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878104</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Lately, I’ve been thinking of writing a novel…</title>
			<link>https://chavanniclass.wordpress.com/2025/11/28/thinking-novel/</link>
						<dc:creator>Ratika Deshpande</dc:creator>
			<category>Writing</category>
			<category>cities</category>
			<category>life</category>
			<category>love</category>
			<category>novel</category>
			<media:content url="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/3c01cee950e21d4f28b9086b49afb4c05bddf47c69611ed3eaf3e40277707053?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image"><media:title type="html">ratikadeshpande</media:title></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Nothing too big or important. Just little anecdotes patched together, the ingredients a mix of real and imagined things and feelings. Something that could have a soft painting as its cover. A gentle title. A book one could read with a cup of tea, leaned back in a chair. A book about cities and cafes, long walks and urban greenery. About books and lakes and cakes and markets. About one-time strangers and regular, familiar strangers. About known haunts and unknown places. About people one could dial anytime and people one could dial only at certain times. About feeling lost, feeling hopeful, feeling stuck. About wondering whether you’ve fallen in love. About nursing heartbreak in a city of a thousand daily heartbreaks. About chai at a tapri and coffee in aesthetic restaurants. About stationery shops and second-hand shops, gardens and historical monuments. Little houses painted with bright colors. Big houses bursting with plants and vines in balconies. Spotting stray cats and delighting at a bougainvillea bulging with magenta flowers over someone’s boundary wall. A small novel about small things and big and small feelings (but not big things). I think I’d like to write a novel like that.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 08:13:40 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878103</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>On eating shit</title>
			<link>https://manuelmoreale.com/thoughts/on-eating-shit</link>
						<dc:creator>hello@manuelmoreale.com (Manuel Moreale)</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>You’re sitting at a table. In front of you, a series of plates. They’re full of shit (like some people). Not the same shit, mind you. It’s different types, produced by different animals, in different quantities. The unfortunate reality of the situation is that you have to eat the contents of one of those plates. Yeah, it sucks, I’m sorry. But you just have to.</p>
<p>So you understandably start going through the thought process of figuring out which one is the “best” one. You start examining the shape, the texture, the animal that produced it. You start finding reasons to pick one over another. You start rationalising, trying to justify your decision to the other people who, like you, also need to pick which one to eat.</p>
<p>It’s a process. A shitty one, I might say. But in going through this ordeal, you start losing track of the only thing that really matters: this situation fucking sucks, and there’s no good answer. The only reasonable thing to do is to pick the plate with the least steamy, smelly, nasty pile of shit and then figure out a way not to find yourself in that situation ever again.</p>
<p>Sometimes eating shit is unavoidable. The only thing you can do is make it as painless as possible.</p>        <hr>
        <p>Thank you for keeping RSS alive. You're awesome.</p>
        <p><a href="mailto:hello@manuelmoreale.com">Email me</a> ::
        <a href="https://manuelmoreale.com/guestbook">Sign my guestbook</a> :: 
        <a href="https://ko-fi.com/manuelmoreale">Support for 1$/month</a> :: 
        <a href="https://manuelmoreale.com/supporters">See my generous supporters</a> :: 
        <a href="https://buttondown.email/peopleandblogs">Subscribe to People and Blogs</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 08:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878102</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Cloudfare Takes Down The Internet; Here’s an Alternative</title>
			<link>https://takebackourtech.org/cloudfare-takes-down-the-internet/</link>
						<dc:creator>Take Back Our Tech</dc:creator>
			<media:content url="https://takebackourtech.org/content/images/2025/11/TBOT-EP18-Cloudflare-Takes-Down-the-Internet.jpg" medium="image"></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://takebackourtech.org/content/images/2025/11/TBOT-EP18-Cloudflare-Takes-Down-the-Internet.jpg" alt="Cloudfare Takes Down The Internet; Here’s an Alternative"><p>Cloudflare just had its worst outage since 2019, lasting about 5 hours on November 18th. It took down all of its customers due to the scope of the outage, and even Cloudfare thought they had been hacked at first. Let’s dig in.</p><p>What is Cloudfare?</p><ul><li>Its an edge network and proxy providing different services like DNS, DDOS prevention, and web firewalls.</li><li>Its supposed to make websites faster by service their resources closer to the visitor, through CloudFare’s 330 edge nodes all over the world</li><li>These edge nodes also do many other things like protect websites from DDoS attacks, and active attackers - these are identified and dropped at the edge</li></ul><p>For all of these reasons, 18% of sites on the internet choose to use Cloudfare, they have massive visibility on the internet at large - and have visibility to about 25% of the world’s internet traffic, since many big sites use them.</p><p>On November 18th, Cloudfare went down, taking down a big chunk of the internet with them.</p><ul><li>Canva</li><li>CharacterAI</li><li>ChatGPT</li><li>ClaudeAI</li><li>Ikea</li><li>Spotify</li><li>Truth Social</li><li>Uber</li><li>X</li><li>Zoom</li></ul><p>On <a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/18-november-2025-outage/?ref=takebackourtech.org">their blog</a>, Cloudflare shared that a bug to their Bot Management module was responsible for the outage. Each request incoming through Cloudfare’s core proxy system goes through a number of modules, the Bot Management module gives visitors bot scores. This happens every single request going through Cloudfare - its detecting whether you are a bot.</p><p>An underlying change to their distributed database caused the Bot Management module to load extra data and run out of memory.</p><p>You can see in this graph, almost all of Cloudflare’s traffic was effected - around 26M requests per seconds as the team tried to figure out what was going on.</p><figure data-sanitized-class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/%24s_!UiwQ!,w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F619771c0-b36c-4571-b955-fcbed2f0087e_1507x733.png" alt="Cloudfare Takes Down The Internet; Here’s an Alternative" width="1456" height="708" data-sanitized-class="kg-image"></figure><p>Although Cloudflare perceives itself as defenders of the internet, protecting government websites and organizations from DDOS attempts - its important to remind ourselves how much power this one company holds.</p><p>It makes the internet less resilient as 20% of the internet can fail at one time.</p><p>Cloudflare can also make the decision to <a href="https://www.trtworld.com/article/12879922?ref=takebackourtech.org">cut off websites</a> from the internet - cutting off its services to the image board 8Chan in 2019 for hateful content.</p><p>8Chan could have used some other provider to protect itself against DDOS attack but it ended up going offline instead.</p><p>The CEO Matthew Prince has also arbitrarily kicked websites off the service for their views such as a <a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2017/08/cloudflare-ceo-the-people-behind-the-daily-stormer-are-assholes/?ref=takebackourtech.org">Neo Nazi website.</a></p><p>This was his personal arbitrary decision, he wrote that he “woke up this morning in a bad mood and decided to kick them off the Inernet.”</p><p>He then said that this amount of centralized power was bad and it shouldn’t be in one person’s hand - I suppose he’d rather hand it off to an oligopoly of big tech companies following government regulations.</p><p>To make things more confusing, Cloudlfare reportedly provided services to groups considered terrorists under US Sanction laws, including the Taliban and Hamas - although the U.S makes no moves to punish them for providing services to sanctioned groups.</p><p>Why is Cloudflare able to do this without being prosecuted under OFAC?</p><p>Lead counsel for Cloudflare said they are trying to be “neutral”, and are “aware of their obligations under sanctions laws” and have a “policy in place to stay in compliance”. I don’t know how that’s possible given that they <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/cloudflare-cybersecurity-terrorist-groups_n_5c127778e4b0835fe3277f2f?ref=takebackourtech.org">receive money from these organizations</a>, but hey - they have good lawyers.</p><p>Perhaps its because knowing who visits these websites is valuable information for Cloudflare and its partners.</p><p>Cloudflare received <a href="https://cf-assets.www.cloudflare.com/slt3lc6tev37/2BmbjEkYKHyCBKwipz2Hjf/bed72e2328f2967941a17d773005a2d6/H2_2024_LegalRequestsforInformationTransparencyReport_AQFinal.pdf?ref=takebackourtech.org">700 requests from the U.S government</a> in 2024 for data, and around 60% of these cases, data was provided.</p><p>So what should sites do if they need to protect themselves from bots?</p><p>In comes <a href="https://felsqualle.com/posts/2025/05/anubis-saved-our-websites-from-a-ddos-attack/?ref=takebackourtech.org">Anubis</a>, a Web AI Firewall utility that acts as a proxy to judge requests before they reach your website. It protects the site from automated botnets and potential DDOS attacks by making incoming requests perform proof of work, where people’s browsers solve simple challenges, the same types of challenges miners solve in the Bitocin network.</p><p>Cloudflare’s outage is a reminder of just how fragile the modern internet becomes when so much power is concentrated in a single company. One bug shouldn’t be able to take down nearly 20% of the web, and one CEO shouldn’t be able to decide who stays online and who disappears.</p><p>But this doesn’t have to be the future.<br>Tools like Anubis show that we <em>can</em> build defenses that don’t rely on centralized gatekeepers with oversized control and opaque relationships with governments. We can choose infrastructure that is transparent, distributed, and accountable.</p><p>The more we adopt alternatives and decentralize our digital foundations, the stronger — and freer — the internet becomes.</p><figure data-sanitized-class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/%24s_!kb5V!,w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F51603866-8995-4844-ba63-6087ea3491ed_941x521.png" alt="Cloudfare Takes Down The Internet; Here’s an Alternative" width="941" height="521" data-sanitized-class="kg-image"></figure><p>🛍️ <strong>Above’s Black Friday Sale is Back!</strong><br>Our best sale of the year is back—with some phones up to <strong>$500 off</strong>, plus deals on laptops and bundles.</p><p>If you’re ready to upgrade your privacy gear, now is the best time.</p><p>Don’t wait—supplies of our most popular devices are extremely limited!</p><p><a href="https://abovephone.com/blackfriday/?above=tbot&amp;ref=takebackourtech.org">Shop now!</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 07:58:24 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878101</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>&quot;On Writing Well&quot; by William Zinsser</title>
			<link>https://lwgrs.bearblog.dev/on-writing-well-by-william-zinsser/</link>
						<dc:creator>lwgrs</dc:creator>
			<category>books</category>
			<category>echo</category>
			<category>reviews</category>
			<category>writing</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>To properly review this book, I should write about my experience while reading it. One thing I learned is that if you're not a professional reviewer or critic, you may not have the expertise to draw on to express how "good" or "bad" a book may be. I'm not an expert writer, nor a professional reviewer, but my feelings are my own.</p>
<p>I can't remember when I first learned of the book. It was probably form one of many blogs in my feed reader, but when the book became available from the library I was hesitant to check it out. If I couldn't remember <em>why</em> I placed the hold, was the book still relevant?</p>
<p>After brief research I borrowed the book and found it was exactly the right book for me. I raced through each chapter, recording multiple passages in my notes. If I owned the book, I would have used a highlighter.</p>
<p>As I read the book I became more inspired to write and to start a project - any project. The most prominent among them is my ongoing desire to write a book about my experiences with Epilepsy.</p>
<p>The immediate effect was that I started reviewing and revising everything I wrote. Not even work correspondences are immune to revision; in fact this was where I found the advice most useful. I was already careful to write clear and concise emails, but the advice in the book helped further distill my writing.</p>
<p>I'm trying my best to practice reviewing and rewriting my blog posts too, but it's difficult to resist the temptation to click "publish" right away. I'm too excited to share my work, but I now realize by holding myself to higher standards I can produce <em>better</em> work that people will enjoy reading. I can only write as well as I'm able, but now I know I'm capable of more.</p>
<p>Self-doubt is something that any writer faces, and despite early chapters addressing this, it surfaced again as I continued reading. Zinsser uses examples from wonderful sources, showing what is possible with hard work and practice.</p>
<p>The effect this had on me was to hold myself to an impossible standard. It felt like Zinsser wanted the reader to mimic the style of the writers he cited.</p>
<p>Thankfully I realized that wasn't the case. The book is meticulously planned, like he was setting those expectations, only to bring them down to Earth and reassure the writer to trust their own style. The sources cited serve to show what is possible when you put effort into your craft - not that all non-fiction should be written in a certain tone, or rely on a sophisticated vocabulary.</p>
<p>Perhaps the greatest takeaway is this: write about what interests you, and refine it. If you present it in a way that makes it easy to read and hook the reader, they'll follow you anywhere.</p>
<p>A great example of this is Zinsser's article about a trip to Timbuktu. He used it to break down the decisions that went into crafting the article, but I would have enjoyed it even without the annotations. I would never have chosen to read a travel article, but I found his account a joy to read.</p>
<p>This brings me to a recent blog post written by <a href="https://veronique.ink/" data-sanitized-class="nametag">Véronique</a>. She gave examples of what you can put in a zine: <a href="https://veronique.ink/anything-and-everything/">anything and everything.</a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<ul>
<li>diary entries</li>
<li>interviews</li>
<li>lists</li>
<li>manifestos</li>
<li>memories</li>
<li>personal news/observations</li>
<li>quotes</li>
<li>recipes</li>
<li>reviews of your fav books, movies, shows, zines you've been reading</li>
<li>playlists</li>
<li>cut-outs of your phone notes</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>The point is - make it interesting to you, and make it engaging. People will enjoy it if they can relate to you through your writing.</p>
<p>Write a blog post, or book, or zine. Let it breathe, and then see what you can change to make it better. Maybe it's as little as tweaking a few words, or fixing a paragraph that has a clunky rhythm.</p>
<p>That is what I got from this book, and it will forever hold a place at my desk. It is an invaluable resource that no star rating can properly define.</p>
<p>(For the record, my star rating is ⭐⭐⭐⭐⭐.)</p>
<h6 data-sanitized-id="a-hrefhttpsletterbirdcosrgreply-by-emaila-nbsp-a-hrefhttpswwwaddtoanycomshareurl-post_link-title-post_title-target_blankshare-this-postanbsp-a-hrefhttpsottawaplacesrgowermastodonanbsp-a-hrefhttpsbskyappprofilesrgowercomblueskya"><a href="https://letterbird.co/srg">Reply by email</a>   <a href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=https://lwgrs.bearblog.dev/on-writing-well-by-william-zinsser&amp;title=%22On%20Writing%20Well%22%20by%20William%20Zinsser">Share this post</a>  <a href="https://ottawa.place/@srgower/">Mastodon</a>  <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/srgower.com">Bluesky</a></h6>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 07:45:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878100</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Build A Daily Writing Ritual</title>
			<link>https://nikhil.bearblog.dev/build-a-daily-writing-ritual/</link>
						<dc:creator>nikhil</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>If you want to write with style, you must formulate your thoughts completely before putting them on paper. This allows your mind to focus not on <em>what</em> to write but on <em>how</em> to write, thereby delivering stylistic excellence. This approach naturally means producing fewer works, but with greater quality. The primary focus remains on delivering substance.</p>
<p>However, when you want to crystallize your thoughts, you need to write extensively because your thinking is scattered and requires organization. That's why people who write daily often appear sharper, possess greater clarity, and are more articulate than their peers. The bulk of their thinking has been done on blank pages. The daily writing ritual forces them to take a fragment of thought and explain it without confusion. In the process, they encounter their own ideas and the reasons behind cultivating them.</p>
<p>I am a prolific writer—or so I like to think. I write historical ebooks, fiction short stories and novels, financial newsletters and posts, and essays on various thoughts. I strongly believed that one must never post essays of inferior quality; there's enough clutter on the internet without adding to it. I still agree with this principle, but when it comes to maintaining a blog, I beg to differ.</p>
<p>It's far easier to sustain a daily writing ritual if you have a blog. You gain a sense of sharing your ideas with the world, and when you look back on those essays, they remind you of everything you went through. All the essays on my blog are essentially thoughts I first captured in notes, then expanded upon later. I deliberately keep them free of fluff. I write as if explaining to a friend. When you remove the pressure of delivering polished quality, you naturally start generating more ideas.</p>
<p>You must let ideas flow through your mind. Let them come—these are the thoughts you need to resolve. You must grow comfortable seeing your ideas manifest on paper, translating them into words. I guarantee they will not only grant you additional clarity but will also trouble you far less. Say you're navigating a difficult phase of life and write about it in one essay. The next time, you'll examine the same phase through a different lens, another perspective, and delve deeper than before.</p>
<p>That is the ultimate purpose of writing, and precisely why you must maintain a blog. Cultivate a writing ritual. Identify the thoughts racing through your head and address them one by one. Quality doesn't matter in every context. You need quantity first to resolve all those thoughts. Eventually, you'll realize you've achieved greater clarity and become more articulate.</p>
<p>And isn't that what they call peace?</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 07:42:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878099</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Actual Burnout</title>
			<link>https://frills.dev/blog/2025/november/actual-burnout/</link>
						<description><![CDATA[Processing my time spent signed off work]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 06:01:43 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878098</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Our Oven Died at 1:00pm on Thanksgiving (As in… Yesterday.)</title>
			<link>https://kennethbwrites.substack.com/p/our-oven-died-at-100pm-on-thanksgiving</link>
						<dc:creator>Kenneth B.</dc:creator>
			<media:content url="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/$s_!B7tq!,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fb9868401-bdce-40e0-9ee9-7395a952818d_2016x928.heic" type="image/jpeg"></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[<div data-sanitized-class="captioned-image-container"><figure><a href="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/%24s_!B7tq!,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fb9868401-bdce-40e0-9ee9-7395a952818d_2016x928.heic" data-component-name="Image2ToDOM" data-sanitized-class="image-link image2 is-viewable-img"><div data-sanitized-class="image2-inset"><picture><source type="image/webp"><img src="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/%24s_!B7tq!,w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fb9868401-bdce-40e0-9ee9-7395a952818d_2016x928.heic" width="1456" height="670" data-attrs='{"src":"https://substack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/b9868401-bdce-40e0-9ee9-7395a952818d_2016x928.heic","srcNoWatermark":null,"fullscreen":null,"imageSize":null,"height":670,"width":1456,"resizeWidth":null,"bytes":218332,"alt":null,"title":null,"type":"image/heic","href":null,"belowTheFold":false,"topImage":true,"internalRedirect":"https://kennethbwrites.substack.com/i/180173898?img=https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2Fb9868401-bdce-40e0-9ee9-7395a952818d_2016x928.heic","isProcessing":false,"align":null,"offset":false}' alt="" data-sanitized-class="sizing-normal"></picture><div data-sanitized-class="image-link-expand"><div data-sanitized-class="pencraft pc-display-flex pc-gap-8 pc-reset"><button data-sanitized-class="pencraft pc-reset pencraft icon-container restack-image"></button><button data-sanitized-class="pencraft pc-reset pencraft icon-container view-image"></button></div></div></div></a></figure></div><p>I have always suspected that God has a sense of humor. Yesterday He decided to prove it.</p><p>There I was—two-thirds of the way through Thanksgiving dinner, the mashed potatoes whipped into pillows of glory, the sweet potatoes caramelized to perfection, the ham finished, however five other dishes were only half done—when suddenly our oven let out a groan, flickered, huge sparks, and suddenly it died. Not politely. Not with dignity. Just <em>dead.</em></p><p>A short, a spark, and then the kind of silence that makes your stomach drop.</p><p>We had guests arriving in two and a half hours. Every burner on the stovetop was gone. We called neighbors on both sides of us, and they each had their ovens and stovetops filled to the brim with their own Thanksgiving feasts. And I still had enough dishes left to qualify for a cooking show meltdown.</p><p>In the middle of this domestic apocalypse, our daughter remembered:<br>“I’m cat-sitting. My friend said we could use his kitchen if we need anything.”</p><p>Ten minutes later we were in the car—me clutching half-cooked dishes like sacred relics, my daughter driving, both of us praying the cat didn’t decide to help. We dashed in, commandeered the kitchen like culinary pirates, finished every dish in a strange house, and then rushed home with steaming trays and triumphantly rescued turkey.</p><p>We walked through the door ten minutes before our guests arrived.</p><p>I don’t think I’ve ever been more grateful for a fully functioning oven <em>that wasn’t mine.</em></p><p>It was, shall we say, a stressful Thanksgiving.</p><div><hr></div><h3><strong>But Here’s the Part I Can’t Shake</strong></h3><p>Later that night, when the last plate was washed and the house finally exhaled, my wife and I sat down, tired….</p><p>For the first time in nearly thirty years of marriage, we feel like we are at a crossroads.</p><p>Not a crisis. Not a collapse. A crossroads.</p><p>The road ahead is not spelled out the way it has been in other seasons. There was a long stretch of life—raising children, pursuing careers, building routines—where the next step always seemed obvious. There was always a plan, always a direction, always a sense of “forward.” But now? There is something new, something quieter, something strangely open-ended.</p><p>And yesterday, in its small domestic absurdity, felt like a parable.</p><p>Sometimes the oven just dies.</p><p>Sometimes the plan collapses halfway through.</p><p>Sometimes what you thought was predictable suddenly isn’t—and you find yourself scrambling, improvising, borrowing someone else’s kitchen, discovering that you are far more dependent on others than you realized.</p><p>Sometimes God gently removes the illusion that you had everything under control.</p><p>And as strange as it sounds, maybe that is good.</p><div><hr></div><h3><strong>What If This Is the Gift?</strong></h3><p>Maybe the real spiritual significance of our Thanksgiving fiasco was not the turkey or the timing or the broken appliance. Maybe it was the reminder that we are never meant to navigate life by sheer foresight and planning.</p><p>Maybe the collapse was the invitation.</p><p>Maybe God is teaching us—after thirty years of marriage—to hold the future more lightly, to embrace the unknown with less fear, to trust Him in the gaps where our competence can no longer carry us.</p><p>We often think spiritual growth happens in monasteries or mountaintop moments. But I’m beginning to suspect it also happens in borrowed kitchens on Thanksgiving afternoon.</p><p>Because the question is not whether we know what the next season holds.</p><p>It’s whether we trust the One who does.</p><p>And maybe—just maybe—the broken oven was the most honest sermon I heard all week.<br><br>~ Kenneth </p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 05:54:33 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878097</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Playing games without speaking English was an experience on its own</title>
			<link>https://kkc.bearblog.dev/playing-games-without-speaking-english-was-an-experience-on-its-own/</link>
						<dc:creator>kkc</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes me and my wife reminisce about our early memories of playing videogames. We indulge in the nostalgic memories of having only one or two games and playing them all over again, even if they were not perfect.</p>
<p>But there is one fundamental difference in our experiences: my wife's mother tongue is German, which is usually one of the default language settings in mainstream games, while I grew up speaking Hungarian, not really understanding English until I was around 15.</p>
<p>There were some early Hungarian games and some language packs on PC, but I only had a "chipped" PlayStation 1. (There was a guy in a nearby socialist block house running a "PS STORE", he had some legit games on the shelves, but his main business was selling pirated copies from under the counter.)</p>
<p>I remember trying to figure out in the Phantom Menace what I was supposed to do using a trusty old dictionary, but I was mostly just clicking through all the dialogue options and hoping for the best. (It was an action game with some inconsequential <a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/PrequelMemes/comments/6v2dmk/the_phantom_menace_video_game_is_a_goldmine_for/#lightbox">dialogue options</a>, so it didn't really matter.)</p>
<p>Other games like Final Fantasy or Metal Gear Solid were an insurmountable obstacle, my early experience with latter was spending 10+ hours in the hangar area killing guards and triggering alarms. (I have played it through a couple of months ago, and it was a blast!)</p>
<p>There are still some English words which I pronounce internally the way when I was 7. For example I had no idea what an "exhaustion" was, but that was the cheapest part you could buy in Gran Turismo. I still read it as "ex - haus - tsee - on" occasionally.</p>
<p>But I usually preferred straightforward games where you could ignore the story  entirely (I still have no idea wtf was going on in Ace Combat 3) or where you could rely on third party lore (this was mainly Harry Potter).</p>
<p>After a while I was at least familiar with various menu options and basic UI stuff, such as "Loading" (which I read as "low - ad - ing" -- it approximately means "the horse gives a t-shirt" in Hungarian and it always made me smile as a child), or "Continue" ("Coon - teen - nu - eh").</p>
<p>My future children will grew up being fluent in German, and I cannot wait to tell them how "back in my days" games were fun despite not understanding them. OK BOOMER.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 05:41:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878096</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Citizens United</title>
			<link>http://www.unfogged.com/archives/week_2025_11_23.html#019069</link>
						<dc:creator>Heebie-Geebie</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>1. Does <a href="https://robertreich.substack.com/p/how-to-get-rid-of-citizens-united?r=2nztnd&amp;utm_medium=ios&amp;triedRedirect=true">Robert Reich's plan to get rid of CU</a> work? It feels a little like one weird trick:</p>

<blockquote>Here's the thing: Individual states -- either through their legislators or their citizens wielding ballot initiatives -- have the authority to limit corporate political activity and dark money spending, because they determine what powers corporations have.</blockquote>
...
<blockquote>Importantly, a state that no longer grants its corporations the power to spend in elections also denies that power to corporations chartered in the other 49 states, if they wish to do business in that state.</blockquote>

<blockquote>All a state would need to do is enact a law with a provision something like this:
</blockquote>
<blockquote>"Every corporation operating under the laws of this state has all the corporate powers it held previously, except that nothing in this statute grants or recognizes any power to engage in election activity or ballot-issue activity."</blockquote>

<p>Is this the Moops invading Spain? Or is this real?</p>

<p>2. Conventional progressives are horrified over CU, but I have definitely been chided here for misunderestimating the amount of donor money that saturated the market pre-CU.  </p>

<p>Fifteen years later, what do you all think? Is reversing CU (or reining in corporate spending in some other way) a necessary component of righting the ship? </p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 05:38:04 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878095</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Karen</title>
			<link>https://manuelmoreale.com/interview/karen</link>
						<dc:creator>hello@manuelmoreale.com (Manuel Moreale)</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>This week on the People and Blogs series we have an interview with Karen, whose blog can be found at <a href="https://chronosaur.us/">chronosaur.us</a>.</p>
        <p>Tired of RSS? <a href="https://manuelmoreale.com/interview/karen">Read this in your browser</a> or <a href="https://buttondown.com/peopleandblogs">sign up for the newsletter</a>.</p>
        <p>The People and Blogs series is supported by <a href="https://kemper.fyi/">Jonathan Kemper</a> and the other 126 members of my <em>"One a Month"</em> club.</p>
        <p>If you enjoy P&amp;B, <a href="https://ko-fi.com/manuelmoreale">consider becoming one</a> for as little as 1 dollar a month.</p>
        <hr>
        <h2>Let's start from the basics: can you introduce yourself?</h2>
<p>Hello! My name is Karen. I work in IT support for a large company’s legal department, and am currently working on my Bachelors in Cybersecurity and Information Assurance.</p>
<p>I live near New Orleans, Louisiana, with my husband and two dogs - Daisy, A Pembroke Welsh Corgi, and Mia, a Chihuahua. Daisy is The Most Serious Corgi ever (tm), and Mia has the personality of an old lady who chain smokes, plays Bingo every week at the rec center, and still records her soap operas on a VHS daily. My husband is an avid maker (woodworking and 3D printing, mostly), video gamer, and has an extensive collection of board games that takes up the entire back wall of our livingroom.</p>
<p>As for me, outside of work, I’m a huge camera nerd and photographer. I love film photography, and recently learned how to develop my own negatives at home! I also do digital - I will never turn my nose up at one versus the other. I’ve always been into assorted fandoms, and used to volunteer at local sci-fi/fantasy/comic conventions up to a few years ago. I got into K-Pop back in 2022, and am now an active participant in the local New Orleans fan community, providing Instax photo booth services for events. I’ve also hosted K-Pop events here in NOLA as well. My ult K-Pop group is ATEEZ, but I’m a proud multi fan and listen to whatever groups or music catch my attention, including Stray Kids, SHINee, and Mamamoo. I also love 80s and 90s alternative, mainly Depeche Mode, Nine Inch Nails, and Garbage.</p>
<p>And yes, I may be named Karen but I refuse to BE a “Karen”. I don’t get upset when people use the term, I find it hilarious.</p>
<h2>What's the story behind your blog?</h2>
<p>So I have been blogging off and on since 2001 or so - back when they were still called “weblogs” and “online journals”. Originally, I was using LiveJournal, but even with a paid account, I wanted to learn more customization and make a site that was truly my own. My husband - then boyfriend - had their own server, and gave me some space on it. I started out creating sites in Microsoft Frontpage and Dreamweaver (BEFORE Adobe owned them!), and moved to using <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greymatter_(software)">Greymatter</a> blog software, which I loved and miss dearly.</p>
<p>I moved to Wordpress in - 2004 maybe? - and used that for all my personal sites until 2024. I’d been reading more and more about the Indieweb for a while and found <a href="https://bearblog.dev/">Bear</a>, and I loved the simplicity.</p>
<p>I’ve had sites ranging from a basic daily online journal, to a fashion blog, to a food blog, to a K-Pop and fandom-centric blog, to what it is today - my online space for everything and anything I like.</p>
<p>I taught myself HTML and CSS in order to customize and create my sites. No classes, no courses, no books, no certifications, just Google and looking at other people’s sites to see what I liked and how they did it. My previous job before this one, I was a web administrator for a local marketing company that built sites using DNN and Wordpress, and I’m proud to say that I got that job and my current one with my self-developed skills and being willing to learn and grow. I would not be where I am today, professionally, if it wasn’t for blogging.</p>
<h2>What does your creative process look like when it comes to blogging?</h2>
<p>I’ll be totally honest - I don’t have a writing process. I get inspiration from random thoughts, seeing things online, wanting to share the day-to-day of my life. I don’t draft or have someone proof read, I just type out what I feel like writing.</p>
<p>When I had blogs focusing on specific things - plus size fashion and K-Pop, respectively - I kept a list of topics and ideas to refer back to when I was stuck for ideas. That was when I was really focused on playing the SEO and search engine algorithm game, though, where I was trying to stick to the “two-three posts a week” rule in an attempt to boost my search engine results. I don’t do that now. I do still have a list of ideas on my phone, but it’s nothing I am feeling FORCED to stick to. It’s more along the lines of that I had an idea while I was out, and wanted to note it so I don’t forget. Memory is a fickle thing in your late 40s, LOL.</p>
<h2>Do you have an ideal creative environment? Also do you believe the physical space influences your creativity?</h2>
<p>My space absolutely influences my mindset for writing. I prefer to write in the early morning, because my brain operates best then. (I know I am an exception to the rule by being an early bird.) I love weekend mornings when I can get up really early and settle into my recliner with my laptop and coffee, and just listen to some lofi music and just feel topics and ideas out. I also made my office/guest bedroom into a cozy little space, with a daybed full of soft blankets and fluffy pillows and cushions, and a lap desk.</p>
<p>In all honesty, my preferred location to write is at a coffeeshop first thing in the morning. I love sitting tucked in a booth with a coffee and muffin, headphones on and listening to music, when the sun is just on the cusp of rising and the shop is still a little too chilly. That’s when the creative ideas light up the brightest and the synapses are firing on all cylinders.</p>
<h2>A question for the techie readers: can you run us through your tech stack?</h2>
<p>Currently, my site is hosted on <a href="https://bearblog.dev/">Bear</a>.</p>
<p>I used to be a self-hosted Wordpress devotee, but in mid-late 2024, I got really tired of the bloat that the apps had become. In order to use it efficiently for me, I had to install entirely too many plugins to make it “simpler”. (Shout-out to the Indieweb Wordpress team, though - they work so hard on those plugins!) Of course, the more plugins you have, the less secure your site…</p>
<p>My domain is registered through <a href="https://hostinger.com/">Hostinger</a>.</p>
<p>To write my posts, I use Bear Markdown Notes. I heard about this program after seeing a few others talking about using it for drafts, notes, etc.</p>
<h2>Given your experience, if you were to start a blog today, would you do anything differently?</h2>
<p>I honestly don’t think I’d change much! I really love using Bear Blog. It reminds me of the very old school LiveJournal days, or when I used Greymatter. It takes me back to the web being simpler, more straightforward, more fun. I also like Bear’s <a href="https://herman.bearblog.dev/manifesto/">manifesto</a>, and that he built the service for <a href="https://herman.bearblog.dev/building-software-to-last-forever/">longevity</a>.</p>
<p>I would probably structure my site differently, especially after seeing some personal sites set up with more of a “digital garden” format. I will eventually adjust my site at some point, but for now, I’m fine with it. (That and between school and work, it’s kind of low on the priority list.)</p>
<h2>Financial question since the Web is obsessed with money: how much does it cost to run your blog? Is it just a cost, or does it generate some revenue? And what's your position on people monetising personal blogs?</h2>
<p>I purchased a lifetime subscription to Bear after a week of using it, which ran around $200 - I don’t remember exactly. I knew that I was going to be using the service for a while and thought I should invest in a place that I believed in. My Hostinger domain renewals run around $8.99 annually.</p>
<p>My blog is just my personal site - I don’t generate any revenue or monetise in any way.</p>
<p>I don’t mind when people monetize their site - it’s their site and they can do what they choose. As long as it’s not invading others’ privacy or harmful, I have absolutely no issue. Make that money however you like.</p>
<h2>Time for some recommendations: any blog you think is worth checking out? And also, who do you think I should be interviewing next?</h2>
<p>Ooooh I have three really good suggestions for both checking out and interviewing!</p>
<p><a href="https://binarydigit.city/">Binary Digit</a> - B is kind of an influence for me to play with my site again. They have just this super cool and early 2000s vibe and style that I really love. Their site reminds me of me when I first started blogging, when I was learning new things and implementing what I thought was cool on my site, joining fanlistings, making new online friends.</p>
<p><a href="https://kevinspencer.org/posts/">Kevin Spencer</a> - I love Kevin’s writing and especially his photography. Not only that, he has fantastic taste in music. I’ve left many a comment on his site about 80s and 90s synthpop and industrial music.</p>
<p><a href="https://sylvia.bearblog.dev/">A Parenthetical Departure</a> - Sylvia was one of the first sites I started reading when I started looking up info on Bear Blog. They are EXTREMELY talented and have an excellent knack for playing with design, and showing others how it works.</p>
<h2>Final question: is there anything you want to share with us?</h2>
<p>One of my side projects is <a href="https://burnlikeafla.me/">Burn Like A Flame</a>, which is my local K-pop and fandom photography site. I actualy just started a project there that is more than slightly based on People and Blogs - <a href="https://burnlikeafla.me/the-fandom-story-project/">The Fandom Story Project</a>. I’m interviewing local fans to talk about what they love and what their feelings are on fandom culture now, and I’m accompanying that with a photoshoot with that person. It’s a way to introduce people to each other within the community.</p>
<p>Two of my favorite YouTube channels that I have recently been watching are focused on fashion discussion and history - <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@BlissFoster">Bliss Foster</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@understitchYT">understitch,</a>. If you like learning and listening to information on fashion, I highly recommend these creators.</p>
<p>I know a TON of people have now seen K-Pop Demon Hunters (which I love, and the movie has a great message for not only kids, but adults). If you’ve seen this and are interested in getting into K-Pop, I suggest checking out my favorite group, ATEEZ. If you think that most K-Pop is all chirpy bubbly cutesy songs, let me suggest two by this group that aren’t what you’d expect: <a href="https://youtu.be/2HcVZm_4qAI?si=VYVqzgPVzEbj_vXT">Guerrilla</a> and <a href="https://youtu.be/80WvAnsHOdM?si=oCV0-oqaBXBrQ2nl">Turbulence</a>. I strongly suggesting watching without the translations, and then watching again with them. Their lyrics are the thing that really drew me into this group, and had me learning more about the deeper meaning behind a lot of K-Pop songs.</p>
<p>And finally, THANK YOU to Manu for People and Blogs! I always find some really great new sites to check out after reading these interviews, and I am truly honored to be asked to join this list of great bloggers. It’s inspiring me to work harder on my blog and to post more often.</p>        <hr>
        <h3>Keep exploring</h3>
        <p>Now that you're done reading the interview, <a href="https://chronosaur.us/">go check the blog</a> and <a href="https://chronosaur.us/feed/">subscribe to the RSS feed</a>.</p>
        <p>If you're looking for more content, go read one of the previous <a href="https://peopleandblogs.com/">117 interviews</a>.</p>
        <p>Make sure to also say thank you to <a href="https://doug.pub/">Doug Jones</a> and the other 126 supporters for making this series possible.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878094</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>I got a new computer recently and I think I configured NVM, NPM, and all th…</title>
			<link>https://www.nicksimson.com//notes/2025-11-28-rsvp-indieweb-black-friday.html</link>
						<description><![CDATA[<p>I got a new computer recently and I <em>think</em> I configured NVM, NPM, and all the dependencies this site runs on correctly so I can update my website from this new machine.</p>
<p>I RSVP’d to an IndieWeb event today: <a href="https://events.indieweb.org/2025/11/indieweb-black-friday-create-day-build-don-t-buy-C044CcYllKyt">IndieWeb Black Friday Create Day — Build Don’t Buy</a>. A clever bit of holiday season counter-programming. I’ll see if I can work on the site a bit on my day off today.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:49:56 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878093</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Belfast TradFest back in July.</title>
			<link>https://adactio.com/notes/22275</link>
						<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://adactio.com/images/uploaded/22275/small.jpg" alt="Belfast TradFest back in July.">
<p>Belfast TradFest back in July.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 04:37:06 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764351500878092</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
