<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >
	<channel>
		<title> | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>http://192.168.1.206/FreshRSS/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of  | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 11:50:10 -0700</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 18:50:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="/i/?a=rss&amp;state=2" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
				<item>
			<title>When writing writes itself</title>
			<link>https://robertbirming.com/writing-writes/</link>
						<dc:creator>birming</dc:creator>
			<category>reflections</category>
			<category>writing</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>I’m in the process of moving old posts into this blog. It’s honestly one of the most boring things I’ve ever done. Sigh.</p>
<p>I felt I needed a break.</p>
<p>So, what to do? Maybe watch a movie or read a book. Or take a walk while listening to a podcast.</p>
<p>Great activities that I enjoy. But there’s one I love even more, and that’s writing. I find it so relaxing and rewarding.</p>
<p>Just a blank page and a quiet mind. Then bits and pieces slowly start falling into place. It might begin with only a couple of words, or sometimes just a feeling, a hunch, an itch.</p>
<p>Something is coming to life. You’re not even sure what it is yet, but the words, sentences, and paragraphs start piling up. Slowly revealing a story you didn’t even realize was waiting to be written.</p>
<p>But there it is, seemingly born out of nothing. You look at it, read it, read it again, and think to yourself:</p>
<p>I’m gonna call it “When writing writes itself”.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 08:42:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765128719244318</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Tyranny Of Social Benchmarks</title>
			<link>https://nikhil.bearblog.dev/the-tyranny-of-social-benchmarks/</link>
						<dc:creator>nikhil</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>We cannot measure our progress unless we have a reference point. Progress is, after all, a transition from one state to another. But the only way to define that earlier state is by anchoring it to something fixed. A reliable way to measure progress is through time spent and milestones achieved. What were you doing five years ago compared to today? How do you stand relative to your peers in society? Social benchmarks therefore function as reference points against which we evaluate all forms of progress.</p>
<p>From a societal perspective, it is efficient to measure a community’s past condition against its present one. If the change is positive, we call it progress. But what happens when we start applying this same benchmark to our own lives? Our sense of progress becomes distorted. This can easily breed an enduring sense of inadequacy. It can trigger moral crises in people who suddenly realise that certain goals are no longer attainable for them.</p>
<p>The problem with measuring everyone by the same yardstick is that it produces the same kind of person. We risk becoming identical—sharing the same biases, the same ideology, the same interests, the same frustrations. How can that lead society forward? The point of progress is evolution and elevation, but if all remain the same, there is no evolution—only stagnation and eventual collapse.</p>
<p>People fall into severe mental crises, develop illnesses, and despair because they believe they “missed the boat” and ruined their lives. They believe this because they were handed a social benchmark against which to measure themselves. And by that benchmark, failure becomes a crime. That is how creativity and genius are extinguished. Perhaps a true social benchmark should not be <em>social</em> at all if we genuinely aim for progress. It should be individual. When each individual progresses, society progresses alongside them.</p>
<p>And an individual can progress only when they evolve, which they cannot do unless they revise their reference point—their personal benchmark. People must use their own lives as a valid frame of comparison. What were they doing a few years ago? Have they moved beyond that point? If the movement is forward, it is progress. What they aspired to and what they achieved should be the only true metric.</p>
<p>The beauty of this approach is that it does not criminalise failure; it nurtures it. Missing the benchmark does not trouble you because it is your benchmark. You can begin again today and meet yourself five years later. You are still enforcing feedback, still carrying the burden of progress, but this time it is not imposed by society. It is aligned with your own pace, your own trajectory—making it truly yours and genuinely relevant.</p>
<p>The goal was never to abandon progress or descend into nihilism, but to recalibrate the north star. The benchmarks must be your own, not bestowed upon you by society. The true aim is to remain in motion; the speed is secondary.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 07:42:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765128719244316</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pascale De Backer Likes Playing On The Game Gear</title>
			<link>https://brainbaking.com/post/2025/12/pascale-de-backer-likes-the-game-gear/</link>
						<dc:creator>Wouter Groeneveld</dc:creator>
			<category>game gear</category>
			<category>flemish culture</category>
			<category>tv shows</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>After pointing out yesterday that <a href="https://brainbaking.com/post/2025/12/sinterklaas-likes-playing-on-the-game-boy/">Sinterklaas likes the Game Boy</a>, I feel I need to make it up to Sega. It wasn’t that difficult to come up with a counterargument that’s also part of the <a href="https://brainbaking.com/tags/flemish-culture">Flemish canon</a>. In <em>F.C. De Kampioenen</em> (“The Champions”), a long running Flemish sitcom about misunderstandings and misadventures of a lowly ranked football team, Pascale De Backer—the ex-wife of the ex-trainer of the club that runs the café that is not of René<sup data-sanitized-id="fnref:1"><a href="https://brainbaking.com/post/2025/12/pascale-de-backer-likes-the-game-gear/#fn:1" role="doc-noteref" data-sanitized-class="footnote-ref">1</a></sup>—has been pictured playing the Game Gear:</p>
<p>
<figure><a href="https://brainbaking.com/post/2025/12/pascale-de-backer-likes-the-game-gear/pascale.jpg" data-sanitized-class="lbox">
		<img src="https://brainbaking.com/post/2025/12/pascale-de-backer-likes-the-game-gear/pascale.jpg" title="Pascale playing Sonic on the Game Gear. Copyright VRT 2001." data-pagefind-index-attrs="title">
	</a>
	
		<figcaption>Pascale playing Sonic on the Game Gear. Copyright VRT 2001.</figcaption></figure>
</p>
<p>Pascale is playing the mobile version of Sonic in season 12, episode 2 called <em>Stoelendans</em> (dancing chairs I guess?). For exactly ten seconds, we hear the iconic theme song of Sonic playing and the <em>ploing</em> jumping sound as she presses the buttons, before throwing the thing aside and calling her daughter. She’s alone that evening and having a hard time adjusting after her daughter and son-in-law just moved out. Bieke, her daughter, is fed up with Pascale constant checking up on her.</p>
<p>This is different from Sinterklaas playing the Game Boy for a few key reasons. First, Sinterklaas is having fun, while Pascale is just seeking a distraction and doesn’t know what to do with herself. Second, Sinterklaas, being the saint of the children, is an authority when it comes to toys, while Pascale is just a lonely café owner. Yet <em>De Kampioenen</em>, with more than twenty seasons, is one of the most watched Flemish TV shows of all time, and loved by virtually everyone—even the ones who saw the unfortunate downfall after season eight or so.</p>
<p>The strangest part of this very short Game Gear appearance is that episode 2 of season 12 originally aired in 2001—the launch year of the Game Boy Advance. The GBA got to us Europeans in the late summer of 2001, and season 2 aired the 15th December 2001. Why didn’t they have Pascale play <em>Mario Advance</em>?</p>
<p>At first, I couldn’t trace the exact episode in which the above scene takes place. Being the handheld game nerd that I am, I remembered the Game Gear scene, but I misremembered the period. I went looking for it in seasons five, six, and seven because my mind reconstructed the scene as a time period correct one, when the Game Gear was in full motion. Considered it ever was in motion at all. Dang it, I did it again, sorry Sega.</p>
<p>Perhaps the crew asked Danni Heylen who portrayed Pascale to bring a handheld device. “We’re gonna do a scene in which you’re lonely and bored, bring an electronic device to play on the couch so our viewers can place the feeling”. If she brought a Game Boy—any Game Boy would do here—she certainly wouldn’t be bored. Ah dang it, again!?</p>
<p>The Game Gear was discontinued in 1997, only six years after its initial release. Four years later, it pops up in <em>F.C. De Kampioenen</em>. It turns out to be next to impossible to find local historical sales data to see when the popularity of the Game Gear dipped into obscureness here in Belgium. I do remember Sega being stronger than initially suspected: we had a Mega Drive instead of a SNES and a buddy did own the Game Gear. Me and my sisters didn’t: we went the Game Boy—and later, Color—route.</p>
<p>The suspected reasons for that? A couple:</p>
<ul>
<li>The overabundance of Game Boy games available back then (on school playgrounds, during vacation trips, in shops, …)</li>
<li>The GB’s 4 batteries lasted for 20 hours. The GG’s 6 batteries for nearly 4.</li>
<li>The GG initially sold for <code>$150</code>—that’s almost <code>€295</code> nowadays. The GB? The Pocket revision released in 1996 started at <code>$70</code>. That’s less than half the price!</li>
<li>Who are you going to Link Cable Play <em>Tetris</em> and <em>Mortal Kombat</em> with if you were the poor soul with rich parents that got you a Game Gear for Christmas?</li>
</ul>
<p>Yes, it’s got colours, but that’s basically it. Technically, the Game Gear was essentially a shrunken down Sega Master System, which was impressive considering the Game Boy couldn’t even emulate the NES until the 1998 Color revision came by. So why does Pascale like hers so much? The still image I captured might evoke “liking” but the scene in motion does not do a very good job at convincing potential buyers. For that, we’ll need Sinterklaas.</p>
<p><em>Mijn Gedacht</em>.</p>
<div role="doc-endnotes" data-sanitized-class="footnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li data-sanitized-id="fn:1">
<p>For the international reader enticed by this piece of excellent writing, here’s one of my favourite episodes of the TV show <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a0Db_nUQElI">called Doping</a> available on YouTube. <a href="https://brainbaking.com/post/2025/12/pascale-de-backer-likes-the-game-gear/#fnref:1" role="doc-backlink" data-sanitized-class="footnote-backref">↩︎</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>


          
          <p>
            Related topics: /
                  <a href="https://brainbaking.com/tags/game-gear">game gear</a> /
                  <a href="https://brainbaking.com/tags/flemish-culture">flemish culture</a> /
                  <a href="https://brainbaking.com/tags/tv-shows">tv shows</a> /
          </p>
          
          <p>
            By <a href="https://brainbaking.com/about">Wouter Groeneveld</a> on 7 December 2025. 
            <a href="mailto:hifromrss@brainbaking.com?subject=Re:%20Pascale%20De%20Backer%20Likes%20Playing%20On%20The%20Game%20Gear">Reply via email</a>.
          </p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 06:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765128719244314</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Did Anyone Ever Teach You How to Pray? How the Ancient Church Shows Us the Way</title>
			<link>https://kennethbwrites.substack.com/p/did-anyone-ever-teach-you-how-to</link>
						<dc:creator>Kenneth B.</dc:creator>
			<media:content url="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/$s_!OCjY!,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F8dfffb9b-d398-472c-929b-6891dfcf2349_8686x5791.heic" type="image/jpeg"></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[<div data-sanitized-class="captioned-image-container"><figure><a href="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/%24s_!OCjY!,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F8dfffb9b-d398-472c-929b-6891dfcf2349_8686x5791.heic" data-component-name="Image2ToDOM" data-sanitized-class="image-link image2 is-viewable-img"><div data-sanitized-class="image2-inset"><picture><source type="image/webp"><img src="https://substackcdn.com/image/fetch/%24s_!OCjY!,w_1456,c_limit,f_auto,q_auto:good,fl_progressive:steep/https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F8dfffb9b-d398-472c-929b-6891dfcf2349_8686x5791.heic" width="1456" height="971" data-attrs='{"src":"https://substack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com/public/images/8dfffb9b-d398-472c-929b-6891dfcf2349_8686x5791.heic","srcNoWatermark":null,"fullscreen":null,"imageSize":null,"height":971,"width":1456,"resizeWidth":null,"bytes":3734645,"alt":null,"title":null,"type":"image/heic","href":null,"belowTheFold":false,"topImage":true,"internalRedirect":"https://kennethbwrites.substack.com/i/180950471?img=https%3A%2F%2Fsubstack-post-media.s3.amazonaws.com%2Fpublic%2Fimages%2F8dfffb9b-d398-472c-929b-6891dfcf2349_8686x5791.heic","isProcessing":false,"align":null,"offset":false}' alt="" data-sanitized-class="sizing-normal"></picture><div data-sanitized-class="image-link-expand"><div data-sanitized-class="pencraft pc-display-flex pc-gap-8 pc-reset"><button data-sanitized-class="pencraft pc-reset pencraft icon-container restack-image"></button><button data-sanitized-class="pencraft pc-reset pencraft icon-container view-image"></button></div></div></div></a></figure></div><p>When I was young, nobody taught me to pray.</p><p>Growing up in evangelical America in the 1980s, prayer was everywhere and nowhere at the same time. </p><p>People talked about it constantly. Books were written about it. Sermons explained its importance. Testimonies praised its power. Yet the actual practice of prayer had a strange absence, as though it were some instinctive ability that one simply possessed the moment they closed their eyes and bowed their head. This always puzzled me later in life because everything else worth doing requires apprenticeship. Even speaking is learned at the feet of our parents. We hear sounds, imitate them, stumble and experiment until one day we discover we are fluent. Yet prayer, for some reason, was treated as something we were expected to know without teaching, without shaping, without any elder guiding the movements of the heart.</p><p>I do not mean that we never prayed. When it came to formal moments, the evangelical world could pray with the eloquence of Cicero addressing the Roman court. If someone was asked to bless a meal or open a Bible study, they could summon a polished and poetic prayer with no preparation at all. But in daily life, during the mornings and evenings and quiet spaces between tasks, I almost never saw anyone pray. Certainly not in the way Saint Paul describes when he urges Christians to pray without ceasing. None of my friends or I knew a single adult who woke early every morning without fail, and prayed even ten minutes a day, let alone for half an hour or more. Reading Scripture was common. Many of our parents faithfully rose each morning to read the Bible. Yet prayer existed in a different category. It was mysterious and vaguely sentimental, admired but not practiced.</p><p>At age fifteen I began having coffee every Saturday morning with a spiritual father. His name was Pastor Pohly, a full-time dairy farmer and part-time Methodist minister. He was the first person I ever met whose life of prayer was not theoretical or occasional but woven into the very structure of his days. He woke every morning at four to tend his cows, and as he worked he prayed for his family, his congregation and the world. He sang the Psalms in the dark before dawn and recited hymns as naturally as breathing. His prayers flowed over the farmyard like a quiet river. Seven days a week he kept this rhythm, year after year. When I met him he was in his early sixties, and the Saturday mornings we spent together over coffee and prayer continued for nineteen years until the day he died. In those hours he introduced me to a life shaped by prayer rather than by mood or circumstance. He prayed as though prayer were not an activity but a way of inhabiting the world.</p><p>Being around him awakened something in me, a sense that prayer had a shape and a texture that could be learned. I began to suspect that the Christian life had a pattern older and deeper than the spontaneous habits I had grown up with, and that others had walked this road long before I ever knew it existed. That suspicion ripened in time, leading me to the Book of Common Prayer. Through it I discovered the ancient prayers of the Church. Suddenly prayer was not a feeling or an impulse. It was something learned and patterned, something shaped by those who came before us. Later when I encountered the Jesus Prayer, Saint Paul’s words about prayer without ceasing finally made sense. Those words no longer sounded like an impossible ideal. They became an invitation into another way of living.</p><p>And then there were the Psalms.</p><p>Even as a child I loved them. I could not explain why. Whenever I opened the Psalter I felt as though I had entered a secret conversation. The words felt older than the world, full of brightness and alarm and comfort. They were not prayers I invented. They were prayers I received. Yet they felt more like my own prayers than anything I could have created. It was as though I had stumbled into the prayers of angels.</p><p>Still, even then, I sensed a quiet message in the evangelical environment around me. People said that real prayer was spontaneous and authentic and came straight from the heart. Reading a prayer was considered a lesser form of devotion. The Psalms were Scripture, so it was acceptable to read them, but to pray them felt suspicious to many of the adults in my world. The idea that written prayers could form the soul was almost unheard of.</p><p>Looking back, this belief is not merely unusual. It is modern and unbiblical. A life of prayer that consists only of spontaneous moments is historically thin and spiritually fragile. Scripture itself teaches us to pray through the words God has given. The ancient Church hands down prayers that shape us. Our spontaneous prayers are meant to flow out of this inherited life. Anything else resembles the errors of the early innovators and spiritual experimenters who valued novelty over the wisdom of the apostles.</p><p>This morning as I read the Philokalia I came across a short and luminous exchange that captures the beauty of this truth. It concerns Abba Philimon, and the text reads as follows:</p><p>“‘Why, father, do you find more joy in the psalms than in any other part of divine Scripture? And why, when quietly chanting them, do you say the words as though you were speaking with someone?’ And Abba Philimon replied: ‘My son, God has impressed the power of the psalms on my poor soul as He did on the soul of the prophet David. I cannot be separated from the sweetness of the visions about which they speak: they embrace all Scripture.’ He confessed these things with great humility, after being much pressed, and then only for the benefit of the questioner.”</p><p>His answer is simple to the point of embarrassment, as though someone asked him why he loved breathing. </p><p>The Psalms were not merely verses to him. They were a presence. They held all of Scripture within them. They taught the soul to repent, to rejoice, to lament and to hope. They sketched the inner landscape of faith’s mountains and deserts. They were the school where he had learned to speak with God.</p><p>Reading Abba Philimon reminded me how I learned to pray. At first I simply repeated the words of the Church, just as a child repeats the words of his parents. I did not understand everything, but the words were wiser than I was. Slowly they began to form me. As the Psalms settled into my heart, I found that even my spontaneous prayers had changed. The language of David shaped the language of my soul. The words of repentance, amazement and hope became the grammar of my inner life.</p><p>Perhaps that is what Abba Philimon meant when he said the Psalms embrace all Scripture. They do not merely summarize it. They give us the posture in which Scripture can be received. They do not only teach us what to say. They teach us how to be.</p><p>Many Christians feel anxiety about prayer because they believe they must invent prayer on their own each time. But prayer is not self-expression. It is communion. And communion begins with receiving what has been given. When a child learns to speak, she begins with imitation. In imitation she grows in understanding. In understanding she begins to love.</p><p>Prayer works the same way.</p><p>If the Psalms and the ancient prayers of the Church feel foreign to us, perhaps it is because we have not yet lived inside them long enough. Abba Philimon reminds us that prayer is not a technique or a talent. It is a way of being with God. And like all ways of being, it must be learned. The Psalms are where we learn it.<br><br>~Kenneth </p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 05:48:34 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765128719244313</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Inside you are two wolves</title>
			<link>https://www.maaikebrinkhof.nl/inside-you-are-two-wolves/</link>
						<dc:creator>Maaike Brinkhof</dc:creator>
			<category>IT</category>
			<media:content url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1515253475595-2aa42d668c8c?crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;fit=max&amp;fm=jpg&amp;ixid=M3wxMTc3M3wwfDF8c2VhcmNofDd8fHdvbHZlc3xlbnwwfHx8fDE3NjUxMDIyMjV8MA&amp;ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=80&amp;w=2000" medium="image"></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[<img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1515253475595-2aa42d668c8c?crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;fit=max&amp;fm=jpg&amp;ixid=M3wxMTc3M3wwfDF8c2VhcmNofDd8fHdvbHZlc3xlbnwwfHx8fDE3NjUxMDIyMjV8MA&amp;ixlib=rb-4.1.0&amp;q=80&amp;w=2000" alt="Inside you are two wolves"><p>Let me jump on a trend for once, yeah? For some reason, I'm seeing the "two wolves" meme making a comeback over on Mastodon, which is admittedly pretty niche as far as social media platforms go. But it made me think!</p><p>It made me realise that software testers live with these two wolves inside them, and I think one of the painful realities of being in this profession is that you can never resolve these two wolves. </p><p>Working as a tester means living with permanent cognitive dissonance. Let me explain.</p><p>Developers are hired to <strong>build</strong> the product, but as a tester, you are hired to <strong>critique</strong> the product. To find problems. </p><figure data-sanitized-class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://www.maaikebrinkhof.nl/content/images/2025/12/2-wolves.jpg" alt="Inside you are two wolves" width="500" height="511" data-sanitized-class="kg-image"></figure><p>However, when your main task is to find problems, that might not feel so nice. It can feel negative (some people at work call testers negative), <strong>like you are not truly working on the product because you are not building like a developer.</strong></p><p>What if you also want to feel like you are part of building the product, like the developers? Well, you are! But not in the way that might <em>feel</em> like you are. </p><p><strong>Testers find problems because we want to make the product better.</strong> We do this in a risk based manner, we don't go out and critique the product just for the heck of it. This is a very important part of creating good software! </p><p>Important business decisions can be made based on the problems that testing has uncovered, and this is an indispensable step in making good software. </p><p>But for some reason, many testers feel uncomfortable when they're "only" finding problems, and thus branch out into other tasks in software development, thereby muddying their value as a tester. Like peanut butter that you spread too thin over a large slice of bread. </p><p>For some reason, the industry encourages this behaviour. Being "only" a tester is widely looked down upon, like it's a second rate job that anyone can do. Testing is dead, testers aren't needed, bla bla bla. I've heard it all. </p><p>I've written about this before, but I've also gone through this cycle of self-doubt. And, I've come out of the other side, fully confident that I can be very valuable to any software project in the tester role. </p><figure data-sanitized-class="kg-card kg-bookmark-card"><a href="https://www.maaikebrinkhof.nl/why-do-so-many-testers-have-an-identity-crisis/" data-sanitized-class="kg-bookmark-container"><div data-sanitized-class="kg-bookmark-content"><div data-sanitized-class="kg-bookmark-title">Why do so many testers have an identity crisis?</div><div data-sanitized-class="kg-bookmark-description">Why do so many testers think they aren’t enough? That they should be ashamed of their role? That they should be called something different in order to get the respect they desire and deserve? Well, I can venture a guess! Many other people in our work context hold testing</div><div data-sanitized-class="kg-bookmark-metadata"><img src="https://www.maaikebrinkhof.nl/content/images/icon/Maaike--100-x-100-px--3--25.png" alt="Inside you are two wolves" data-sanitized-class="kg-bookmark-icon"><span data-sanitized-class="kg-bookmark-author">Maaike Brinkhof's blog</span><span data-sanitized-class="kg-bookmark-publisher">Maaike Brinkhof</span></div></div><div data-sanitized-class="kg-bookmark-thumbnail"><img src="https://www.maaikebrinkhof.nl/content/images/thumbnail/photo-1617704716344-8d987ac681a4.jpeg" alt="Inside you are two wolves"></div></a></figure><p>If you cannot feel okay with having "finding problems" as your main mission without feeling highly uncomfortable, you should really figure out if the testing profession is the right profession for you. </p><p>Or, try this: fully embrace the tester role and show people what we can do. </p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 03:33:17 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765128719244308</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Took pictures of animals at Whittier Narrows</title>
			<link>https://blog.lauramichet.com/took-pictures-of-animals-at-whittier-narrows/</link>
						<dc:creator>lauram</dc:creator>
			<category>los_angeles</category>
			<category>photography</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Now that I have a new phone, thanks to Dexcom CGMs and diabetes, I went to take pictures of animals with it.</p>
<p>I'd never been to Whittier Narrows Recreation Area before, and I wanted to check it out. It's so nice!!! It was full of people even in the late afternoon and evening, but it's a large enough park that finding some alone space is very easy. Tons of people were fishing. I saw a lot of people feeding the ducks.</p>
<p>When you go to a park to take pictures of animals you're pretty much going to find the same things all over LA: feral mallards, canada geese, coots, fox squirrels, and a bunch of little songbirds. We were not disappointed.</p>
<p>Here are the mallards and the coots:</p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/lauram/img_1486.webp" alt="IMG_1486"></p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/lauram/img_1466.webp" alt="IMG_1466"></p>
<p>We also saw common gallinules. I like how scary their feet and toes are. Coots, too, have crazy looking feet.</p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/lauram/img_1390.webp" alt="IMG_1390"></p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/lauram/img_1310.webp" alt="IMG_1310"></p>
<p>The geese were extremely habituated to the presence of people, to the point where they'd just lock onto you if they noticed you staring and try to intimidate you into giving them food:</p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/lauram/img_1374.webp" alt="IMG_1374"></p>
<p>Same went for the squirrels. They would notice you staring and come right up to you. This is probably not great, but it did allow me some of my only not-so-zoomed-in animal photos of the day.</p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/lauram/img_1417.webp" alt="IMG_1417"></p>
<p>There are a ton of great blue herons at the park as well. I had to zoom in pretty hardcore to get pictures of all of them. Here is a blurry heron with rim lighting:</p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/lauram/img_1276.webp" alt="IMG_1276"></p>
<p>I was jumping from an iPhone X to a 17. The overall look of the photos the 17 takes is pretty significantly different; there's obviously a lot of new processing taking place that I didn't have on my old phone. The zoomed-in photo modes are really urgently modifying the image to avoid certain kinds of noise and artifacting... but the smeary look it gives you instead is pretty dang odd. I am not sure that I like it.</p>
<p>I have no idea how this will look on your screen, but here's the smeariest duck I got:</p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/lauram/img_1452.webp" alt="IMG_1452"></p>
<p>This is clearly what most people seem to think looks good. Crucially, this stuff does look good, I think, on a phone-sized screen. On my monitor at home is where they start looking really strange. I don't think it's bad, really... It's just very odd to leap forward 8 years in mobile photography trends and so clearly see the changing preferences around this stuff. What "looks good" in a zoomed-in photo is a lot more subjective than you'd think.</p>
<p>Anyway, I highly recommend reading <a href="https://www.portablecity.net/your-cellphone-camera-digital-processing-settings-and-you/">this article</a> from Shel about digital photography, color noise, and mobile phone image processing. This stuff is very interesting!!</p>
<p>And if you live in LA and you've never been to Whittier Narrows, I recommend it! Next time I'll bike here!</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 20:41:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765128719244304</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>On revisiting a foundational text</title>
			<link>https://tracydurnell.com/2025/12/06/on-revisiting-a-foundational-text/</link>
						<dc:creator>Tracy Durnell</dc:creator>
			<category>Comics</category>
			<category>Reflection</category>
			<category>books</category>
			<category>canon</category>
			<category>innovation</category>
			<category>longevity</category>
			<category>media</category>
			<category>reading</category>
			<category>recommendations</category>
			<category>taste</category>
			<category>value</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been re-reading Scott McCloud’s <em>Understanding Comics</em> with the intention of writing about it for the <a href="https://artlung.com/understandingcomics-ibc/">November IndieWeb book club</a>, but I couldn’t think of anything to say about it in time. Then I mentioned this to a friend, and in chatting with them realized I <em>do</em> have thoughts, just not what I was expecting.</p>
<p><span data-sanitized-id="more-32209"></span></p>
<p>I was interested in re-reading <em>Understanding Comics</em> because I first read it in 2005, and had no idea it was referencing Marshall McLuhan’s <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2025/02/21/notes-from-understanding-media/"><em>Understanding Media</em></a>. Now that I’ve read a bit of McLuhan, which I was anti-impressed by, I was curious whether that would influence how I took McCloud’s work.</p>
<p>As I read through, there were certainly parts I’d forgotten, but nothing leapt out as being reinterpreted through my new context. McCloud does an excellent job using the comics medium to explain the media of comics… hence why I thought I had nothing to say about it. “Good book is good” 😂</p>
<p>But my friend asked me why the book stood out to me as a foundational work, and I explained that 2005 was when I started really getting into comics, so it reinforced my interest in graphic storytelling and how I thought about stories. My friend pointed out that it makes sense that I would attach more meaning to this personally highly contextual work, and that I probably bounced off the less contextual McLuhan because I’d already been exposed to many of the ideas in it, better explained using a format that resonated with me, so I was less willing to put up with his bullshit than people encountering the ideas for the first time. This is the same thing we experience when we go back and watch, say, Alien, having seen a dozen derivatives first, and find it nothing to write home about. <strong>Foundational works of the last generation can lose their novelty when their innovations are adopted into the medium or genre.</strong></p>
<p>I’ve seen advice to “only read things that have lasted”, but <strong>I find <em>new</em> books more compelling in general than old books; they have already built another level upon those past foundations</strong>. I do not think that a book is <em>better</em> simply because it is old and still in print (in fact, I think a lot of older books lose value for a general audience because we lack cultural context, and remain valuable more in the sense of understanding references). <strong>This approach presumes that <em>quality</em> rather than <em>power</em> has been the selection filter over time</strong>, when the biases of publishing and power mean that what was published originally, and what has “lasted”, are <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2020/12/16/where-are-the-women/">heavily dominated by white male Western authors</a>. I’m not saying that what has lasted isn’t good per se, but that quality isn’t the only selection factor.</p>
<p><strong>On a <em>personal</em> scale, time is a filter for <a href="https://ckarchive.com/b/68ueh8hk25687hkq88gqmtzope0kk">what books I remember</a> and how my understanding of works changes over time.</strong> The Ancillary series felt exciting when it came out, but today its ripples have settled into placid water. I rated <em>Binti</em> well when I read it, but on thinking about it more and separating my own opinion from the social pressures of what “we” thought about it, I have come to hate it and would never recommend it. I used to read a lot of productivity books, but <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2023/05/24/assuming-no-change-is-an-option/">my perspective about work</a> <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2025/09/01/imagining-better-work-creating-a-niche-for-myself/">has changed radically</a>, so books I found excellent a decade ago are no longer ones I’d recommend. What’s funny is that when I opened up Goodreads to mark that I was re-reading <em>Understanding Comics</em>, which I today remember as a personally foundational text, I had rated it three stars 😂 <strong>It does mean something when a work still seems valuable and relevant twenty years later — or even more valuable in hindsight than it seemed at first. </strong></p>
<p>Our cultural understanding is that there are books that are capital-G Good — this is the concept behind best of lists and “the canon” of literature. I have a <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2023/08/19/my-reading-philosophy-and-17-reading-guidelines/">much more individualized understanding of quality</a> — <strong>our interpretation of a book and how meaningful it is to us is so dependent on our personal context</strong>. This is why I find it tricky to recommend books to others, because I’m not sure that what sang for me will sing for them. What I find important in a book is not necessarily what you believe to be important in a book, and things that bug me may not phase you, or vice versa.</p>
<aside data-sanitized-class="sidenote">(I’ve noticed lately that <strong>it’s the books I loved I find hardest to review</strong> because I’m not sure whether my particular enthusiasms are shading my view of the whole… but I think I need to be <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2024/04/16/the-vulnerability-of-having-taste/">more confident in expressing my taste</a> 😉)</aside>
<p>But what people are really looking for from a recommendation is both a good experience, a book they will <em>enjoy</em> (and ideally be able to talk about with friends) — and to develop their taste. By asking for a recommendation they are <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2025/08/26/best-sff-published-2020-2024/">trusting my taste</a> enough to influence what direction <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2024/05/09/taste-requires-intentional-attention/">they explore <em>their</em> taste</a> — <strong>I’m never going to know what will become <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2024/07/10/re-15-books-with-the-most-impact/">a foundational work</a> for someone else, but I can <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2023/05/26/nudging-people-towards-overlooked-books-with-inspired-recommendations/">steer them towards books</a> that I think are <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2024/10/08/agency-in-reading/">more likely to be than others</a></strong>, books that I think are doing interesting things.</p>
<p>All that to say, <em>Understanding Comics</em> is very probably worth your time if you are at all interested in media or storytelling.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Related reading:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.personalcanon.com/p/no-one-told-me-about-proust">no one told me about proust</a> by Celine Nguyen</p>
<p><a href="https://gardenscenery.net/p/on-being-interested-in-stuff-almost">On Being Interested in Stuff Almost No One is Interested in</a> by david c. porter</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 17:20:08 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765128719244303</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Pointless… No Notes Taken</title>
			<link>https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/2025/12/06/pointless-no-notes-taken/</link>
						<dc:creator>Musings from a Tangled Mind</dc:creator>
			<category>Everyday Musings</category>
			<category>blogging</category>
			<category>musings</category>
			<category>observations</category>
			<category>writing</category>
			<media:content url="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/31ec7a2e33056eb9b17551f99a60a9ba20d8b41e7681ea12d7fe7911294c5215?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image"><media:title type="html">surojabu11</media:title></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>I own an alarming number of pens for someone who cannot, at any point, locate one that actually works. Every day, I reach for a pen with the same optimism people bring to scratch-off lottery tickets. <em>Maybe today is the day</em>. But it’s not today. It’s never today.</p>
<p>Every time I test one and it doesn’t work, I think, “Ah, well, maybe it’s just tired.” But then again, aren’t we all? We still show up. Pens apparently don’t know about that part. Or they do and simply do not care. Pens are the cats of the office supply world.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, I’m scribbling frantic, invisible zigzags on an old envelope like I’m trying to summon a demon who specializes in ink flow.</p>
<p>Do I throw it away?</p>
<p>No. No, I do not. Instead, I throw it back in pen hospice (aka the junk drawer) so I can reenact this exact same scene again tomorrow, like a very low-budget “Groundhog Day” but with stationery.</p>
<p>This is my life now. A person who needs a pen. Wants a pen. And is somehow surrounded by pens that refuse to do pen things. Don’t tell me the universe doesn’t have a sense of humor. It does. And it’s absolutely killing it.</p>
<p>I just wish I could write that down.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><span>.</span></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 17:00:37 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765128719244302</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
