<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >
	<channel>
		<title> | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>http://192.168.1.206/FreshRSS/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of  | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 04:40:09 -0700</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 11:40:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="/i/?a=rss&amp;state=2" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
				<item>
			<title>Context plumbing</title>
			<link>https://interconnected.org/home/2025/11/28/plumbing</link>
						<description><![CDATA[<div>
<p>These past few weeks I’ve been deep in code and doing what I think about as <strong>context plumbing.</strong></p>
<p>I’ve been building an AI system and that’s what it feels like.</p>
<p>Let me unpack.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Intent</strong></p>
<p>Loosely AI interfaces are about intent and context.</p>
<p>Intent is the user’s goal, big or small, explicit or implicit.</p>
<p>Uniquely for computers, AI can understand intent and respond in a really human way. This is a new capability! Like the user can type <em>"I want to buy a camera"</em> or point at a keylight and subvocalise <em>"I’ve got a call in 20 minutes"</em> or hit a button labeled <em>"remove clouds"</em> and <em>job done.</em></p>
<p>Companies care about this because computers that are closer to intent tend to win.</p>
<p>e.g. the smartphone displaced the desktop. On a phone, you see something and you then you touch it directly. With a desktop that intent is mediated through a pointer – you see something on-screen but to interact you tell your arm to move the mouse that moves the pointer. Although it doesn’t seem like much your monkey brain doesn’t like it.</p>
<p>So the same applies to user interfaces in general: picking commands from menus or navigating and collating web pages to plan a holiday or remembering how the control panel on your HVAC works. All of that is bureaucracy. Figuring out the sequence for yourself is <em>burden</em> between intent and result.</p>
<p>Now as an AI company, you can overcome that burden. And you want to be present at the very millisecond and in the very location where the user’s intent - desire - arises. You don’t want the user to have the burden of even taking a phone out of their pocket, or having to formulate an unconscious intent into words. Being closest to the origin of intent will crowd out their competitor companies.</p>
<p>That explains the push for devices like AI-enabled glasses or lanyards or mics or cameras that read your body language.</p>
<p>This is why I think <a href="https://interconnected.org/home/2025/08/29/dwim">the future of interfaces is Do What I Mean</a>: it’s not just a new capability enabled by AI, there’s a whole attentional economics imperative to it.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Context</strong></p>
<p>What makes an AI able to handle intent really, really well is <strong>context.</strong></p>
<p>Sure there’s the world knowledge in the large language model itself, which it gets from vast amounts of training data.</p>
<p>But let’s say an AI agent is taking some user intent and hill-climbing towards that goal using a sequence of tool calls (which is how agents work) then it’s going to do way better when the prompt is filled with all kinds of useful context:</p>
<p>For example:</p>
<ul>
<li>Background knowledge from sources like Wikipedia or Google about what others have done in this situation.</li>
<li>Documentation about the tools the agent will use to satisfy the intent.</li>
<li>The user’s context such as what they’ve done before, the time of day, etc.</li>
<li>Tacit knowledge and <a href="https://interconnected.org/home/2022/05/09/npcs">common ground</a> shared between the user and the AI, i.e. what we’re all assuming we’re here to do.</li>
<li>The shared “whiteboard”: the document we’re working on.</li>
<li>For the agent itself, session context: whether this task is a subtask of a larger goal, what’s worked before and what hasn’t, and so on.</li>
</ul>
<p>This has given rise to the idea of <a href="https://blog.langchain.com/the-rise-of-context-engineering/">context engineering</a> (LangChain blog):</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Context engineering is building dynamic systems to provide the right information and tools in the right format such that the LLM can plausibly accomplish the task.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>btw access to context also explains some behaviour of the big AI companies:</p>
<p>If you want to best answer user intent, then you need to be where the user context is, and that’s why being on a lanyard with an always-on camera is preferred over a regular on-demand camera, and why an AI agent that live in your email archive is going to be more effective than one that can’t. So they really wanna get in there, really cosy up.</p>
<p>(And what’s context at inference time is valuable training data if it’s recorded, so there’s that too.)</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Plumbing?</strong></p>
<p>What’s missing in the idea of context engineering is that context is dynamic. It changes, it is timely.</p>
<p>Context appears at disparate sources, by user activity or changes in the user’s environment: what they’re working on changes, emails appear, documents are edited, it’s no longer sunny outside, the available tools have been updated.</p>
<p>This context is not always where the AI runs (and the AI runs as closer as possible to the point of user intent).</p>
<p>So the job of making an agent run really well is to move the context to where it needs to be.</p>
<p>Essentially copying data out of one database and putting it into another one – but as a continuous process.</p>
<p>You often don’t want your AI agent to have to look up context every single time is it answering intent. That’s slow. If you want an agent to act quickly then you have to plan ahead: build pipes that flows potential context from where it is created to where it’s going to be used.</p>
<p>How can that happen continuously behind the scenes without wasting bandwidth or cycles or the data going stale?</p>
<p>So I’ve been thinking of AI system technical architecture as plumbing the sources and sinks of context.</p>
<hr>
<p>In the old days of Web 2.0 the go-to technical architecture was a “CRUD” app: a web app wrapping a database where you would have entities and operations to create, read, update, and delete (these are also the HTTP verbs).</p>
<p>This was also the user experience, so the user entity would have a webpage (a profile) and the object entity, say a photo, would have a webpage, and then dynamic webpages would index the entities in different ways (a stream or a feed). And you could decompose webapps like this; the technology and the user understanding aligned.</p>
<p>With AI systems, you want the user to have an intuition about what context is available to it. The plumbing of context flow isn’t just what is technically possible or efficient, but what matches user expectation.</p>
<hr>
<p>Anyway.</p>
<p>I am aware this is getting - for you, dear reader - impossibly abstract.</p>
<p>But for me, I’m building the platform I’ve been trying to build for the last 2 years only this time it’s working.</p>
<p>I’m building on Cloudflare and I have context flowing between all kinds of entities and AI agents and sub-agents running where they need to run, and none of feels tangled or confusing because it is plumbed just right.</p>
<p>And I wanted to make a note about that even if I can’t talk specifically, yet, about what it is.</p>

  <hr>



  <p><small>Auto-detected kinda similar posts:</small></p>
  <ul>
  
  <li><small><a href="https://interconnected.org/home/2024/07/19/ai-landscape">Mapping the landscape of gen-AI product user experience</a>
  (19 Jul 2024)</small></li>
  
  <li><small><a href="https://interconnected.org/home/2025/02/11/mcp">Extending AI chat with Model Context Protocol (and why it matters)</a>
  (11 Feb 2025)</small></li>
  
  <li><small><a href="https://interconnected.org/home/2024/03/20/agents">Who will build new search engines for new personal AI agents?</a>
  (20 Mar 2024)</small></li>
  
  <li><small><a href="https://interconnected.org/home/2023/05/04/hunches">The 14 year old boy alignment problem, future shock, and AI microscopes</a>
  (4 May 2023)</small></li>
  
  <li><small><a href="https://interconnected.org/home/2025/05/23/turntaking">Multiplayer AI chat and conversational turn-taking: sharing what we learnt</a>
  (23 May 2025)</small></li>
  
  </ul>

</div>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 11:05:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048410</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Context plumbing</title>
			<link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Nov/29/context-plumbing/#atom-everything</link>
						<dc:creator>Simon Willison</dc:creator>
			<category>definitions</category>
			<category>matt-webb</category>
			<category>ai</category>
			<category>generative-ai</category>
			<category>llms</category>
			<category>ai-agents</category>
			<category>context-engineering</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="https://interconnected.org/home/2025/11/28/plumbing">Context plumbing</a></strong></p>
Matt Webb coins the term <strong>context plumbing</strong> to describe the kind of engineering needed to feed agents the right context at the right time:
<blockquote>
<p>Context appears at disparate sources, by user activity or changes in the user’s environment: what they’re working on changes, emails appear, documents are edited, it’s no longer sunny outside, the available tools have been updated.</p>
<p>This context is not always where the AI runs (and the AI runs as closer as possible to the point of user intent).</p>
<p>So the job of making an agent run really well is to move the context to where it needs to be. [...]</p>
<p>So I’ve been thinking of AI system technical architecture as plumbing the sources and sinks of context.</p>
</blockquote>


    <p>Tags: <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/definitions">definitions</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/matt-webb">matt-webb</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai">ai</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/generative-ai">generative-ai</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llms">llms</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-agents">ai-agents</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/context-engineering">context-engineering</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 04:26:24 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048409</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Experimenting with web design</title>
			<link>https://jamesg.blog/2025/11/29/experimenting-with-web-design/</link>
						<dc:creator>James' Coffee Blog</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Every so often I open developer tools in the web browser and start tinkering with my website. I love experimenting with different design directions, not necessarily in pursuit of a complete design so much as fuelled by a sense of curiosity. <em>What would it look like if I made my web pages wider? What would I do with the extra room? Would this help me create grids of images that would be easier to peruse? What would it look like if my accent colour was on the left side of a page?</em></p><p>I was recently playing around with using more of the space available on desktops to create wider content columns. I experimented with this both in the context of blog posts and then, later, an overall layout that I could use as a template for other pages on my website.</p><p>While the final results are not anywhere on the web, I was proud of what I made so I decided to take the styles from my browser and put them into a local stylesheet. I started developing a layout. I then took a few screenshots of the results as documentation for the project, which I have listed below. Perhaps you will find them interesting!</p><h2 data-sanitized-id="a-blog-post-layout-with-an-image">A blog post layout with an image</h2><p>In this concept, I simplified my navigation bar, moved it to the top of the page, and created a new card component that appears on the far left with metadata about a blog post. I also moved my accent stripe from the top of the web page to the left side.</p><img alt="" src="https://editor.jamesg.blog/content/images/2025/11/content.png" data-sanitized-class="kg-image"><h2 data-sanitized-id="a-blog-post-with-a-wider-image">A blog post with a wider image</h2><p>I then replaced the heading with a serif font which I thought would fit the page better. I also made the image on the page bleed out both the left and right sides of the main content container, and made the text a bit wider, too.</p><img alt="" src="https://editor.jamesg.blog/content/images/2025/11/Screenshot-2025-11-17-at-20.54.49.png" data-sanitized-class="kg-image"><h2 data-sanitized-id="a-page-for-hats">A page for hats</h2><p>I was enjoying the direction I was exploring, so I decided to see what the design would look like on a page that was not for blog posts. I experimented with my <a href="https://editor.jamesg.blog/hats">hats page</a>, creating a four-column grid that escaped the main content container in a similar fashion to the full-bleed image I tried in the blog post.</p><img alt="" src="https://editor.jamesg.blog/content/images/2025/11/hats.png" data-sanitized-class="kg-image"><h2 data-sanitized-id="an-about-page">An about page</h2><p>I liked the single-column content layout and also the floating container I had for tags on my blog post layout. I decided to experiment with a layout that had a single column for content and a column on the right side of the page for images. I experimented with this on an about page.</p><img alt="" src="https://editor.jamesg.blog/content/images/2025/11/about.png" data-sanitized-class="kg-image"><h2 data-sanitized-id="playing">Playing</h2><p>I was going to start this paragraph with "I spent many more hours tinkering" but, in truth, I'm not sure how long I spent playing around. Indeed, I wasn't keeping track. Whether an hour or several passed, it didn't matter for I was having so much fun with the new direction.</p><p>I thought about turning my template into a new layout and design for my website, but I then realised that it would be non-trivial to transfer my new design concepts to my existing website. I had made changes to the HTML, and wanted to change some of my pages to have new elements like the image grid on the about page. It would have been a lot of work to make everything work. And I wanted to play!</p><p>With that said, I did copy what I wrote for the about page I designed onto this website. So now <a href="https://jamesg.blog/about">I have an About page</a>!</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 04:25:27 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048408</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Quoting Wikipedia content guideline</title>
			<link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Nov/29/wikipedia-content-guideline/#atom-everything</link>
						<dc:creator>Simon Willison</dc:creator>
			<category>ai-ethics</category>
			<category>slop</category>
			<category>generative-ai</category>
			<category>wikipedia</category>
			<category>ai</category>
			<category>llms</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<blockquote cite="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Writing_articles_with_large_language_models"><p>Large language models (LLMs) can be useful tools, but they are not good at creating entirely new Wikipedia articles. <strong>Large language models should not be used to generate new Wikipedia articles from scratch</strong>.</p></blockquote>
<p data-sanitized-class="cite">— <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Writing_articles_with_large_language_models">Wikipedia content guideline</a>, promoted to a guideline <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia_talk:Writing_articles_with_large_language_models/Archive_1#RfC">on 24th November 2025</a></p>

    <p>Tags: <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-ethics">ai-ethics</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/slop">slop</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/generative-ai">generative-ai</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/wikipedia">wikipedia</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai">ai</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llms">llms</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:55:30 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048407</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Instagram Mothers - The Offing</title>
			<link>https://theoffingmag.com/wit-tea/the-instagram-mothers/</link>
						<category>short</category>
			<category>story</category>
			<category>instagram</category>
			<category>influencers</category>
			<category>parents</category>
			<category>children</category>
			<category>social</category>
			<category>media</category>
			<category>online</category>
			<category>offline</category>
			<category>sci-fi</category>
			<category>speculative</category>
			<category>fiction</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>A short piece of speculative fiction.</p>

<p><a href="https://adactio.com/links/22277">adactio.com/links/22277</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:32:19 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048406</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>CSS-in-JS: The Great Betrayal of Frontend Sanity - The New Stack</title>
			<link>https://thenewstack.io/css-in-js-the-great-betrayal-of-frontend-sanity/</link>
						<category>css</category>
			<category>js</category>
			<category>javascript</category>
			<category>styling</category>
			<category>complexity</category>
			<category>overengineering</category>
			<category>performance</category>
			<category>frontend</category>
			<category>development</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>This is a spot-on analysis of how CSS-in-JS failed to deliver on any of its promises:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>CSS-in-JS was born out of good intentions — modularity, predictability and componentization. But what we got was complexity disguised as progress.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><a href="https://adactio.com/links/22276">adactio.com/links/22276</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 03:26:30 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048405</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Weeknotes: Nov. 22-28, 2025</title>
			<link>https://tracydurnell.com/2025/11/28/weeknotes-nov-22-28-2025/</link>
						<dc:creator>Tracy Durnell</dc:creator>
			<category>Weeknotes</category>
			<category>personal</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Win of the week:</strong></p>
<p>Had our gross 1988 insulation removed, and new R-49 put in! Probably too much work for one day, four guys were here from 9am to 6:45pm. Cats were terrified of the blower generator noise, and aggravated at being locked in my office with me for nearly 10 hours 😂 Diesel fumes were getting in the house for a while but my husband figured out where they were coming from.</p>
<p>(They were supposed to install an exterior vent for our bathroom fan, but didn’t include a photo of it in their “after” shots so I’m skeptical that happened. They were also meant to clean out, seal and sanitize our garage attic, but again, no photos so I suspect they just cleaned it out… I’ll find out when the office reopens.)</p>
<p><strong>Looking forward to: </strong>rest of the long weekend!</p>
<h2>Stuff I did:</h2>
<ul>
<li>2.5 hours consulting</li>
<li>took Thursday and Friday off for Thanksgiving (got basically nothing done on Tuesday or Wednesday either tbh)</li>
<li>went to Homebrew Website Club: Writer’s Edition</li>
<li>made <a href="https://www.asmallkitcheningenoa.com/chickpeas-and-chard-soup/">soup</a> for lunch on the weekend, I should probably cook midmorning more often</li>
<li>made sourdough pancakes for Sunday brunch</li>
<li>first mammogram, not as painful as I feared — if you’ve ever done a foot water/ice bath that hurts worse</li>
<li>went through draft posts on <a href="https://cascadiainspired.com/">my old blog</a> and pulled over a handful that might be worth finishing, then privately published or deleted most of the rest (in preparation for archiving it as a static site so I don’t have to worry about WordPress updates forever)</li>
<li>woke up hot in the middle of the night to be reminded that when the batteries in the thermostat die, the furnace defaults to running… house should have been 65F but it was 75F — blearily scrambled through my office testing rechargeable batteries, thankfully finally found a pair of AA with some charge so I didn’t have to figure out how to manually turn off the heat pump at 3:30am 😂</li>
</ul>
<p><span data-sanitized-id="more-31803"></span></p>
<h3>Dinners:</h3>
<ul>
<li>Rice + veggie sausage + <a href="https://www.themediterraneandish.com/braised-leeks/#wprm-recipe-container-82755">braised leeks</a> (mostly tasted like the chardonnay I used 😂 I was hoping for sauce but there was very little — could probably make with just broth and a dash of champagne or sherry vinegar — I omitted the sliced lemon) + apple cider</li>
<li>Burrito bowls: leftover rice, air fryer sweet potato (<a href="https://forktospoon.com/mexican-air-fryer-sweet-potatoes/">based on</a>), black beans, avocado + tortilla chips</li>
<li>Thai takeout — peanut noodles with fried tofu + rice + crab rangoon</li>
<li>Leftover Thai</li>
<li>Teriyaki takeout — tofu yakisoba</li>
<li><a href="https://foragersofhappiness.com/sourdough-buttermilk-biscuits/#recipe">Sourdough buttermilk biscuits</a> + mushroom gravy + roasted golden beets with feta and balsamic vinegar + <a href="https://www.daisybeet.com/lemon-garlic-braised-kale/">braised kale</a> 👎 + apple cider (we had meant to make salmon but the pieces I defrosted had alarming discoloration and we decided a vegetarian meal sounded lovely)</li>
<li><del>Basil Pesto Sea Veggie burgers</del> (wow these were so bad I couldn’t eat mine) + tater tots + biscuit with honey</li>
</ul>
<h2>Reading:</h2>
<ul>
<li>Read <em>Violet Thistlewaite is Not a Villain Anymore</em> by Emily Krempholtz 👍and <em>Sunward</em> by William Alexander 👍</li>
<li>DNF’d <em>The Last Gifts of the Universe</em> by Riley August and <em>Surrendering to the Duke</em> by Stevie Sparks</li>
</ul>
<p>If you, like me, get mad that knowledge is locked away at institutions, I just learned that <a href="https://support.jstor.org/hc/en-us/articles/115004760028-How-to-Register-Get-Free-Access-to-Content">you can get a personal JSTOR account</a> and read papers for free! 😃 Why yes I am an “independent researcher”</p>
<h3>Words I looked up:</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hyperstition">hyperstition</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Pretty stuff I saw:</h2>
<ul>
<li>cute <a href="https://hoaglandhandmade.com/product/chunky-beanie-2/">hand-knitted beanie</a></li>
<li>Fumi Nakamura – <a href="https://www.antlerpdx.com/collections/fumi-nakamura-soulseekers/products/fumi-nakamura-metempsychosis">Metempsychosis</a></li>
<li>oversized but not overwhelming <a href="https://studiotoujours.com/collections/earrings/products/modern-hoops-1">dangly earrings</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.teaganwhite.com/blog/2025/11/5/102724">fall bird photos</a> from Teagan White</li>
<li><a href="https://www.portlandleathergoods.com/products/arrowhead-strap?variant=42212111188050">Arrowhead Strap</a> in “bubble pop” pink 🩷</li>
<li><a href="https://mastodon.scot/@MikeBolam/115620788798372837">Sunset over Ardwall Island</a> by Mike Bolam</li>
<li><a href="https://bosie.co/products/fjord-yoke-brushed-fair-isle-womens-lambswool-sweater-midnight-black?variant=55424418546047">lovely brushed wool sweater</a> from Scotland</li>
<li><a href="https://lioninthetrees.com/ceramics">whimsical animal ceramic sculptures</a> by Shirley Jackson — I’m partial to <a href="https://lioninthetrees.com/img/dragon2.jpg">the dragon</a> and <a href="https://lioninthetrees.com/img/littlefoot4.jpg">littlefoot</a></li>
</ul>
<h2>Watching:</h2>
<p>If you have any interest in WWII <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bd8_vO5zrjo">this</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BXjydKPcX60">series of</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WHO6xrSF7Sw">videos</a> (1.5 hours in total) on the battle of Midway was well done (we watched it <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2023/06/30/weeknotes-june-24-30-2023/">a couple years ago</a> but we enjoyed it again 😂)</p>
<h2>Website changes:</h2>
<ul>
<li>finally transferred my webhosting away from HostGator, which I’ve been meaning to do for years — went with KnownHost, who has a local server — they got everything transferred within a few hours, apparently they just moved over my whole cPanel — I also researched archiving a couple retired websites as static sites but decided that’s a project for another day 😉</li>
<li>updated my <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/blogroll/neat-websites/">Neat Websites page</a> — I’m racking up quite a collection there!</li>
</ul>
<h2>Nature notes:</h2>
<ul>
<li>still hearing the hummingbird but haven’t been able to spot it yet, little bugger blends in well</li>
<li>backyard squirrel is lookin chonk for the winter</li>
</ul>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:27:24 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048404</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>november 28 etc</title>
			<link>https://combatdavey.net/november-28-etc/</link>
						<dc:creator>combatdavey</dc:creator>
			<category>etc</category>
			<category>tbbs</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://combatdavey.net/november-27-etc/">Yesterday's post</a> was a doozy but also a low-key big moment for me. I don't really write much about struggling with depression and anxiety and things of that type for reasons including that I was really turned off 12-15 years ago when everyone was selling their trauma to magazines and blogs for dispiritingly small amounts of money. I didn't disapprove. People can talk about whatever they want and should be allowed to sell anything they own if they want to. Thing is, because of this the public conversation about mental health grew to be focused on talking about things a little bit —— but not doing anything to change the societal underpinnings and social structures that lead to mental illness or, really, any kind of struggle.</p>
<p>It was so disingenuous. Corporations assured us that they understood mental health was health and were interested in promoting and fostering a healthy, inclusive culture —— but it was never serious.</p>
<p>I once told a manager person at an ad agency I worked at that I was strugglling with an assignment because I was having anxiety attacks at work and she asked if I did yoga. That same company didn't let me go home the day my friend died. They let me sob in my office instead. I got zero work done but I sure was there. Later that night I went to the gym and lifted so heavy I probably tore something and then I drank a million drinks at Disgraceland back when that place existed.</p>
<p>I guess all I'm saying is that I lived most of my life feeling ashamed for being different, for being broken, for being too emotional, for having dreams and goals that were unrecognizable and incoherent to my friends and family and I'm just not anymore.</p>
<p>I carried it for so long. I may as well have been holding a brick of yellow cake uranium because shame does things to a person and they're not good things, and so one day I said fuck it, quit drinking, started taking my health seriously, started pulling at some threads to figure out some stuff that felt important and some other stuff that was only important to me. I got honest with myself, sure, but I also gave myself the kind of grace I had saved up and spent on others my whole life and I got better.</p>
<p>Five, ten, fifteen years ago I would never have written about struggling with depression because I would have feared the judgment and scorn of others. Nowadays I wouldn't even notice it because my veins are made of gold.</p>
<p>🌲 gonna <br>
🌼 go <br>
🌱 <del>touch</del> zzzzzzzzzz <br>
🌳 <del>grass</del> zzzzzzzzzz <br>
🌷 zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz</p>
<p>Be good to yourself.</p>
<p><mark>If you enjoyed this post, click the little up arrow chevron thinger below the tags to help it rank in Bear's <a href="https://bearblog.dev/discover/">Discovery feed</a> and maybe consider sharing it with a friend or on your socials.</mark></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 21:59:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048403</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>On work: who sets the defaults?</title>
			<link>https://tracydurnell.com/2025/11/28/on-work-who-sets-the-defaults/</link>
						<dc:creator>Tracy Durnell</dc:creator>
			<category>Technology</category>
			<category>Work</category>
			<category>AI</category>
			<category>automation</category>
			<category>capitalism</category>
			<category>corporate interests</category>
			<category>income inequality</category>
			<category>Labor</category>
			<category>management</category>
			<category>meritocracy</category>
			<category>normal</category>
			<category>power dynamics</category>
			<category>worker's rights</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://starbreaker.org/blog/personal/good-enough-april-2024/index.html#content">Good Enough; or, Never Give Your Best At Work</a> by Matthew Cambion</p>
<blockquote><p>A <em>good enough</em> job is one that doesn’t pay so little that you’re living paycheck to paycheck. It should let you support a family on no more than twenty-four hours a week of work, <em>without</em> your spouse also having to work.</p></blockquote>
<p>+<img src="http://tracydurnell.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/virtue-hoarders-214x300.jpg" alt="" width="214" height="300" data-sanitized-class="alignright size-medium wp-image-29263"></p>
<blockquote><p>“The radical and material difference in average income between janitor and CEO should be intolerable to everyone who is not a capitalist, but PMC elites have internalized the values of the meritocracy so deeply that they cannot see the radical nature of this difference in incomes as essentially different from all other kinds of difference.”<br>
— Catherine Liu, <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2025/09/03/read-virtue-hoarders/"><em>Virtue Hoarders</em></a></p></blockquote>
<p>See also: <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2023/02/10/who-is-high-income-anyway/">Who is high income anyway?</a></p>
<p><a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2022/12/22/they-dont-only-take-our-labor/">They don’t only take our labor.</a></p>
<p>+</p>
<p><a href="https://www.robinsloan.com/lab/all-that-is-solid/">All That is Solid Melts Into Code</a> by Robin Sloan</p>
<blockquote><p>Automation never meets a task in the world and simply does it. There’s always negotiation, the invention of some new zippered relationship.</p></blockquote>
<p>See also: <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2023/05/19/robotizing-both-employees-and-customers/">Robotizing both employees and customers</a></p>
<p><span data-sanitized-id="more-31901"></span></p>
<p>+<img src="http://tracydurnell.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/saving-time-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" data-sanitized-class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-31942"></p>
<blockquote><p>“This phenomenon, in which one adapts her temporal rhythms to those of something or someone else, is called <dfn>entrainment</dfn>, and it often plays out on an uneven field of relationships that reflects hierarchies of gender, race, class, and ability.”<br>
— Jenny Odell, <em>Saving Time</em></p></blockquote>
<p>See also: <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2022/12/19/who-do-you-give-power-over-your-time/">Who do you give power over your time?</a></p>
<p><a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2021/01/07/time-is-a-tool-of-capitalism/">Time is a Tool of Capitalism</a></p>
<p>+</p>
<p><a href="https://crookedtimber.org/2025/07/31/moral-deskilling-or-why-you-spend-more-time-on-admin-than-doing-your-job/">Moral Deskilling – or, why you spend more time on admin than doing your job</a> by Hannah Forsyth</p>
<blockquote><p>Systematising virtue handed control to managers. Who, endlessly mistrusting these expert folk who were always trying to do things the expensive way, converted that mistrust into endless, endless paper work.</p></blockquote>
<p>+</p>
<p><img src="http://tracydurnell.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/medium-hot-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" data-sanitized-class="size-medium wp-image-30846 alignright"></p>
<blockquote><p>“[I]t is more likely that many [digital and administrative white-collar laborers] will be forced to ‘upgrade’ by renting services built on their own stolen labor, in order to remain ‘competitive’, than that they will be replaced fully by ML automation. Today, training for these professionals means getting them used to their disappearance over the medium term and conditioning them to dependency on monopoly stacks, in order to be able to continue to work and access the results of their own labor.”<br>
— Hito Steyerl, <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2025/10/31/read-medium-hot/"><em>Medium Hot</em></a></p></blockquote>
<p>See also: <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2024/07/09/when-you-dont-own-your-tools/">When you don’t own your tools</a></p>
<p><a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2023/09/25/generative-ai-is-intellectual-sharecropping/">Generative AI is intellectual sharecropping</a></p>
<p>+</p>
<p><a href="https://eev.ee/blog/2025/07/03/the-rise-of-whatever/">The rise of Whatever</a> by Eevee (emphasis original)</p>
<blockquote><p>I think the core of what pisses me off is that selling this magic machine <strong>requires</strong> selling the idea that <em>doing things is worthless</em>. Because if <em>doing something</em> has some value, then it must be somehow better than pushing a button and receiving Whatever for essentially no cost. If you’re some assclown like Sam Altman, whose graph-go-up depends on convincing you to replace all your employees with ChatGPT, you <em>have to destroy that idea</em>. It is the greatest threat to your business model. You have to destroy the idea that <em>things are worth doing</em>.</p></blockquote>
<p>See also: <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2024/01/30/the-siren-call-of-llms/">The siren call of LLMs</a></p>
<p>+<img src="http://tracydurnell.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/the-class-matrix-199x300.jpg" alt="" width="199" height="300" data-sanitized-class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-31943"></p>
<blockquote><p>“Workers submit to capitalism not because they view it as legitimate or just but because they see no real possibility for changing it.”<br>
— Vivek Chibber, <em>The Class Matrix</em></p></blockquote>
<p>See also: <a href="https://tracydurnell.com/2024/01/24/capitalism-brain/">Capitalism brain</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 21:08:11 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048402</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>What we did for Thanksgiving</title>
			<link>https://blog.lauramichet.com/what-we-did-for-thanksgiving/</link>
						<dc:creator>lauram</dc:creator>
			<category>recommendations</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>We did a hot pot lunch!!</p>
<p><img src="https://bear-images.sfo2.cdn.digitaloceanspaces.com/lauram/img_0985.webp" alt="IMG_0985"></p>
<p>I highly recommend this for a Thanksgiving meal.</p>
<ul>
<li>People can be assigned to bring various hot pot food items.</li>
<li>Nobody has to cook any of the food items ahead of time (unless you really want to provide a side dish).</li>
<li>Cooking the food is genuinely entertaining!!</li>
<li>You can get TWO pots and do both meat and vegetarian hot pots at the same table!!</li>
<li>Cleanup is pretty easy...</li>
</ul>
<p>There truly is no better Thanksgiving.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 20:44:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048401</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Hyperlink Roundup 10</title>
			<link>https://basic.bearblog.dev/hyperlink-roundup-10/</link>
						<dc:creator>basic</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Been a long week at work and I'm glad it is over. I was able to setup an old Mac Pro as a desktop station with Ubuntu, revived an old ThinkPad with Ubuntu and still have another for OpenBSD that used to be my wife's old Windows 10 laptop. I've been busy with off-loading iCloud Photos and other Apple software from my life to save money as a bonus from monthly charges. It is so easy to fall into that trap of where the convenience makes you forget what is actually happening in the background with your data. Back to "self-hosting" which is another way of what we used to do and save our files locally and didn't think about "syncing".</p>
<h3 data-sanitized-id="tech-stuff">Tech Stuff</h3><p><a href="https://journal.bsd.cafe/2025/11/28/jellyfin-on-freebsd/">Jellyfin on FreeBSD</a> - Installing Jellyfin on your BSD system.</p>
<p><a href="https://joe-editor.sourceforge.io/">Joe's Own Editor</a> - JOE is a full featured terminal-based screen editor</p>
<p><a href="https://itsfoss.com/new-gen-linux-apps/">11 of My Favorite Linux Apps That Refused to Stay Dead</a> - These Linux apps were popular once. And then they were abandoned. And then they came back with a new generation tag.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/tanrax/maza-ad-blocking">Maza ad blocking</a> - Simple, native and efficient local ad blocker. Only Bash.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/sakofchit/system.css/">System.css</a> - A design system for building retro Apple interfaces.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/ai-robots-txt/ai.robots.txt">ai.robots.txt</a> - A list of AI agents and robots to block.</p>
<p><a href="https://deskto.ps/o/openbsd">OpenBSD desktops</a> - Screenshots from many OpenBSD desktops.</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/kavishdevar/librepods">LibrePods</a> - unlocks Apple's exclusive AirPods features on non-Apple devices.</p>
<h3 data-sanitized-id="blogs">Blogs</h3><p><a href="https://kevquirk.com/blog/how-i-replaced-my-son-s-pc-with-an-88-imac/">How I Replaced My Son’s PC With an £88 iMac</a> - Kev explains his experience installing Linux on an older iMac.</p>
<p><a href="https://hackaday.com/2025/11/25/so-long-firefox-part-two/">So Long Firefox, Hello Vivaldi</a> - Where Do I Go From Here?</p>
<p><a href="https://it-notes.dragas.net/2025/11/24/why-i-still-love-linux/">Why I (still) love Linux</a> - Stefano loves BSD but Linux still holds a place in his heart.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.markpitblado.me/blog/a-self-hosted-music-setup-that-rivals-spotify/">A self-hosted music setup that rivals spotify</a> -  starting my own music collection streaming it with Navidrome.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 20:40:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048400</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>A ChatGPT prompt equals about 5.1 seconds of Netflix</title>
			<link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Nov/29/chatgpt-netflix/#atom-everything</link>
						<dc:creator>Simon Willison</dc:creator>
			<category>netflix</category>
			<category>ai-energy-usage</category>
			<category>openai</category>
			<category>ai</category>
			<category>llms</category>
			<category>ai-ethics</category>
			<category>sam-altman</category>
			<category>generative-ai</category>
			<category>chatgpt</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>In June 2025 <a href="https://blog.samaltman.com/the-gentle-singularity">Sam Altman claimed</a> about ChatGPT that "the average query uses about 0.34 watt-hours".</p>
<p>In March 2020 <a href="https://www.weforum.org/stories/2020/03/carbon-footprint-netflix-video-streaming-climate-change/">George Kamiya of the International Energy Agency estimated</a> that "streaming a Netflix video in 2019 typically consumed 0.12-0.24kWh of electricity per hour" - that's 240 watt-hours per hour at the higher end.</p>
<p>Assuming that higher end, a ChatGPT prompt by Sam Altman's estimate uses:</p>
<p><code>0.34 Wh / (240 Wh / 3600 seconds) =</code> 5.1 seconds of Netflix</p>
<p>Or double that, 10.2 seconds, if you take the lower end of the Netflix estimate instead.</p>
<p>I'm always interested in anything that can help contextualize a number like "0.34 watt-hours" - I think this comparison to Netflix is a neat way of doing that.</p>
<p>This is evidently not the whole story with regards to <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-energy-usage/">AI energy usage</a> - training costs, data center buildout costs and the ongoing fierce competition between the providers all add up to a very significant carbon footprint for the AI industry as a whole.</p>
<p><small>(I got some help from ChatGPT to <a href="https://chatgpt.com/share/692a52cd-be04-8006-bb01-fbd68aae05ba">dig these numbers out</a>, but I then confirmed the source, ran the calculations myself, and had Claude Opus 4.5 <a href="https://claude.ai/share/0a1792e6-6650-4ad3-8d01-99d8eeccb7f0">run an additional fact check</a>.)</small></p>

    <p>Tags: <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/netflix">netflix</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-energy-usage">ai-energy-usage</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/openai">openai</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai">ai</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llms">llms</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-ethics">ai-ethics</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/sam-altman">sam-altman</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/generative-ai">generative-ai</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/chatgpt">chatgpt</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 19:13:36 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048399</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bandcamp Finds 251128</title>
			<link>https://dallincrump.com/bandcamp-finds-251128?pk_campaign=rss-feed</link>
						<description><![CDATA[<p>I probably spent too much on music today. I tend to do that on Bandcamp, especially when labels are having sales on their entire catalogs so I can buy multiple titles and save on shipping costs. “Hey, its supporting small and independent artists and labels,” I tell myself. </p>

<p>I recently discovered a label called <a href="https://businesscasual.biz/"><em>business casual</em></a>. Founded in 2013, they first specialized in Vaporwave but have since expanded to include a variety of electronic genres and styles. And they love to release their albums on cassette. I'm starting to focus more on that format since deciding to ditch vinyl, so I jumped on the sale and ordered a handful of tapes and a CD.</p>
<ul><li><a href="https://businesscasual87.bandcamp.com/album/broadcasts"><em>Broadcasts</em></a> by Sonnig 991 &amp; Simple Syrup</li>
<li><a href="https://businesscasual87.bandcamp.com/album/twin-palms"><em>Twin Palms</em></a> by GammaFlow</li>
<li><a href="https://businesscasual87.bandcamp.com/album/jewel-in-the-crown"><em>Jewel in the Crown</em></a> by Bart Graft</li>
<li><a href="https://businesscasual87.bandcamp.com/album/in-place-of-power"><em>In Place Of Power</em></a> by Full Eclipse</li>
<li><a href="https://businesscasual87.bandcamp.com/album/lake-hiraeth"><em>Lake Hiareth</em></a> by Ghostmemory</li>
<li><a href="https://businesscasual87.bandcamp.com/album/rainbow-smears"><em>Rainbow Smears</em></a> by maggie.wav</li></ul>

<p>I also bought digital versions of a couple albums from <a href="https://farfallarecords.com/">Farfalla Records</a>, a French label specializing in 70s and 80s Library music.</p>
<ul><li><a href="https://farfallarecords.bandcamp.com/album/occhio-occhio"><em>Occhio Occhio</em></a> by Eleven76</li>
<li><a href="https://farfallarecords.bandcamp.com/album/heatwaves"><em>Heatwaves</em></a> by Pleasurewood</li></ul>

<p>These are the first albums I've bought from either label and I look forward to exploring them.</p>

<p>I actually had to pare down my original cart for <em>business casual</em> – lots of interesting albums there.</p>

<p>I'll be playing the physical media on my <a href="https://twitch.tv/newfangledhifi">Twitch stream</a> hopefully soon.</p>

<p><a href="https://remark.as/p/dallincrump.com/bandcamp-finds-251128">Discuss...</a></p>

<p><a href="https://dallincrump.com/tag:100DaysToOffload" data-sanitized-class="hashtag"><span>#</span><span data-sanitized-class="p-category">100DaysToOffload</span></a> (No. 115) <a href="https://dallincrump.com/tag:music" data-sanitized-class="hashtag"><span>#</span><span data-sanitized-class="p-category">music</span></a> <a href="https://dallincrump.com/tag:libraryMusic" data-sanitized-class="hashtag"><span>#</span><span data-sanitized-class="p-category">libraryMusic</span></a> <a href="https://dallincrump.com/tag:vaporwave" data-sanitized-class="hashtag"><span>#</span><span data-sanitized-class="p-category">vaporwave</span></a> <a href="https://dallincrump.com/tag:synthwave" data-sanitized-class="hashtag"><span>#</span><span data-sanitized-class="p-category">synthwave</span></a> <a href="https://dallincrump.com/tag:electronicMusic" data-sanitized-class="hashtag"><span>#</span><span data-sanitized-class="p-category">electronicMusic</span></a> <a href="https://dallincrump.com/tag:Bandcamp" data-sanitized-class="hashtag"><span>#</span><span data-sanitized-class="p-category">Bandcamp</span></a> <a href="https://dallincrump.com/tag:physicalMedia" data-sanitized-class="hashtag"><span>#</span><span data-sanitized-class="p-category">physicalMedia</span></a> <a href="https://dallincrump.com/tag:cassette" data-sanitized-class="hashtag"><span>#</span><span data-sanitized-class="p-category">cassette</span></a> <a href="https://dallincrump.com/tag:compactDisc" data-sanitized-class="hashtag"><span>#</span><span data-sanitized-class="p-category">compactDisc</span></a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 19:01:02 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048398</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>One thing I’d like to change about Pokémon TCG</title>
			<link>https://hamatti.org/posts/one-thing-id-like-to-change-about-pokemon-tcg/</link>
						<dc:creator>Juha-Matti Santala</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>
  Youtube channel
  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/post/UgkxncbEjzh153fyjf55hIG0xxVvyAX52vGE" data-sanitized-class="notion-text-href">Control Players Unite posted a poll</a>
  with a question and four options
</p>
<img src="https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/one-thing-id-like-to-change-about-pokemon-tcg/1.png.webp" alt="A Youtube poll from Control Players Unite. The question and answer options are described below. ">
<blockquote data-sanitized-class="notion-quote notion-color-default">
  Of the following, if you could change ONE thing about the Pokémon TCG, it
  would be…
</blockquote>

<p>with the options of</p>
<ul data-sanitized-class="notion-bulleted_list">
  <li data-sanitized-class="notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default">
    The prize check rule — let us look at them already!
  </li>

  <li data-sanitized-class="notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default">
    The power creep — why on earth am I hitting 230 for 1 energy?
  </li>

  <li data-sanitized-class="notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default">
    Best of 1 rules (especially relevant for control play)
  </li>

  <li data-sanitized-class="notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default">
    Something to fix slow play
  </li>
</ul>
<p>
  All four make sense so let’s go through all options and why or how they should
  be fixed.
</p>

<h2 data-sanitized-class="notion-heading_2 notion-color-default">
  Eliminating prize checking
</h2>

<p>
  In Pokémon TCG, at the start of each game, you put aside 6 random cards as
  “prize cards”. You are not allowed to look at them and each time you knock out
  opponent’s Pokémon, you get to pick some prizes (usually at least…).
</p>

<p>Prize cards create an extra level of randomness and require you to</p>
<ul data-sanitized-class="notion-bulleted_list">
  <li data-sanitized-class="notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default">
    build your deck in a way where prizing something important doesn’t
    completely ruin your game plan and
  </li>

  <li data-sanitized-class="notion-bulleted_list_item notion-color-default">
    adapt your gameplay based on your prizes
  </li>
</ul>
<p>
  Still, the current system creates a problem. Players, especially in higher
  competitive play, want to know what their prizes are so they spend (and are
  allowed to spend) quite a lot of time during their first deck search going
  through their remaining cards to deduce which 6 cards they don’t have access
  to.
</p>

<p>
  A tournament game of Pokémon is played as best of three wins with a time limit
  of usually 50 minutes.
</p>

<p>
  I mostly play casual so this isn’t really a problem for me. I don’t prize
  check a lot myself — I usually make sure I know how many energies I have
  available and check a couple of the most important cards. In casual play, we
  also don’t generally play with time limits so I’m only exposed to this when
  watching official streams.
</p>

<p>
  I really like what
  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/@ComebackMechs" data-sanitized-class="notion-text-href">Comeback Mechanics</a>
  group do in their Gym Leader Challenge matches. They have a custom houserule
  (that they call Matty’s Map) that allows the player to look at their prizes
  when they search their deck for the first time.
</p>
<img src="https://hamatti.org/assets/img/posts/one-thing-id-like-to-change-about-pokemon-tcg/2.png.webp" alt="A custom Pokemon TCG Item card named Matty’s Map that reads: You can only use this card during your first deck search. Look at your face-down prize cards. Then, shuffle your face-down prize cards. ">
<p>
  This gives the player same knowledge than rigorously going through their deck
  but in fraction of time.
</p>

<p>
  Some people argue that efficiently checking your prizes is a skill and they
  don’t want that skill requirement reduced from the game. I can understand
  where they come from but I do disagree. Especially in a game where the game
  clock is shared and there’s no individual clocks like in chess.
</p>

<p>
  In a game that goes to full 3 matches, if both players spend a couple of
  minutes checking for prizes, that’s easily over 10 minutes out of the general
  play time just to check for prizes. For example, the first deck search in a
  recent Latin America International Championship’s 2nd day stream lasted 3.5
  minutes.
</p>

<p>
  Being able to check your prizes and make notes would cut these early game
  searches short and would speed up the game. I think it would be a good
  tradeoff for the game.
</p>

<h2 data-sanitized-class="notion-heading_2 notion-color-default">The power creep</h2>

<p>
  I chose the power creep as my answer in the poll. Even though I think prize
  checking would be beneficial for the game, I really wish the game’s balance
  would change.
</p>

<p>
  I’ve been lately enjoying my share of retro Pokémon — especially
  <a href="https://jklaczpokemon.com/ex/" data-sanitized-class="notion-text-href">RS-PK format</a>
  from early 2000s. It’s a format I never played when it was the active format
  but I highly prefer it over the current standard format.
</p>

<p>
  The biggest thing is that there’s very few one hit KO options. The game is
  slower, requires better board management and you need to make — in my opinion
  — more interesting decisions constantly because it’s hard to get rid of all of
  your opponent’s threats in one turn. So you have to think about how you
  balance between building your board and being aggressive to chase knockouts.
</p>

<p>
  It’s no wonder why that format has grown to be probably the most played retro
  format. It doesn’t have quite as broken trainers as the early years and it’s
  not full of 3-prize Pokémon and one hit KOs like modern standard format.
</p>

<p>
  I really wished that Pokémon Company had learned their lesson after the
  previous 3-prize cards like Tag Team and VMAX Pokémon but somehow they managed
  to bring the concept back with the newest iteration of Mega evolutions.
</p>

<p>
  This is also why I like casual
  <a href="https://gymleaderchallenge.com/" data-sanitized-class="notion-text-href">Gym Leader Challenge</a>. While some people play the format similarly to modern standard — going full
  meta and trying to find the best deck in the format — there’s a lot of
  opportunities to play the format in a slower pace, utilising cards you
  wouldn’t otherwise play.
</p>

<p>
  I’ve also been enjoying playing
  <a href="https://notes.hamatti.org/gaming/board-games/pokemon/scarlet--and--violet-progression-series" data-sanitized-class="notion-text-href">Progression Series</a>
  with our local game group. Your card pool in it is limited so you can’t put 4
  copies of the best card and 4 of each card that supports it to build super
  consistent decks. You need to make do with what you have and that slows down
  the game a lot.
</p>

<h2 data-sanitized-class="notion-heading_2 notion-color-default">Best of 1 rules</h2>

<p>
  I’m not sure what the author of the poll means with the better best of 1 rules
  but I think this game doesn’t lend to the format that well, especially in a
  competitive format. The game is too prone for donking (winning the game in
  turn 1 or 2 by knocking out all your opponent’s Pokémon before they manage to
  set up) that it feels it would create a very volatile format with luck playing
  even bigger role.
</p>

<p>
  Maybe that could be solved by some of the better rules but especially right
  now (see previous section), the game is so fast that I’m worried it would lead
  to even less varied meta game. W consistent early game setup (likely with big
  basics) becomes a crucial part of not getting donked, the game loses a lot of
  it charm.
</p>

<h2 data-sanitized-class="notion-heading_2 notion-color-default">
  Something to fix slow play
</h2>

<p>
  Game is played in best of 3 format but finishing 3 games in 50 minutes is a
  lot to ask. In the recent
  <a href="https://labs.limitlesstcg.com/0046/pairings" data-sanitized-class="notion-text-href">Latin America Internationals</a>, each round, 15-21% of the games finished in a draw. That’s a lot. And I
  couldn’t find data on how many games ended 1-0 with even the second game not
  having time to finish but it’s a non-zero amount.
</p>

<p>
  Prize checking is one part of the problem but even without it, it’s too easy
  for the games to run long.
</p>

<p>
  I don’t have good solutions though. It’s not something that really affects me
  because we don’t really have sanctioned tournaments here and when playing
  casually over a couple of beers, slow play is usually a result of chatting
  about life and it’s always worth it.
</p>

<p>
  For competitive play at the highest level, I think chess clocks could be an
  option. Give each player their own time budget. It’s very easy in Pokémon TCG,
  within its rules, to manipulate the clock and speed up or slow down the game.
  A clock could help with that as it would deincentivize slow play. Everytime
  someone brings it up though, the community gets up and arms so I’m not gonna
  champion the idea any further.
</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048397</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bluesky Thread Viewer thread by @simonwillison.net</title>
			<link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Nov/28/bluesky-thread-viewer/#atom-everything</link>
						<dc:creator>Simon Willison</dc:creator>
			<category>projects</category>
			<category>tools</category>
			<category>ai</category>
			<category>generative-ai</category>
			<category>llms</category>
			<category>cors</category>
			<category>bluesky</category>
			<category>vibe-coding</category>
			<category>coding-agents</category>
			<category>claude-code</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="https://tools.simonwillison.net/bluesky-thread.html?url=https%3A%2F%2Fbsky.app%2Fprofile%2Fsimonwillison.net%2Fpost%2F3m6pmebfass24&amp;view=thread">Bluesky Thread Viewer thread by @simonwillison.net</a></strong></p>
I've been having a lot of fun hacking on my Bluesky Thread Viewer JavaScript tool with Claude Code recently. Here it renders a thread (complete with <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/simonwillison.net/post/3m6pmebfass24">demo video</a>) talking about the latest improvements to the tool itself.
<p><img alt='This short animated GIF demo starts with the Thread by @simonwillison.net page where a URL to a Bluesky post has been entered and a Fetch Thread button clicked. The thread is shown as a nested collection of replies. A "Hide other replies" button hides the replies revealing just the top-level self-replies by the original author - and turns into a "Show 11 other replies" button when toggled. There are tabs for Thread View and Most Recent First - the latter when clicked shows a linear list of posts with the most recent at the top. There are "Copy" and Copy JSON" green buttons at the top of the page.' src="https://static.simonwillison.net/static/2025/bluesky-thread-viewer-demo.gif"></p>
<p>I've been mostly vibe-coding this thing since April, now spanning <a href="https://github.com/simonw/tools/commits/main/bluesky-thread.html">15 commits</a> with contributions from ChatGPT, Claude, Claude Code for Web and Claude Code on my laptop. Each of those commits links to the transcript that created the changes in the commit.</p>
<p>Bluesky is a <em>lot</em> of fun to build tools like this against because the API supports CORS (so you can talk to it from an HTML+JavaScript page hosted anywhere) and doesn't require authentication.


    </p><p>Tags: <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/projects">projects</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/tools">tools</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai">ai</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/generative-ai">generative-ai</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llms">llms</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/cors">cors</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/bluesky">bluesky</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/vibe-coding">vibe-coding</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/coding-agents">coding-agents</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/claude-code">claude-code</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 16:57:22 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048396</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Walk with me: The bigger picture</title>
			<link>https://gabe.rocks/health/wwm-emotional-transformation/</link>
						<media:content url="https://gabe.rocks//audio/2025-11-28.opus"></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>This off-the-cuff recording is an attempt to share the much broader context behind my ongoing transformation. Now that I have accomplished enough that people say they regularly point to my example, I feel obligated to disclose the bigger fight taking place. My health changes have merely been a major objective in a broader emotional battle. This is an attempt to put into words the emotional turmoil behind <a href="https://gabe.rocks/health/how">how I got so big.</a> This particular recording is a bit more intense than usual, so be advised of more difficult subject matter being discussed.</p>
<h2 data-sanitized-id="major-victories">Major Victories</h2>
<h3 data-sanitized-id="new-low-3178lbs">New low: 317.8lbs</h3>
<p>Unfortunately, I’m not likely to reach this year’s ‘greedy’ goal of losing 200lbs in 2025. I’ve got a month to go and with everything I have learned I don’t think I will be able to lose 40lbs in another month. But even being already 160lbs down for the year is still a massive hard-won victory. This new low puts me at almost 260lbs down total. By shedding all this extra weight, I’m finally at a point where the benefits are beginning to compound.</p>
<h3 data-sanitized-id="feeling-more-capable-and-mobile">Feeling more capable and mobile</h3>
<p>Despite a stubborn foot injury, getting around feels so much better. I can move a lot quicker than before and it feels very gratifying. Some of my small investments into building better habits are making things that would be very mentally and physically taxing feel much more within reach. I’m finding myself getting much better at making small investments in taking better care of myself, and feeling the gratifying sense of accomplishment when it pays off.</p>
<h3 data-sanitized-id="feeling-genuinely-comfortable-in-my-skin">Feeling genuinely comfortable in my skin</h3>
<p>With most of the extreme health and mobility challenges behind me, I’m back to a familiar state. But a great deal has changed under the surface. These days, I genuinely feel like I am at a point where being at peace with myself is closer to the default than the exception. The regular positive interactions I’m having with people is comforting in a level that is hard to get in the moment, but I can certainly appreciate the cumulative effects.</p>
<p>It is very difficult to articulate, but I no longer feel like my mind is actively working against me. I am experiencing a shocking yet familiar sense in my mind that I can only concisely summarize as “I’m back!”. It feels like the fog of numbness and dread has lifted and I get to embrace my chance at life for all it is in both big and small ways.</p>
<h2 data-sanitized-id="the-emotional-battle">The emotional battle</h2>
<p>The meat of this recording is where I try to articulate the ‘story behind the story’ of my health journey. Making new friends lately has had me face regret and loss I didn’t realize I was burying. I miss many of my old friends so much more now that I have gotten to know other excellent people on a deeper level as I’ve slowly and gradually come out of various forms of isolation. It wouldn’t be me if this reflection didn’t include my thoughts on how it all connects to the wider world. The more I think about the long arc of this path I’ve walked, the more I understand things about myself I took for granted. I am now at a point where I am ignited with a passion for sharing much more than just the physical changes that brought me to this point.</p>
<p>Thank you for reading this through RSS 📡</p>
        <p>Your thoughts and feedback are both very important to me.<br><a href="https://gabe.rocks//get-in-touch">Get in touch!</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 16:47:15 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048395</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Feet First into Madness</title>
			<link>https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/2025/11/28/feet-first-into-madness/</link>
						<dc:creator>Musings from a Tangled Mind</dc:creator>
			<category>Everyday Musings</category>
			<category>black friday</category>
			<category>comedy</category>
			<category>dailyprompt</category>
			<category>dailyprompt-2138</category>
			<category>fashion</category>
			<category>favorite things</category>
			<category>humor</category>
			<category>musings</category>
			<category>rich people</category>
			<category>style</category>
			<media:content url="https://0.gravatar.com/avatar/31ec7a2e33056eb9b17551f99a60a9ba20d8b41e7681ea12d7fe7911294c5215?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" medium="image"><media:title type="html">surojabu11</media:title></media:content>
			<media:content url="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/table-leg-boot-710-2-e1764369876509.png?w=660" medium="image"></media:content>
			<media:content url="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/bent-toe-boot-3900-1.png?w=1017" medium="image"></media:content>
			<media:content url="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/slinky-shoe-1200-1.png?w=552" medium="image"></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>So, I don’t do Black Friday. I don’t even <em>think</em> about going out on Black Friday. I mean, I hate people. I hate <em>crowds</em> of people even more. Why would I voluntarily walk into a store on the one day of the year when strangers turn into UFC fighters over a microwave? Do you know me at all? I would rather buy absolutely nothing for the rest of my life and cook all my meals over a single tea light than go to Target on Black Friday.</p>



<p>But apparently the universe said, “Hey, since you’re not going outside… let’s bring the chaos to <em>you</em>.”</p>



<p>Because while I’m curled up peacefully on my couch, scrolling through social media like a normal hermit, I get hit with a series of ads from the same store. A fancy <em>boutique </em>store clearly designed for people who collect yachts the way I collect stress. Like… why am I in this algorithm? What did I click? Who does Instagram think I am? I can’t even afford socks without coupons and they’re showing me items that cost more than my car.</p>



<p>But then I saw the shoes. The shoes that looked like someone described fashion to an alien who had only ever seen video transmissions of office supplies and workplace accidents.</p>



<p>The first pair? White ankle boots that looked like an office chair got tired of corporate life and decided to transition into footwear. Same bland, corporate cream color. Same texture. And the heel — I swear to you — is literally an office chair leg. Yes, I’m talking about the chrome desk-chair thing. I looked at it and immediately felt the urge to file paperwork. </p>



<p>See for yourself:</p>


<div data-sanitized-class="wp-block-image">
<figure data-sanitized-class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/table-leg-boot-710-2-e1764369876509.png"><img width="660" height="309" data-attachment-id="12582" data-permalink="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/2025/11/28/feet-first-into-madness/table-leg-boot-710/#main" data-orig-file="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/table-leg-boot-710-2-e1764369876509.png" data-orig-size="950,445" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta='{"aperture":"0","credit":"","camera":"","caption":"","created_timestamp":"0","copyright":"","focal_length":"0","iso":"0","shutter_speed":"0","title":"","orientation":"0"}' data-image-title="table leg boot = 710" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/table-leg-boot-710-2-e1764369876509.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/table-leg-boot-710-2-e1764369876509.png?w=660" src="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/table-leg-boot-710-2-e1764369876509.png?w=660" alt="" data-sanitized-class="wp-image-12582"></a></figure>
</div>


<p></p>



<p>Seven. Hundred. Dollars.</p>



<p>For shoes that clock in at nine a.m., gossip about coworkers by noon, and get passive-aggressive by five. I mean, yeah, that sounds like me, but believe it or not, it’s really not my style (that’s sarcasm for you folks in the back).</p>



<p>And just when I thought, “Okay. That’s the worst of it. That’s the peak. Surely we have hit the summit of Mount What-The-Hell,” the next pair appeared.</p>



<p>These brown leather boots where the toe — and I mean this — has snapped backwards like it tried to fight a wall lost. It looks like the shoe stubbed its own toe. Like it tripped over itself. Like it has seen some things. This shoe looks like it’s still in physical therapy.</p>


<div data-sanitized-class="wp-block-image">
<figure data-sanitized-class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/bent-toe-boot-3900-1.png"><img width="1017" height="547" data-attachment-id="12583" data-permalink="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/2025/11/28/feet-first-into-madness/bent-toe-boot-3900/#main" data-orig-file="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/bent-toe-boot-3900-1.png" data-orig-size="1017,547" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta='{"aperture":"0","credit":"","camera":"","caption":"","created_timestamp":"0","copyright":"","focal_length":"0","iso":"0","shutter_speed":"0","title":"","orientation":"0"}' data-image-title="bent toe boot = 3900" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/bent-toe-boot-3900-1.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/bent-toe-boot-3900-1.png?w=660" src="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/bent-toe-boot-3900-1.png?w=1017" alt="" data-sanitized-class="wp-image-12583"></a></figure>
</div>


<p></p>



<p>And the price?<br>Three thousand, nine hundred dollars.</p>



<p>Oh yeah. Four grand to walk around looking like you’ve just survived some kind of Wile E. Coyote mishap. One of his crazier ones to boot. (ha!) I have never seen a shoe look tired before. That shoe needs a nap. That shoe needs to sit on a heating pad and reevaluate its life choices.</p>



<p>But THEN the pièce de resistance (yeah, I know French…).  The slinky shoe.</p>



<p>A lovely blue upper, genuinely pretty, and then… a heel made out of what appears to be a dryer vent pipe. Or a slinky someone glued together. Or maybe a half-crushed can of cranberry sauce from Thanksgiving dinner. The whole thing screams, “I was designed during a drug-induced fever dream.” I mean, really, who looks at duct work and thinks fashion?</p>


<div data-sanitized-class="wp-block-image">
<figure data-sanitized-class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/slinky-shoe-1200-1.png"><img width="552" height="366" data-attachment-id="12584" data-permalink="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/2025/11/28/feet-first-into-madness/slinky-shoe-1200/#main" data-orig-file="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/slinky-shoe-1200-1.png" data-orig-size="552,366" data-comments-opened="1" data-image-meta='{"aperture":"0","credit":"","camera":"","caption":"","created_timestamp":"0","copyright":"","focal_length":"0","iso":"0","shutter_speed":"0","title":"","orientation":"0"}' data-image-title="slinky shoe = 1200" data-image-description="" data-image-caption="" data-medium-file="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/slinky-shoe-1200-1.png?w=300" data-large-file="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/slinky-shoe-1200-1.png?w=552" src="https://musingsfromatangledmind.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/slinky-shoe-1200-1.png?w=552" alt="" data-sanitized-class="wp-image-12584"></a></figure>
</div>


<p></p>



<p>Twelve hundred dollars. Twelve hundred dollars for footwear that looks like the HVAC system escaped and attacked your foot. That’s some Final Destination shit right there. Only you’re paying for it.</p>



<p>And listen, I know rich people have money. I know they can buy whatever they want. But… do they lose a bit of common sense for every dollar they make? At a certain point, you’re not buying fashion — you’re buying evidence. Evidence that you shouldn’t be trusted unsupervised.</p>



<p>Even if I had that kind of money, I still wouldn’t drop $700 on a pair of shoes that look like they’d swivel if I leaned too far to the left. I wouldn’t pay four thousand dollars to look like my toes suddenly turned on me in the night. And I damn sure wouldn’t spend twelve hundred dollars to strap a soup can to my foot.</p>



<p>I’ll take my fluffy socks and 20-year-old sneakers any day of the week, thank you very much.</p>



<p>It’s painfully obvious that the gap between rich people and the rest of us has never been wider. You’ve got folks choosing between groceries and medication, trying to stretch a dollar like it’s made of taffy… and then somewhere out there, someone is dropping four grand on boots that look like they lost a fight with a brick wall. It’s wild. It’s obscene.</p>



<p>If this is what the ultra-rich are spending their money on, we’re definitely not living in the same reality.</p>



<p data-sanitized-class="has-white-color has-text-color has-link-color wp-elements-7e4ac651328708ea719ac0894fa30934">.</p>



<p></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:58:52 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048394</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Announcing Validate Everything</title>
			<link>https://jamesg.blog/2025/11/28/validate-everything/</link>
						<dc:creator>James' Coffee Blog</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>Today the <a href="https://events.indieweb.org/2025/11/indieweb-black-friday-create-day-build-don-t-buy-C044CcYllKyt">IndieWeb community hosted a Create Day event</a> in which participants were invited to make something on the web. The theme of the event was “Build Don't Buy”, an invitation to make something this Black Friday.</p><p>While I wasn’t sure what I wanted to make, I knew I wanted to make <em>something</em>. I consulted my list of ideas and one stood out: a website that lets you type in a URL and creates links to various helpful validators. This project was inspired by Adactio’s “<a href="https://adactio.com/journal/20965">Bookmarklets for testing your website</a>” project.</p><p>During the event, I made a new page on my website called “<a href="https://jamesg.blog/validate-everything">Validate Everything</a>”. The web page lets you paste in a URL and automatically generates links to validators like the WAVE accessibility validator, the Google Rich Results Test tool, microformats testers, and more. I added tools I have used in the past to validate or understand the markup behind web pages.</p><p>I use a several validators but I typically end up typing the name of the validator into a search engine and then reading through the results to find the one I want. With this project, I wanted to have a single page with many common validators.</p><p>You can <a href="https://jamesg.blog/validate-everything">try out the page today</a>, and <a href="https://github.com/capjamesg/validate-everything">see the source code on GitHub</a>. Contributions are most welcome!</p><h2 data-sanitized-id="how-the-page-works"><strong>How the page works</strong></h2><p>As part of the project, I wanted to experiment with CSS. I asked myself: could I show/hide the validator links depending on whether there was a valid URL in the form field on the web page? After some thought, reading, experimentation, and discussion with fellow participants in the Create Day event, I learned that you can select a form field if it its contents are valid or invalid using the <code>:valid</code> and <code>:invalid</code> selectors. I could then combine these with the <code>:has</code> and <code>:not</code> selectors to manipulate content on the page depending on whether the user has typed in a valid URL in the form field on the page.</p><p>I came up with the following selector to show/hide the validator links not he page depending on if there is a valid URL in the page form field:</p><div data-sanitized-class="highlight"><pre><span></span><span data-sanitized-class="nt">body</span><span data-sanitized-class="p">:</span><span data-sanitized-class="nd">not</span><span data-sanitized-class="o">(</span><span data-sanitized-class="p">:</span><span data-sanitized-class="nd">has</span><span data-sanitized-class="o">(</span><span data-sanitized-class="p">#</span><span data-sanitized-class="nn">url</span><span data-sanitized-class="p">:</span><span data-sanitized-class="nd">valid</span><span data-sanitized-class="o">))</span><span data-sanitized-class="w"> </span><span data-sanitized-class="p">#</span><span data-sanitized-class="nn">items</span><span data-sanitized-class="w"> </span><span data-sanitized-class="p">{</span>
<span data-sanitized-class="w">      </span><span data-sanitized-class="k">display</span><span data-sanitized-class="p">:</span><span data-sanitized-class="w"> </span><span data-sanitized-class="kc">none</span><span data-sanitized-class="p">;</span>
<span data-sanitized-class="p">}</span>
</pre></div>
<p>This selector will select the <code>#items</code> element if the page <code>body</code> does not have an element with the ID <code>#url</code> that is valid. If the condition is met, the <code>#items</code> element is hidden. The <code>#items</code> element contains the list of validators.</p><p>For <code>:valid</code> to work, I needed to specify a few validation rules in my HTML input. I wrote the following input tag:</p><div data-sanitized-class="highlight"><pre><span></span><span data-sanitized-class="p">&lt;</span><span data-sanitized-class="nt">input</span> <span data-sanitized-class="na">type</span><span data-sanitized-class="o">=</span><span data-sanitized-class="s">"url"</span> <span data-sanitized-class="na">id</span><span data-sanitized-class="o">=</span><span data-sanitized-class="s">"url"</span> <span data-sanitized-class="na">name</span><span data-sanitized-class="o">=</span><span data-sanitized-class="s">"url"</span> <span data-sanitized-class="na">placeholder</span><span data-sanitized-class="o">=</span><span data-sanitized-class="s">"https://example.com"</span> <span data-sanitized-class="na">pattern</span><span data-sanitized-class="o">=</span><span data-sanitized-class="s">"https://.*\.[a-zA-Z]{3,}.*"</span> <span data-sanitized-class="na">required</span> <span data-sanitized-class="na">autocomplete</span><span data-sanitized-class="o">=</span><span data-sanitized-class="s">"off"</span> <span data-sanitized-class="p">/&gt;</span>
</pre></div>
<p>This input says that the URL field must have a URL that:</p><ol><li>Starts with <code>https://</code>, and;</li><li>Is followed by any string of characters, which is then;</li><li>Followed by a <code>.</code> (dot), which is then;</li><li>Followed by two or more letters.</li></ol><p>For example, <code>https://jamesg.blog</code> would be valid, and as a result the validator URL list would appear. But <code>https://jamesg.b</code> would not be valid (only one character follows the <code>.</code>), so the validator list would not appear. An input is also required by specifying the HTML <code>required</code> boolean. This means that the validator URLs will not appear when the field is blank.</p><p><em>NB: This regex is not testing for whether a user’s TLD is valid. This could be done with a more complex regex, but this is something I can always add later. What I have right now is good enough!</em></p><p>When a URL is typed in, JavaScript makes two changes to the page:</p><ol><li>A <code>?url=…</code> parameter is added so that the user has a link they can bookmark/share, and;</li><li>All the validator links are updated to add the text the user has typed in.</li></ol><p>This means that when the user has finished typing – or has pasted in – their URL, all the links on the page will directly link to different validator websites.</p><h2 data-sanitized-id="building-things-is-fun"><strong>Building things is fun</strong></h2><p>I had a lot of fun making this web page! I learned about the <code>:valid</code> CSS rule. I got to play around with the <code>:has</code> selector more. I experimented with page spacing and typography. And I also learned that you can’t click on a <code>view-source:</code> link directly on a page in Firefox for security reasons. Indeed, with everything I build, I always learn something new.</p><p>I have been in a bit of a creative rut lately in terms of making new things. I am learning about so many new things, but I’m not ready to translate much of what I am learning into a project. I am eager to make things that push me outside my comfort zone and let me use my new skills, but I haven’t been quite sure where to begin. I read somewhere that sometimes the hardest step is getting started. Today, I was able to get started and create a page that I think is fun and interesting, useful, and based on an idea I had several months ago. I’m proud of the page I made today. I love making things.</p><h2 data-sanitized-id="addendum:-how-it-started">Addendum: How it started</h2><p>I like taking screenshots of my projects as I build them, especially if I'm experimenting with different designs.</p><p>I had a tab open from my first version of this project I made early in the meetup. I took the following screenshot:</p><img alt="" src="https://editor.jamesg.blog/content/images/2025/11/list.png" data-sanitized-class="kg-image"><p>When <a href="https://jamesg.blog/validate-everything">compared with the live page</a>, you can see the above list has the essence of what I wanted: a URL bar, and a list of links. I then added subheadings to separate the validators into categories, realising there were many I wanted to add. I added some styles (and dark mode!) and worked on the JavaScript to make the page work.</p><p>Which is to say: all projects start somewhere, and are built one step at a time!</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:09:32 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048393</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The First Ecumenical Synod and Its Significance</title>
			<link>http://www.mystagogyresourcecenter.com/2025/11/the-first-ecumenical-synod-and-its.html</link>
						<dc:creator>Unknown</dc:creator>
			<category>First Ecumenical Synod</category>
			<category>Metropolitan Hierotheos of Nafpaktos</category>
			<media:thumbnail url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg_VjIFdUshxKa3l2TvIgKUHxaeUKpnbQEfNIsVkoiBSD_EzELydhyYjqaX8JDjqJwGKFp76R1jiflOCx97d3IU6Ocyrsop2VLvFMJ04VFsgW3AZgrJYEVabUN-aPMID55UO6XwFxNwTMQNXypLSjr5wX_fPdg-dBQJINr0X9991435XJO0ZpZD4M6UP88/s72-w640-h576-c/8-%CE%91-%CE%9F%CE%99%CE%9A%CE%9F%CE%A5%CE%9C%CE%95%CE%9D%CE%99%CE%9A%CE%97-%CE%A3%CE%A5%CE%9D%CE%9F%CE%94%CE%9F%CE%A3-2.webp" width="72" height="72" />
			<media:content url="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg_VjIFdUshxKa3l2TvIgKUHxaeUKpnbQEfNIsVkoiBSD_EzELydhyYjqaX8JDjqJwGKFp76R1jiflOCx97d3IU6Ocyrsop2VLvFMJ04VFsgW3AZgrJYEVabUN-aPMID55UO6XwFxNwTMQNXypLSjr5wX_fPdg-dBQJINr0X9991435XJO0ZpZD4M6UP88/s72-w640-h576-c/8-%CE%91-%CE%9F%CE%99%CE%9A%CE%9F%CE%A5%CE%9C%CE%95%CE%9D%CE%99%CE%9A%CE%97-%CE%A3%CE%A5%CE%9D%CE%9F%CE%94%CE%9F%CE%A3-2.webp" medium="image" height="72" width="72"></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[<div><span><br><div data-sanitized-class="separator"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg_VjIFdUshxKa3l2TvIgKUHxaeUKpnbQEfNIsVkoiBSD_EzELydhyYjqaX8JDjqJwGKFp76R1jiflOCx97d3IU6Ocyrsop2VLvFMJ04VFsgW3AZgrJYEVabUN-aPMID55UO6XwFxNwTMQNXypLSjr5wX_fPdg-dBQJINr0X9991435XJO0ZpZD4M6UP88/s600/8-%CE%91-%CE%9F%CE%99%CE%9A%CE%9F%CE%A5%CE%9C%CE%95%CE%9D%CE%99%CE%9A%CE%97-%CE%A3%CE%A5%CE%9D%CE%9F%CE%94%CE%9F%CE%A3-2.webp"><span><img border="0" data-original-height="540" data-original-width="600" height="576" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg_VjIFdUshxKa3l2TvIgKUHxaeUKpnbQEfNIsVkoiBSD_EzELydhyYjqaX8JDjqJwGKFp76R1jiflOCx97d3IU6Ocyrsop2VLvFMJ04VFsgW3AZgrJYEVabUN-aPMID55UO6XwFxNwTMQNXypLSjr5wX_fPdg-dBQJINr0X9991435XJO0ZpZD4M6UP88/w640-h576/8-%CE%91-%CE%9F%CE%99%CE%9A%CE%9F%CE%A5%CE%9C%CE%95%CE%9D%CE%99%CE%9A%CE%97-%CE%A3%CE%A5%CE%9D%CE%9F%CE%94%CE%9F%CE%A3-2.webp" width="640"></span></a></div><br></span></div><div><span>At the Synodal Divine Liturgy celebrated on Sunday, June 1st 2025, at the Sacred Metropolitan Church of Athens, presided over by His Beatitude Archbishop of Athens and All Greece, Hieronymos, for the 1700th anniversary of the convening of the First Ecumenical Synod in 325 in Nicaea of Bithynia, His Eminence Metropolitan of Nafpaktos and Agiou Vlasiou, Hierotheos, Vice-President of the Permanent Holy Synod, spoke on the topic: “The First Ecumenical Synod and Its Significance.”</span><br><br>The Sunday of the Holy Fathers of the First Ecumenical Synod, during this Easter period, leading up to the feast of Pentecost, is wonderful, and rightly the Sacred Synod of the Church of Greece determined to celebrate it magnificently. This is done with a Synodal Divine Liturgy, with hymns and speeches meet for God, with a convocation of the Hierarchy of the Church of Greece and with events befitting this great feast, with the completion of 1,700 years since the convocation of the First Ecumenical Synod, which was called “Holy” and “Great” and became the model for the other Ecumenical Synods that followed, in which we, the Bishops, gave a confession that we will abide by their decisions.<br><br>This brief eucharistic homily, by decision of the Sacred Synod, also falls within this framework.<br><b><br><span></span></b></div><a href="http://www.mystagogyresourcecenter.com/2025/11/the-first-ecumenical-synod-and-its.html#more"></a>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:01:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048392</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Make It Easy For You</title>
			<link>https://mirroredworld.bearblog.dev/make-it-easy-for-you/</link>
						<dc:creator>mirroredworld</dc:creator>
			<category>creation</category>
			<category>evergreen</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<hr>
<p>The one thing I write <a href="https://mirroredworld.bearblog.dev/getting-things-done-without-keeling-over/">time and again</a> is how to keep creative sparks alive in day to day living, especially if you consider your routine far removed from your chosen practice. Every segment of my previous post can be its own separate entry, but I want to focus on what is probably the easiest to apply: make it easy for you to start doing the thing (or not, we'll get to that later). This also applies to any activity you'd like to do more of.</p>
<p>We live in an era where everything compete to drain you of your attention and energy, so make it easier for you to write/draw/... than it would take to check notifications (I turn off almost every notification in my phone during the day, and I set all of them off in nighttime). In practice, this looks like this: have a small notebook with you <em>all the time</em>, complete with a pen or two (or any of your favorite writing utensil). Spending your time in front of the TV? Park a sketchbook where you usually sit. Hate spending time priming your paints? Get a travel set if you must. Pin and bookmark your blog dashboard on your main browser. Set up a shortcut. Make the activity front, center, and easy to get into.</p>
<p>This sounds easier than it takes. We often have predilections and entrenched beliefs that may clash with this. I love organizing my files into folders. I like having my spaces in order. But my brain goes out of sight, out of mind. I have to make peace with a little bit of clutter if that means more chance for me to actually get something done. I can put them away when I'm done. There's also a matter of pride. Why should I get water brushes if I usually paint at home? Why should I get a dishwasher if I live alone and perfectly capable of doing my dishes on my own? It could matter when it's a difference between you actually doing the cooking now or slouching back to your couch muttering "eh, maybe tomorrow". Arrange your living space in such a way to minimize movement if your energy is limited and the prospect of going to and fro kills your spark, no matter how nice it is to have a separate office room and a craft room. Get the guitar out of the basement and right by your dresser. Pick an engine you can delve right away without setting a thousand little knobs.</p>
<p>Convenience is not inherently evil. It's also not inherently lazy. It is what you make out of it. Take some time to sit down and make a list of everything you'd like to do and why you are <em>not</em> doing it (or what prevented you from doing more of it). Are you avoiding something? Is there any hack you can find to work around that?</p>
<p>However, do not take this as a maxim. Know yourself. You can flip this over, <em>intentionally create fiction</em>, to create small rituals for you to observe to make the activity feel special. For example, I know people who like to begin their writing sessions by sitting down, rolling a desk mat, lighting a candle, and uncapping their pen slowly. They say the whole sequence helps them set the mood.</p>
<p>There's no shame in making it easy (or hard) for you, so set forth and create.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:22:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1764416361048391</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
