<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >
	<channel>
		<title> | FreshRSS</title>
		<link>http://192.168.1.206/FreshRSS/p</link>
		<description>RSS feed of  | FreshRSS</description>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 12:02:27 -0700</pubDate>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 19:02:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="/i/?a=rss&amp;state=2" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
				<item>
			<title>Weeknotes: 2025-W50</title>
			<link>https://thomasrigby.com/posts/2025-w50/</link>
						<dc:creator>Thomas Rigby</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<h2>8th December - 14th December</h2>
<p>Startled awake at 4am by who knows what. I hate 4am because it's too early for an early start but too late to go back to sleep.</p>
<hr>
<p>As I mentioned last week, the work bedlam continues. I have three full-time projects that I have to get to a certain level of "done" before the Christmas break. It's doable but there's a fair bit of pressure on me. Usually I'd panic but I'm conducting myself pretty well — running point on client communications, writing code, defining strategy.</p>
<p>I have also put plans in place to step up in the role of our team's "AI Champ"; a group of employees championed with helping peers navigate the complicated and controversial world of AI<sup>1</sup>.</p>
<p>Regular readers aware of my position on artificial intelligence tools may be surprised by my decision. My argument goes; they're going to use it anyway, it's better they have a dissenting –and informed– voice at the table than a room full of fanboys!</p>
<hr>
<p><picture><source type="image/webp"><img src="https://thomasrigby.com/images/KlVMVdvRxd-600.jpeg" alt="a pile of four Alan Garner books on a shelf; Boneland, The Stone Book Quartet, Thursbitch, and The Voice That Thunders" width="900" height="675" data-sanitized-class=""></picture><br>
<br>
</p>
<p>Chris the handyman stopped by with a small handful of Alan Garner books for me to borrow so it looks like my "To Read" list just got bigger — physical books too, which will be novel. So lovely of him and made me feel part of a community.</p>
<hr>
<p>The village Christmas Tree is up and sparkling in the evening gloom. Nearby, in the graveyard, tiny Christmas Trees adorned with lights are popping up on the newer graves; sad and heartwarming.</p>
<hr>
<p>Speaking of evening gloom, I <a href="https://social.treehouse.systems/@pndc/115714711071380909">learned</a> about the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Equation_of_time">Equation of Time</a> which days that we're into a period where the evenings are getting lighter (but the mornings are darker). Science is so interesting!</p>
<hr>
<h2>Links of Interest™</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://louplummer.lol/fbi-watchlist/">That Time I Ended Up on an FBI Watchlist</a></li>
<li><a href="https://photoni.st/index.php/2025/12/05/photography-doesnt-have-an-ai-problem/">Photography Doesn’t Have an AI Problem</a></li>
<li><a href="https://niqwithq.com/posts/windows-aero-remnants">Windows Aero Remnants</a></li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p><sup>1</sup>: Neither "artificial" nor "intelligence".</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 11:34:02 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765738103228652</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>In Defense of Lowbrow Space</title>
			<link>https://mirroredworld.bearblog.dev/in-defense-of-lowbrow-space/</link>
						<dc:creator>mirroredworld</dc:creator>
			<category>creation</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<hr>
<p>The problem with practicing artmaking rather publicly is eventually you'll see someone who starts a conversation with, "I have always wished to try writing/drawing/composing/[insert your preferred artform here.]" And you, being a polite person, might reply with, "Well, why not try?" To which you're met with many excuses, but one of my favorite turn of conversations tend to go a certain way. For the sake of coherence, I will give examples for writing in particular, though you can sub this into just about any form of art.</p>
<p>"I don't know where to start. I don't get how people do character interactions well."</p>
<p>"Well, you observe real people, practice. Many of us also got a start in fanfiction. Start with characters you already know."</p>
<p>A frown.</p>
<p>"Isn't that where horny teenagers go? That's just bad writing, isn't it?"</p>
<p>"Not always. You actually see a wide range of skill and observing how different people interpret something can be useful."</p>
<p>The question of platform might have come up. You may tell them it's okay to just write things in a junk journal, or start a blog.</p>
<p>And then you might come up with FFN or AO3, if you want other people to see them and give feedbacks. I might or might not have dated myself.</p>
<p>"I've always been told it's trash. Do you have any other suggestion?"</p>
<p>"If original work is more your jam, you can try Wattpad?"</p>
<p>The exact websites don't matter. DeviantArt? SoundCloud? Itch.io? It can be anything.</p>
<p>"Oh, no, no. Imagine what people would say if they know I'm writing on these seedy websites."</p>
<p><em>They would probably give no two fucks about it, but if they do, you're probably better off finding a better set of friends.</em> But you're trying to be very nice and helpful here, so you remind them that junk drawers exist. Just write something and shove them somewhere. Explore. Just start first.</p>
<p>"Well, no one will see what I make, then? It's pointless."</p>
<p>It's usually a good time to excuse yourself. Or if you're in a charitable mood, you listen to them drone on and on about not having a place to hone their skills. They shun lowbrow space, thinking they're too good for these places, and would gladly laugh at meme pages filled with bad quotes after bad quotes from Wattpad. Do they crank quality piece after quality piece for prestigious publication? No, because they'd just rather <em>not write</em> at all.</p>
<p>What many people seem to have difficulty accepting is the truth that artistic skills don't come fully formed. That many creatives can spend their lives making bad and ugly things until they make something they like. And all these have to start somewhere. That can be an amateur comic group. It can be a garage band. It can be handdrawn zines you exchange with each other at recess. We can't all start in the halls of MoMA, in the pages of The New Yorker.</p>
<p>I take issue with people who love to make fun of these lowbrow spaces but never try making things themselves. These spaces weren't usually built to serve them, Most Honored Consumer (Only Ever Consumer) of Distinguished Taste, masterpieces of the ages (though quality really does vary, and you're bound to realize that many people take their craft seriously even as <em>mere hobbyist</em> in a lowbrow space). They're low-stakes environments where people start and experiment. Where making mistakes don't cost a career. Where ideas can be explored without commercial pressure (sometimes, this also means getting to explore taboo or sensitive topics no sensible publisher would dare to broach). Heck, even where some people test audience appeal. Or just a fun way to spend an evening with friends. They make artmaking feels accessible. (And they teach you that your "super simple idea" is actually not very easy to do)</p>
<p>It's no secret that you'll find a lot of voices from marginal communities in these spaces, which might alienate Most Honored Consumer Whose Taste Must be Catered even more. Some people would recoil at the thought that certain things are not made <em>for</em> them. Imagine.</p>
<p>The continual loss of amateur playgrounds in favor of institutions with more polished sheen is to be lamented. Why mourn "junk" arts? We're mourning the spirit that comes with it.</p>
<p>Do not fear lowbrow space. Sing bad covers. Make noisy nonsense. Draw stupid pictures. These spaces exist, fill them. Or fill your junk drawer if you'd rather have your creative life private. Do yourself a favor: stop making excuses and stop making fun of people who actually take time to make things and brave their heart to publish them.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 11:31:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765738103228651</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Do you want to read a detailed post about eyelid surgery? Here it is. With photos.</title>
			<link>https://anniemueller.com/posts/do-you-want-to-read-a-detailed-post-about-eyelid-surgery-here-it-is-with-photos</link>
						<description><![CDATA[<div data-sanitized-class="trix-content">
  <p>I find this sort of thing fascinating. I looked for detailed info before my own surgery because I like to know what I’m getting into. If you’re grossed out by surgical/medical descriptions or photos, skip this one. </p>
<hr>
<p>So I had this spot — like a pimple or small wart — appear under my right eye years ago. 2017, 2018? Sometime in there. It was very small, directly under/partially on the lash line near the inside corner of my right eye. Not really noticeable, didn’t hurt or itch or grow or change so I didn’t worry about it<sup data-sanitized-id="fnref:1"><a data-id="fb4591ee-2587-4817-a2db-6093361e312d" href="https://anniemueller.com/posts/do-you-want-to-read-a-detailed-post-about-eyelid-surgery-here-it-is-with-photos#fn:1" data-sanitized-class="footnote-ref">1</a></sup>.</p>
<p>Anyway over the last year it got a bit bigger, so I had it checked out. My dermatologist did a biopsy. Result: basal cell carcinoma. So I needed to have the spot removed. Due to its location, it was likely the lid margin<sup data-sanitized-id="fnref:2"><a data-id="7caccf83-77dc-4cec-94e9-e429644a134c" href="https://anniemueller.com/posts/do-you-want-to-read-a-detailed-post-about-eyelid-surgery-here-it-is-with-photos#fn:2" data-sanitized-class="footnote-ref">2</a></sup> would be affected. So after the removal, I’d need eyelid reconstruction surgery by an ophthalmic surgeon. </p>
<p>Here’s how they do it: They schedule the Mohs surgeries<sup data-sanitized-id="fnref:3"><a data-id="4908f4ca-de84-4df8-b074-257eedc48eba" href="https://anniemueller.com/posts/do-you-want-to-read-a-detailed-post-about-eyelid-surgery-here-it-is-with-photos#fn:3" data-sanitized-class="footnote-ref">3</a></sup> in the morning. They schedule the reconstruction surgeries the same afternoon. </p>
<p>They do this because Mohs surgeries can take… hours. They don’t know till they’re doing it. The surgeon takes off the cancerous area and a layer of the skin around it, then examines it under a microscope. If they still see carcinoma cells<sup data-sanitized-id="fnref:4"><a data-id="49ae6dcc-cfa7-4626-b5cf-2b13a42fd995" href="https://anniemueller.com/posts/do-you-want-to-read-a-detailed-post-about-eyelid-surgery-here-it-is-with-photos#fn:4" data-sanitized-class="footnote-ref">4</a></sup>, they take off another layer. Inspect the removed layer. Repeat until there are no carcinoma cells visible in the removed layer. </p>
<p>The removal is quick. The inspection takes longer. So each “layer” (removal + inspection) can be over an hour. </p>
<p>Once that’s done, they either sew you up there or send you off for reconstruction surgery. </p>
<p>I was at the hospital from 7am to 5pm. Most of that time was spent waiting. The Mohs surgery required two layers removed. I was done there around 9:30. They bandaged my eye and sent me off for reconstruction which was scheduled for…. 2:30pm. So, yeah, lots of waiting. </p>
<p><strong>Mohs surgery</strong></p>
<div data-sanitized-class="attachment-gallery">
<figure data-sanitized-class="attachment attachment--preview attachment--jpeg">



    <img height="3088" width="2316" data-zoom-src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/8lXEi2RF6LD-nnDKdxNM4-IRVFpriTcEblrD9Vj9s7g/s:3840:3840/fn:IMG_9151/plain/s3://pika-production/oqmcv2xge877mnx8raec0alydoit" data-original-src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/gp5txzOpXS-2kzIybLYivRkw28pnjHTxDGq2ZQSfnUI/fn:IMG_9151/plain/s3://pika-production/oqmcv2xge877mnx8raec0alydoit" alt="" src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/r8TuplRFWou-5_B3PbbaLVtwyQrqOMz9ZKbAosFXyJY/s:1800:1400/fn:IMG_9151/plain/s3://pika-production/oqmcv2xge877mnx8raec0alydoit">

    <figcaption data-sanitized-class="attachment__caption">
      Waiting after the first layer was removed. 
    </figcaption>
</figure><p></p>
</div>
<ul>
<li><p>Local anesthetic (needle in the cheek below the right eyelid).</p></li>
<li><p>They lean you back in a chair and tuck surgical drapes around the area. </p></li>
<li><p>Assisting docs hold the head still and hold the eyelid open or closed or whatever it needs to be. </p></li>
<li><p>It’s pretty surreal to see a scalpel coming directly toward your eyeball.</p></li>
<li><p>But the most surreal part was hearing the snip-snip-snip of scissors knowing it’s<em> my skin</em> that’s being snipped<em> off my face</em>. </p></li>
<li><p>Pain: none. They gave me another shot of anesthetic right before they patched me up which was nice. </p></li>
</ul>
<div data-sanitized-class="attachment-gallery attachment-gallery--2">
  <figure data-sanitized-class="attachment attachment--preview attachment--jpeg">



    <img height="4032" width="3024" data-zoom-src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/agLkSCT9Nt-WtdnBrd5MRU2flenz5_wsMBx3R_CvJvY/s:3840:3840/fn:IMG_9158/plain/s3://pika-production/n3vwqspfyglt5kjwyk0yceiqu2py" data-original-src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/RciNKFpOYKL4oAgKKt_BZASGFAJtct_9i6nv2bbOzXE/fn:IMG_9158/plain/s3://pika-production/n3vwqspfyglt5kjwyk0yceiqu2py" alt="" src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/0GWM91ouWN4us3WNm95XaiVLXx_ir7OItEWUQMbxD70/s:1800:1400/fn:IMG_9158/plain/s3://pika-production/n3vwqspfyglt5kjwyk0yceiqu2py">

    <figcaption data-sanitized-class="attachment__caption">
      Removal complete. 
    </figcaption>
</figure><figure data-sanitized-class="attachment attachment--preview attachment--jpeg">



    <img height="3088" width="2316" data-zoom-src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/lEJzYmO0XBS2c4bsUkBfsh_mZ-AY3enA6JhxZ8H6CrY/s:3840:3840/fn:IMG_9157/plain/s3://pika-production/lcbrikggmu5pfzes1mqfty318909" data-original-src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/rcMF_7jVVH5-q101oKP2rLu5DWGKNpUAhORq-lWcin0/fn:IMG_9157/plain/s3://pika-production/lcbrikggmu5pfzes1mqfty318909" alt="" src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/IT7L-OSc2WjJUSsrJSflAQ2jYaJdc0WD6dHekI-qVvk/s:1800:1400/fn:IMG_9157/plain/s3://pika-production/lcbrikggmu5pfzes1mqfty318909">

    <figcaption data-sanitized-class="attachment__caption">
      Patched up.
    </figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p><strong>Waiting</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><p>Hungry (no eating allowed before the reconstruction surgery). </p></li>
<li><p>Did some Christmas shopping. </p></li>
<li><p>Pirate impressions.</p></li>
<li><p>Thought about food. </p></li>
<li><p>Went to the bathroom a couple of times to peek under the bandage and make sure my eye was still there. Then the anesthetic wore off so I didn’t need to do that anymore. </p></li>
<li><p>Contemplated the hierarchy of snacks. </p></li>
<li><p>Assured 4 different nurses that there is zero possibility of pregnancy, no really, I promise, <em>I do not have a uterus</em>.</p></li>
<li><p>Speaking of the beast (not) in me: Watched a couple of episodes of <em>The Beast In Me</em>.</p></li>
<li><p>Looked at the entire Internet. </p></li>
<li><p>Thought about food some more. </p></li>
<li><p>Napped a little. </p></li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Eyelid reconstruction </strong></p>
<ul>
<li><p>Sedation (via IV) plus local anesthetic. I was very relaxed and full of warm happy thoughts. </p></li>
<li><p>This part was fascinating: The removal took about half the width of my eyelid rim above the area of removed tissue. They took skin from my left eyelid and grafted it on. To do that, they cut right along the crease of my left eyelid, removed some skin, and sutured the eyelid back together. Then they sewed those two strips of skin (I think it was two, I was a little drowsy) below my right eye, creating a new portion of eyelid rim and filling the hole. Amazing that we can do this stuff. </p></li>
<li><p>The surgery itself took about an hour. </p></li>
<li><p>Recovery was quick. I was home eating a giant Chipotle bowl very soon after. It was delicious. </p></li>
</ul>
<div data-sanitized-class="attachment-gallery"><figure data-sanitized-class="attachment attachment--preview attachment--jpeg">



    <img height="978" width="2316" data-zoom-src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/RtFpBmuDaudaVEFgwH7f8U-rhrxrI5zzbdfrk9fJnFE/s:3840:3840/fn:IMG_9164/plain/s3://pika-production/pqx59s1972m0aa9jzql9graiqbqr" data-original-src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/N4I-OaL2OVuiRbQY3zTcCvWuBMqQAZngEncU1wGd_8w/fn:IMG_9164/plain/s3://pika-production/pqx59s1972m0aa9jzql9graiqbqr" alt="" src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/iUYazkYO6hTO15lLnj0tbQLiRfWn-nhg43P5L6KNr4w/s:1800:1400/fn:IMG_9164/plain/s3://pika-production/pqx59s1972m0aa9jzql9graiqbqr">

    <figcaption data-sanitized-class="attachment__caption">
      Dressing sewn onto skin graft under right eye
    </figcaption>
</figure></div>
<figure data-sanitized-class="attachment attachment--preview attachment--jpeg">



    <img height="843" width="2316" data-zoom-src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/5KlWrE4rx8LiAmKpl_w_muIw8i7NWEzuWsZFkClX31I/s:3840:3840/fn:IMG_9169/plain/s3://pika-production/zvhc93izhsf40yic0xt4hkqxzxhz" data-original-src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/-ojkfEDajh0Y9bE28Yo9AjXU_OgxOwOeMncYvJwDgFs/fn:IMG_9169/plain/s3://pika-production/zvhc93izhsf40yic0xt4hkqxzxhz" alt="" src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/vtsck_oQSAzknIgkZDMR31WcBWezVE1tWJPtJsjRT4Y/s:1800:1400/fn:IMG_9169/plain/s3://pika-production/zvhc93izhsf40yic0xt4hkqxzxhz">

    <figcaption data-sanitized-class="attachment__caption">
      Sutures across crease of left eyelid
    </figcaption>
</figure><p><strong>Recovery</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><p> Pain: minimal. Took Tylenol that first night and following day, then didn’t need it again. </p></li>
<li><p>Antiobiotic ointment applied 3x a day. This is annoying as fuck because I have to make sure I get a lot of ointment on that lid margin (very important to keep it moisturized) which means some ointment always gets in my eye so vision is blurred for an hour+ every time I apply. </p></li>
<li><p>Swelling: yes. </p></li>
<li><p>Bruising: some. Not as much as I anticipated. </p></li>
<li><p>Itchy and irritated: YES. OMG.</p></li>
<li><p>I get the dressing &amp; sutures off tomorrow morning and I CANNOT WAIT. </p></li>
</ul>
<p>Here’s how it looks today (six days post-op):</p>
<div data-sanitized-class="attachment-gallery attachment-gallery--2">
  <figure data-sanitized-class="attachment attachment--preview attachment--jpeg">



    <img height="3088" width="2316" data-zoom-src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/hLL5r-AiMtxODPUlrvWj_VwazLUB6OWFuOXNu1QeBlc/s:3840:3840/fn:IMG_9265/plain/s3://pika-production/ah5cwalupy7fmvll3rvs8noiffow" data-original-src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/ImL5ITPe2ILImFWRZOFwXXPT5ex58__xMmIZOJMbvSI/fn:IMG_9265/plain/s3://pika-production/ah5cwalupy7fmvll3rvs8noiffow" alt="" src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/5BcjSDULVqdjPOMIbGSel8RV1C_mMgdBSZlI-KO3G0c/s:1800:1400/fn:IMG_9265/plain/s3://pika-production/ah5cwalupy7fmvll3rvs8noiffow">

</figure><figure data-sanitized-class="attachment attachment--preview attachment--jpeg">



    <img height="3088" width="2316" data-zoom-src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/b72hTBc4qdPqg8yQZrpR_8WSI4_qR_rZIPbfj1R3qf4/s:3840:3840/fn:IMG_9264/plain/s3://pika-production/jy99804r0mnzvpfkwbbcxs3ajtc8" data-original-src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/drMUsnEnGkrf0B-mASI759A-nMAf6F0KhPO3_sSsOCM/fn:IMG_9264/plain/s3://pika-production/jy99804r0mnzvpfkwbbcxs3ajtc8" alt="" src="https://cdn.u.pika.page/PiEzFjXV0CxJmgim6H_F65ApypT1qIvHb5_Hd08e82A/s:1800:1400/fn:IMG_9264/plain/s3://pika-production/jy99804r0mnzvpfkwbbcxs3ajtc8">

</figure>
</div>
<p>Oh, what’s that? You were hoping for an EYELID SURGERY RECOVERY MONTAGE of POOR QUALITY PHOTOS documenting the healing process from DAY 1 TO DAY 6 POST-OP? I’ve got that right here for you. </p>
<div data-sanitized-class="attachment-gallery">
<p></p>
<figure data-sanitized-class="attachment attachment--preview attachment--gif">



    <img height="492" width="876" data-zoom-src="/rails/active_storage/blobs/redirect/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6OTk3ODgsInB1ciI6ImJsb2JfaWQifX0=--8b4541d0938735808e39b6bac73698aa19a2ffcb/251208-14eyelid%20montage.gif" data-original-src="/rails/active_storage/blobs/redirect/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6OTk3ODgsInB1ciI6ImJsb2JfaWQifX0=--8b4541d0938735808e39b6bac73698aa19a2ffcb/251208-14eyelid%20montage.gif" alt="" src="https://anniemueller.com/rails/active_storage/blobs/redirect/eyJfcmFpbHMiOnsiZGF0YSI6OTk3ODgsInB1ciI6ImJsb2JfaWQifX0=--8b4541d0938735808e39b6bac73698aa19a2ffcb/251208-14eyelid%20montage.gif">

</figure>
</div>
<ol data-sanitized-class="footnotes">
<li data-id="fb4591ee-2587-4817-a2db-6093361e312d" data-sanitized-id="fn:1"><p>Also I did not have health insurance at the time so even if I had been worried about it I probably wouldn’t have done anything. <em>Say you're in the U.S. without saying you’re in the U.S. </em></p></li>
<li data-id="7caccf83-77dc-4cec-94e9-e429644a134c" data-sanitized-id="fn:2"><p>The <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/figure/Zones-and-structures-of-the-human-lid-margin-The-lid-margin-consists-of-different-zones_fig35_44629903">eyelid margin</a> is the “edge” of the eyelid. Also known as the mucocutaneous margin. Eyelashes grow from the margin &amp; there are glands that produce oil to help keep the eye moisturized.</p></li>
<li data-id="4908f4ca-de84-4df8-b074-257eedc48eba" data-sanitized-id="fn:3"><p>Detailed explanation of <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK441833/">Mohs Micrographic Surgery</a>.</p></li>
<li data-id="49ae6dcc-cfa7-4626-b5cf-2b13a42fd995" data-sanitized-id="fn:4"><p><a href="https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/Anatomical-and-molecular-imaging-of-skin-cancer-Hong-Sun/ca31380f28d59ac0d85153301c581584796cf8e1/figure/0">Molecular imaging</a> of different skin cancer cells vs normal skin cells. </p></li>
</ol>
</div>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 11:17:21 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765738103228650</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>So Many Websites</title>
			<link>https://robinrendle.com/notes/So-Many-Websites/</link>
						<dc:creator>Robin Rendle</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>I’ve been thinking about the web and how it’ll change with the increasingly…uh…worrying decline of search. It feels like the order of their results can no longer be trusted, the web no longer reliably scraped. Instead, this essential tool we’ve relied on for more than two decades has halted all progress, reversed course. In a heart beat I would pick the search engine of 2014 over the one I use today.</p>
<p>So there’s a lot of anxiety out there about how this fundamentally changes the economics of the web. Folks are worried that without search functioning properly then the web itself is fading away, becoming irrelevant, or already even broken beyond repair. But I disagree!  The premise at the heart of these conversations is that websites deserve and require a mass readership to be important or worthwhile. But what if they don’t?</p>
<p>Sure, a lot of businesses were built around the economics of search and ten billion people looking at a block of text imprisoned by a swamp of ads for cars and questionable dietary supplements. Although, that doesn’t mean the web itself requires that specific business model to thrive, to still be worthwhile, to still be important. My hot take here is that ugly business models created ugly websites, but I digress.</p>
<p>This idea has been rolling around my head since I started reading <em>So Many Books</em> by Gabriel Zaid where he writes: “It is worth asking, in the first place, whether all books need or deserve a mass readership.” <em>Yikes! Whoa!</em> This line hit me like a ton of bricks because most business models on the web have assumed a mass readership is out there—but what if it isn’t? What if the web, and most websites besides the few obvious exceptions, were instead  more like book publishing? A few thousand dedicated readers out there, at best.</p>
<p>I can feel the disappointment in the conversations I’ve been listening to, as if the whole point of the web is to exist at bewildering, eye-watering scale. A million clicks is so lame, man, when compared to a billion. Heck, your website only gets fifty trillion clicks a day? Is there a point to publishing that dinky website if it’s so small?</p>
<p>But perhaps the death of search is <em>good</em> for the future of the web. Perhaps websites can be free of dumb rankings and junky ads that are designed to make fractions of a penny at a time. Perhaps the web needs to be released from the burden of this business model. Perhaps mass readership isn’t possible for the vast majority of websites and was never really sustainable in the first place.</p>
<p>And perhaps we should let our websites be small and private things once again.</p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 11:06:50 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765738103228649</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>I Made Another RSS Reader... sorta</title>
			<link>https://bearblog.stevedylan.dev/i-made-another-rss-reader-sorta/</link>
						<dc:creator>stevedylandev</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://files.stevedylan.dev/feed-screenshot.png" alt="og"></p>
<p>Some of you who follow me are aware that I <a href="https://bearblog.stevedylan.dev/alcove-an-rss-reader-for-the-open-web/">published Alcove</a> last month, a privacy centered RSS reader. It follows the patterns of traditional RSS readers: categories, syncing, marking read vs unread, viewing content in-app, etc. One of my readers reached out and was excited about the project, but also expressed some hesitancy with RSS as a whole. Their concern was about how with in-app reading we are missing the original context of the post itself, ie the website. This may not be the case for news sites that are littered with ads, but for the majority of blogs, the website is a sacred place. It's where the author puts themself on a page, expressing their personality, their likes or interests, and other helpful information. A great example is <a href="https://xn--gckvb8fzb.com/">マリウス</a>, where the aesthetic and extra information make it a treasure trove of classic web surfing. If you're subscribed in an RSS reader that renders the content within the app, you miss all of this.</p>
<p>The more I thought about this the more I agreed. It's one of the reasons I'm adamantly opposed to AI web browsers that take away the experience of visiting a curated website. Then my mind wandered to the <a href="https://github.com/stevedylandev/freshrss-api-proxy">FreshRSS API Proxy</a> I built a while back to power my <a href="https://bearblog.stevedylan.dev/feeds">feeds page</a>, and I thought "why not give it a face?" That's exactly what I did this weekend, plus a little extra.</p>
<p>Introducing <a href="https://feeds.software/">Feeds</a>. It's a combination of the FreshRSS API proxy and the <a href="https://sipp.so/">Sipp</a> code sharing app I also made a while back. Designed to be self-hosted, has simple architecture that runs on <a href="https://bun.com/">Bun</a>, and made to be hacked around with. There is no categories, no marking posts read or unread, and of course no in-app rendering. It's just a list of posts that link out to the original post.</p>
<p>I recognized that not everyone (more like hardly anyone) has their own FreshRSS instance running, so I setup Feeds to work with multiple source options. To make this happen I built the core RSS parsing logic to accept an array of feed URLs, for example:</p>
<div data-sanitized-class="highlight"><pre><span></span>const items = await parse([
  "https://bearblog.dev/discover/feed/",
  "https://www.nasa.gov/feeds/iotd-feed/"
])
</pre></div>
<p>By taking this approach Feeds can source feeds with the following methods:</p>
<p><strong>URL Queries</strong></p>
<p>You can add on <code>?urls=</code> query to contain comma separated URLs of RSS or Atom feed and the app will automatically source them into a merged list of links. Check out <a href="https://feeds.software/?urls=https://www.nasa.gov/feeds/iotd-feed,https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/feed">this one</a> that merges NASAs Image of the Day and their News Release feed.</p>
<div data-sanitized-class="highlight"><pre><span></span>https://feeds.software?urls=https://www.nasa.gov/feeds/iotd-feed,https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/feed
</pre></div>
<p>This makes it pretty easy for anyone to grab the link and start using it. Make it a bookmark and you have a pretty straight forward reader!</p>
<p><strong>OPML File</strong></p>
<p>If you are self-hosting Feeds you can add a <code>feeds.opml</code> file to the root of the project and the app will automatically read it and render the articles from the feeds inside.</p>
<p><strong>Hard Coding</strong></p>
<p>You can also simply edit the <code>index.html</code> file and hard code in a list of feeds. You'll see some comments in the code in the <code>&lt;script&gt;</code> section that will show you the way!</p>
<p><strong>FreshRSS Instance</strong></p>
<p>If the first two options are not available Feeds will fallback to a FreshRSS instance. Simply <code>cp .env.sample .env</code> and fill in the environment variables.</p>
<div data-sanitized-class="highlight"><pre><span></span>FRESHRSS_URL=
FRESHRSS_USERNAME=
FRESHRSS_PASSWORD=
</pre></div>
<p>Feeds is <a href="https://github.com/stevedylandev/feeds">MIT open sourced</a> for you to do what you want with it. I found this to be a valuable little tool for my own personal use, and I hope others might find it useful as well.</p>
<p>As always, keep the web open.</p>
<div data-sanitized-class="reply-button-container">
  <a href="mailto:contact@stevedylan.dev?subject=Re:%20I%20Made%20Another%20RSS%20Reader...%20sorta" data-sanitized-class="reply-button">reply via email</a>
</div>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 09:29:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765738103228648</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>JustHTML is a fascinating example of vibe engineering in action</title>
			<link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Dec/14/justhtml/#atom-everything</link>
						<dc:creator>Simon Willison</dc:creator>
			<category>html</category>
			<category>python</category>
			<category>ai</category>
			<category>generative-ai</category>
			<category>llms</category>
			<category>ai-assisted-programming</category>
			<category>vibe-coding</category>
			<category>coding-agents</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>I recently came across <a href="https://github.com/EmilStenstrom/justhtml">JustHTML</a>, a new Python library for parsing HTML released by Emil Stenström. It's a very interesting piece of software, both as a useful library and as a case study in sophisticated AI-assisted programming.</p>
<h4 data-sanitized-id="first-impressions-of-justhtml">First impressions of JustHTML</h4>
<p>I didn't initially know that JustHTML had been written with AI assistance at all. The README caught my eye due to some attractive characteristics:</p>
<ul>
<li>It's pure Python. I like libraries that are pure Python (no C extensions or similar) because it makes them easy to use in less conventional Python environments, including Pyodide.</li>
<li>"Passes all 9,200+ tests in the official <a href="https://github.com/html5lib/html5lib-tests">html5lib-tests</a> suite (used by browser vendors)" - this instantly caught my attention! HTML5 is a big, complicated but meticulously written specification.</li>
<li>100% test coverage. That's not something you see every day.</li>
<li>CSS selector queries as a feature. I built a Python library for this <a href="https://github.com/simonw/soupselect">many years ago</a> and I'm always interested in seeing new implementations of that pattern.</li>
<li>html5lib has been <a href="https://github.com/mozilla/bleach/issues/698">inconsistently maintained</a> over the last few years, leaving me interested in potential alternatives.</li>
<li>It's only 3,000 lines of implementation code (and another ~11,000 of tests.)</li>
</ul>
<p>I was out and about without a laptop so I decided to put JustHTML through its paces on my phone. I <a href="https://github.com/simonw/tools/pull/156#issue-3726212220">prompted Claude Code for web</a> on my phone and had it build <a href="https://tools.simonwillison.net/justhtml">this Pyodide-powered HTML tool</a> for trying it out:</p>
<p><img src="https://static.simonwillison.net/static/2025/justhtml.jpeg" alt='Screenshot of a web app interface titled "Playground Mode" with buttons labeled "CSS Selector Query" (purple, selected), "Pretty Print HTML", "Tree Structure", "Stream Events", "Extract Text", and "To Markdown" (all gray). Below is a text field labeled "CSS Selector:" containing "p" and a green "Run Query" button. An "Output" section with dark background shows 3 matches in a green badge and displays HTML code'></p>
<p>This was enough for me to convince myself that the core functionality worked as advertised. It's a neat piece of code!</p>
<h4 data-sanitized-id="turns-out-it-was-almost-all-built-by-llms">Turns out it was almost all built by LLMs</h4>
<p>At this point I went looking for some more background information on the library and found Emil's blog entry about it: <a href="https://friendlybit.com/python/writing-justhtml-with-coding-agents/">How I wrote JustHTML using coding agents</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Writing a full HTML5 parser is not a short one-shot problem. I have been working on this project for a couple of months on off-hours.</p>
<p>Tooling: I used plain VS Code with Github Copilot in Agent mode. I enabled automatic approval of all commands, and then added a blacklist of commands that I always wanted to approve manually. I wrote an <a href="https://github.com/EmilStenstrom/justhtml/blob/main/.github/copilot-instructions.md">agent instruction</a> that told it to keep working, and don't stop to ask questions. Worked well!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Emil used several different models - an advantage of working in VS Code Agent mode rather than a provider-locked coding agent like Claude Code or Codex CLI. Claude Sonnet 3.7, Gemini 3 Pro and Claude Opus all get a mention.</p>
<h4 data-sanitized-id="vibe-engineering-not-vibe-coding">Vibe engineering, not vibe coding</h4>
<p>What's most interesting about Emil's 17 step account covering those several months of work is how much software engineering was involved, independent of typing out the actual code.</p>
<p>I wrote about <a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/Oct/7/vibe-engineering/">vibe engineering</a> a while ago as an alternative to vibe coding.</p>
<p>Vibe coding is when you have an LLM knock out code without any semblance of code review - great for prototypes and toy projects, definitely not an approach to use for serious libraries or production code.</p>
<p>I proposed "vibe engineering" as the grown up version of vibe coding, where expert programmers use coding agents in a professional and responsible way to produce high quality, reliable results.</p>
<p>You should absolutely read <a href="https://friendlybit.com/python/writing-justhtml-with-coding-agents/#the-journey">Emil's account</a> in full. A few highlights:</p>
<ol>
<li>He hooked in the 9,200 test <a href="https://github.com/html5lib/html5lib-tests">html5lib-tests</a> conformance suite almost from the start. There's no better way to construct a new HTML5 parser than using the test suite that the browsers themselves use.</li>
<li>He picked the core API design himself - a TagHandler base class with handle_start() etc. methods - and told the model to implement that.</li>
<li>He added a comparative benchmark to track performance compared to existing libraries like html5lib, then experimented with a Rust optimization based on those initial numbers.</li>
<li>He threw the original code away and started from scratch as a rough port of Servo's excellent <a href="https://github.com/servo/html5ever">html5ever</a> Rust library.</li>
<li>He built a custom profiler and new benchmark and let Gemini 3 Pro loose on it, finally achieving micro-optimizations to beat the existing Pure Python libraries.</li>
<li>He used coverage to identify and remove unnecessary code.</li>
<li>He had his agent build a <a href="https://github.com/EmilStenstrom/justhtml/blob/main/benchmarks/fuzz.py">custom fuzzer</a> to generate vast numbers of invalid HTML documents and harden the parser against them.</li>
</ol>
<p>This represents a lot of sophisticated development practices, tapping into Emil's deep experience as a software engineer. As described, this feels to me more like a lead architect role than a hands-on coder.</p>
<p>It perfectly fits what I was thinking about when I described <strong>vibe engineering</strong>.</p>
<p>Setting the coding agent up with the html5lib-tests suite is also a great example of <a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/Sep/30/designing-agentic-loops/">designing an agentic loop</a>.</p>
<h4 data-sanitized-id="-the-agent-did-the-typing-">"The agent did the typing"</h4>
<p>Emil concluded his article like this:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>JustHTML is about 3,000 lines of Python with 8,500+ tests passing. I couldn't have written it this quickly without the agent.</p>
<p>But "quickly" doesn't mean "without thinking." I spent a lot of time reviewing code, making design decisions, and steering the agent in the right direction. The agent did the typing; I did the thinking.</p>
<p>That's probably the right division of labor.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I couldn't agree more. Coding agents replace the part of my job that involves typing the code into a computer. I find what's left to be a much more valuable use of my time.</p>
    
        <p>Tags: <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/html">html</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/python">python</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai">ai</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/generative-ai">generative-ai</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/llms">llms</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/ai-assisted-programming">ai-assisted-programming</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/vibe-coding">vibe-coding</a>, <a href="https://simonwillison.net/tags/coding-agents">coding-agents</a></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 08:59:23 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765738103228647</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Bearming 3.0 for Bear released</title>
			<link>https://robertbirming.com/bearming-3-bear/</link>
						<dc:creator>robert</dc:creator>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>If you’re a Bear user, chances are you’ve come across my theme <em>Bearming</em> at some point. You may even have used it. Or maybe you’re still using it.</p>
<p>I had a look at the <a href="https://robertbirming.com/bearming/changelog/">changelog</a> the other day. It showed that the theme was first released on August 17, 2024. The last update was February 20, 2025... until today. Because now <a href="https://robertbirming.com/bearming/">Bearming 3.0</a> is finally here. 🥳</p>
<p>The theme has been rebuilt from scratch and now sits on a more modern and solid base. The idea is still the same though. Use it as is, or personalize it further with <a href="https://robertbirming.com/bearming/add-ons/">add-ons</a>, pre-made <a href="https://robertbirming.com/bearming/palettes/">palettes</a>, or your own colors.</p>
<p>As always, I have a ton of ideas for future add-ons, and I’ll probably add a scripts section as well. That said, you can already personalize Bearming in plenty of ways.</p>
<p>If you’re curious, I’m currently using the <a href="https://robertbirming.com/bearming/palettes/#fika">Swedish fika palette</a> together with these add-ons:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://robertbirming.com/bearming/add-ons/#horizontal-header-buttons">Horizontal header with buttons</a></li>
<li><a href="https://robertbirming.com/bearming/add-ons/#header-title-underline">Header title underline</a></li>
<li><a href="https://robertbirming.com/bearming/add-ons/#blog-list-cards">Blog list cards</a></li>
<li><a href="https://robertbirming.com/bearming/add-ons/#upvote-heart">Heart upvote button</a></li>
<li><a href="https://robertbirming.com/bearming/add-ons/#guestbook">Guestbook</a></li>
</ul>
<p>More is coming, but I hope the current options are enough to get you started.</p>
<p>If you’re using the Bearming theme and want to <a href="https://robertbirming.com/bearming/testimonials/">share your thoughts</a>, I’d love to hear from you.</p>
<p><a href="https://robertbirming.com/bearming/">Get Bearming 3.0 here →</a></p>
<p><em>Please note: If you’re using older add-ons, they may look a bit off for now. Updated 3.0 versions are on the way.</em></p>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 08:51:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765738103228646</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Sunday of the Forefathers of Christ</title>
			<link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vwYKbtyPvAA</link>
						<dc:creator>Saint Elias</dc:creator>
			<media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/v/vwYKbtyPvAA?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" height="390" width="640"><media:title type="html">Sunday of the Forefathers of Christ</media:title></media:content>
			<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 08:00:52 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765738103228645</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>Moved my newsletters to Feedbin</title>
			<link>https://focustivity.blog/moved-my-newsletters-to-feedbin</link>
						<category>apps</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<div>I've switched all my newsletters over to my Feedbin address instead of my main email.<br>There are a few stragglers; as they come in, I'll update them. <br><br>Feedbin is such a great RSS reader and is also great for newsletters. You can see the newsletter in the original format, which I love. It's so clean and straightforward—a pleasure to read.<br><br>I don't know why I didn't do this so long ago.</div>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 07:56:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765738103228644</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>🎥 Watched Superman (2025)</title>
			<link>https://www.michaelponders.com/2025/12/watched-superman-2025_02007470074.html</link>
						<dc:creator>Michael</dc:creator>
			<category>movies</category>
			<category>review</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<p>⚠️ <strong>SPOILER WARNING:</strong> FULL SPOILERS</p>

<div><img src="https://media.mitchelltribe.xyz/images/2025/12/b2e4642f_tmdb_102cc9c05fe1.jpg" alt='Promotional poster for a Superman movie featuring the superhero in a vibrant blue and red suit, confidently standing with his arms crossed, against a brightly lit, colorful background. The logo of DC Studios and the title "SUPERMAN" are prominently displayed.' title='Promotional poster for a Superman movie featuring the superhero in a vibrant blue and red suit, confidently standing with his arms crossed, against a brightly lit, colorful background. The logo of DC Studios and the title "SUPERMAN" are prominently displayed.'></div>

<p><em>Superman returns with unwavering resolve, his eyes set on a brighter tomorrow.</em></p>

<strong>My Rating:</strong> ⭐½ (1.5/5 stars)

<p>Let's start with the positives. I appreciated the fresh faces portraying Superman, Lois Lane, Lex Luthor, and Jimmy Olsen, particularly in the later scenes and action sequences. The special effects were impressive, and the soundtrack was a highlight. However, that's where the praise ends.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, this film might be the weakest Superman installment to date. Despite a promising cast, the storyline fell short. The inclusion of the Justice League characters like Green Lantern, Mr. Terrific, and Hawkgirl felt forced and detracted from the narrative. It was supposed to be a Superman movie, not a mixed ensemble. Although I'm a bigger fan of Green Lantern than Superman, his role in this film felt misplaced. Nathan Fillion, a fantastic actor known for his sci-fi roles and being a real-life nerd, was miscast. Overall, this movie did not make it to my list of favorite Superman films.</p>

<p>A more compelling story line and perhaps sticking with Henry Cavill as Superman could have improved the film. While the new actor wasn't terrible, and might have been acceptable had Cavill not already owned the role, he couldn't save the film.</p>

<div><div><img src="https://www.themoviedb.org/assets/2/v4/logos/v2/blue_short-8e7b30f73a4020692ccca9c88bafe5dcb6f8a62a4c6bc55cd9ba82bb2cd95f6c.svg" alt="TMDb"></div><div>This product uses the TMDb API but is not endorsed or certified by <a href="https://www.themoviedb.org/">TMDb</a>.</div></div>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 07:23:27 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765738103228642</guid>
		</item>
		<item>
			<title>The Right Book at the Right Time</title>
			<link>https://focustivity.blog/1b43ab11</link>
						<category>reading</category>
			<description><![CDATA[<div>Enjoying a book often comes down to timing and feeling a real connection.<br><br>If I start a book on a topic I’m not ready for, or just because it’s popular, I usually lose interest quickly.<br><br>But if I pick a book that relates to what I’m going through right now, I get completely absorbed.<br><br>Sometimes it’s even a book I tried to read before. If it matches my interests and situation now, I’m much more likely to finish it (and enjoy it).</div>]]></description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 06:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">1765738103228641</guid>
		</item>

	</channel>
</rss>
